<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-06T21:38:59+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>DoctorLogic provides online marketing tools for the medical industry, primarily to specialty doctors and dentists who own their practice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">2020 01 06 medical Seo Website</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2020-01-06-medical-seo-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020 01 06 medical Seo Website" /><published>2020-01-06T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-06T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2020-01-06%20medical-seo-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2020-01-06-medical-seo-website.html">&lt;p&gt;Every year it seems Google gives us a new ranking factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, mobile page speed looked to be the next big ranking factor to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, Google made several algorithm changes related to content, all leading up to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-11-05what-is-bert-latest-google-update&quot;&gt;biggest algorithm change in Google history: BERT.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true key to ranking and keeping Google happy is to have an awesome digital strategy, including a website that can keep up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetlivestats.com/total-number-of-websites/&quot;&gt;1 billion-plus websites&lt;/a&gt; online keeping up sounds easier said than done, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with Google evaluating sites based on hundreds of ranking factors, knowing where to aim your SEO strategy in 2020 may sound like trying to find a needle in a haystack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key item that continues is that ranking signals are going to continue to adapt to how users search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetlivestats.com/total-number-of-websites/&quot;&gt;new SEO&lt;/a&gt; trends already surviving have roots in the current algorithm and with a little creativity and SEO savvy, it’s entirely possible for you to rank well in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the ranking factors that will really matter in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publish High-Quality Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality content still reigns as king. And with the launch of the Artificial Intelligence (AI) based system BERT, quality content and user experience continue to be key to a strong SEO strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-quality content is about creating pages that increase time on page, lower bounce rate, and provide helpful content for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/just-say-it-future-search-voice-personal-digital-assistants/1392459&quot;&gt;According to Comscore,&lt;/a&gt; by 2020 50% of search is expected to be driven by voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the existence of innovative smartphones, people searched by plugging words into search engine boxes on their desktop computers. And this is how keywords were born. With the growing use of mobile devices, voice searches are becoming a popular trend with internet users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Google, 72 percent of people who own a voice-activated speaker say their devices are often used as part of their daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-you-need-voice-search.html&quot;&gt;optimize your website for voice search&lt;/a&gt; can help you generate more organic traffic if you understand and implement conversational searches into your SEO strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snippets Dominate More Search Clicks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stat: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginepeople.com/blog/googles-featured-snippets-roundup-recent-stats-studies.html&quot;&gt;54.7% of clicks &lt;/a&gt;from Google originate from Featured Snippets - proving they drive more than half of search engine clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/OXYSIhE9V4BokiB4enypOWN9H_iHEPXa_i8UAjlDyAyF2aU6URFbBWnlGwHTEbm6d5DwoS8mJ535BDgx2gGCZpKWNn8LohyNDelee_5TFw1DqGuP0LbR-Vpj4AXbMy1Lq86A1R3M =624x364&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google continues to evolve in recent years to deliver a better search experience for the user, like through Featured Snippets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured Snippets usually appear above the number #1 organic result, commonly referred to as “Position 0”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take advantage of this feature and drive more clicks to your website, you need to provide clear answers to commonly asked questions on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured Snippets are evaluated and boosted to the top depending on their quality, which Google has a way of determining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Websites are a Must&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A secure website is a critical component of being on Google’s good side. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/security/encrypt-in-transit/why-https&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, HTTPS “&lt;em&gt;helps prevent intruders from tampering with the communications between your websites and your users’ browsers&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a secure website is also best practice for your patients’ security as well. If you have non-secure links asking for patient-identifying information, you’re at risk of breaking HIPAA as well as exposing your patient’s information to potential hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webarxsecurity.com/5-reasons-website-security-important-2018/&quot;&gt;56%&lt;/a&gt; of all internet traffic is from an automated source; hacking tools, scrapers, spammers, and impersonators. If your site is not secure, there’s about a 50/50 chance your patient’s information is compromised by visiting your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google also released they removed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webarxsecurity.com/5-reasons-website-security-important-2018/&quot;&gt;80%&lt;/a&gt; of hacked sites from search results. Being blacklisted by Google is a large hurdle to overcome. It’s better to update your website security than to risk being blacklisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/website-analysis&quot;&gt;Find out&lt;/a&gt; if your website is at risk of sharing your patients’ private health information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile User Experience Will Determine Your Rankings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A website that does not have a mobile version may lose most of its users in the coming years as mobile web pages are a growing trend that will get even more popular in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology and how people find information through their mobile devices is getting so advanced it’s not enough to just have a mobile website - the interface has to be easy to read, grab people’s attention and then have the ability to answer their questions or at least keep them entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies show 4 in 5 consumers conduct local searches on search engines using their mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since more people are searching from their smartphones than from a computer it’s important to have a mobile version for your website to reach the most amount of people interested in your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stats: There are 2.7 billion smartphone users around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google My Business&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;Claim and optimize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While optimizing your website for SEO needs to be your number one priority,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt; Google My Business (GMB)&lt;/a&gt; should be second in line; especially for practices who rely on local traffic. It’s free and can get you incredible exposure if you’re optimized enough to show up in Google’s three-pack:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/K9MtGx5Fq1lxHrp3LSBNT_Qf8_dzCxgfYGIQpE4B-tmPafvOll86IyFWXGC6ZnWIQtA8ggnaH8Hfmh9HAyPCGp-XZtGN2A2AQID2uiD4KhT5DAvCUYNG6PgBu5el86rIOSLRP_Rn =405x386&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GMB works in conjunction with your website ranking. The more you boost your practice online, the more chances you have towards dominating the first page of search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to setting up your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-01do-and-dont-google-business.html&quot;&gt;Google My Business account&lt;/a&gt; is to fill out as much information as you can, accurately. The more information you list, the higher your business will show in search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://thrivehive.com/how-to-rank-your-business-higher-on-google/&quot;&gt;In fact&lt;/a&gt;, a complete and accurate Google My Business listings get 7x more clicks than those missing information and are 70% more likely to attract location visits.” That type of traffic is huge, especially if your goal is to bring in more new patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Reviews Matter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medical practices are finally starting to realize the importance of online reviews from their customers. According to a recent survey, 84 percent of people trust online reviews as much as a personal recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a review is left about your practice, positive or negative, be sure to respond to it. This shows other people reading the reviews that your practice cares what customers think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two places where you should focus on getting reviews is on your website, Facebook page and Google My Business page. These are big ones. Getting reviews is crucial because these reviews show up on Google when someone searches for your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google also notes: high quality, positive reviews from your patients will improve your practice’s visibility, which implies reviews might factor into rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can simplify the review process by working with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/social-reputation&quot;&gt;reputation marketing software &lt;/a&gt;that can manage and proactively work your practice to get reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization, when done effectively, can prove significant value to your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re already familiar with these trends, then you are definitely ahead of the game. It’s time to double-down so you can generate more targeted traffic from Google. But if you still have questions and need help with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/search-amplifier&quot;&gt;SEO services&lt;/a&gt;, contact DoctorLogic to help solve your SEO challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="SEO" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Every year it seems Google gives us a new ranking factor.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 12 30plastic Surgery Marketing Budget</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-30plastic-surgery-marketing-budget.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 12 30plastic Surgery Marketing Budget" /><published>2019-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-30T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-30plastic-surgery-marketing-budget</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-30plastic-surgery-marketing-budget.html">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plasticsurgery.org/documents/News/Statistics/2018/plastic-surgery-statistics-full-report-2018.pdf&quot; title=&quot;2018 ASPS Statistics&quot;&gt;ASPS 2018 Plastic Surgery Statistics Report&lt;/a&gt;, breast augmentation continues to be the top cosmetic surgical procedure and has been since 2006. Silicone implants were used in 88%, and saline implants in 12%, of all breast augmentations in 2018. The other top procedures with notable gains include tummy tuck (up 107%), liposuction (up 5%), and buttock augmentation with fat grafting (up 19%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With more cutting-edge procedures and technologies hitting the market, patients are becoming more aware of new opportunities and more interested in researching the best options for their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plastic surgeons interested in starting their own practice or looking to market their long-standing practice need to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be visible in a competitive market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Properly address patients who have become obsessed with wanting to know answers within seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions come down to: How do I set a budget for marketing? What’s the best way for a plastic surgery practice to achieve sustained growth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spending too much on marketing can take away from the costs needed for a healthy operations budget. Spending too little on marketing can keep you from achieving your goals and paying off your loans in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;marketing-strategy&quot;&gt;Marketing Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building a strategy for marketing your plastic surgery practice, three things must be considered: the age of the practice, the location of the practice, and the size of the practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age -&lt;/strong&gt; A practice that is just starting up will need to invest more money upfront to help build brand awareness in its market. This can include internal marketing software, branding, and website and digital marketing (SEO/SEM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location -&lt;/strong&gt; Practices in high-population, high-income locations will face larger competition than practices in other areas. The more competition in your market, the more dollars need to be allocated toward your marketing budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Size &amp;amp; Number of Procedures -&lt;/strong&gt; The more services your practice offers, the more competition it will have with other plastic, cosmetic, derm, and medspa practices. Each procedure offered will need a specific marketing strategy to get more patients inquiring about this procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;measuring-roi&quot;&gt;Measuring ROI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While digital marketing always delivers the strongest ROI, it’s important that each and every individual marketing activity is being measured in regard to the number of leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means tracking every single phone call and email that comes into the practice from the marketing strategy at play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At DoctorLogic, a website software company that specializes in launching startup plastic surgery practices, doctors can log in any time to see how many leads have come through their website. They can listen to all phone calls and read all emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows the practice to accurately measure how many new patients are inquiring, which services they are inquiring about, and what the total ROI is on their website and through their digital marketing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;budget-for-plastic-surgery-marketing&quot;&gt;Budget for Plastic Surgery Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plastic or cosmetic surgery practice should plan on spending no less than 6 – 12% of its annual revenue on marketing. Younger practices will need to spend more initially to gain exposure — same for practices in areas of larger competition. Initial costs will focus on establishing a digital and physical presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of guidelines on how to plan out your marketing budget for the first five years of your plastic or cosmetic surgery practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year 1 - 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$500,000 – $1,000,000 projected annual revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$2,500 – $5,000/month budget (larger markets could need more)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Organic Presence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Directory Listing Optimization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PPC Ads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing ROI software (i.e., call and email tracking)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internal marketing automation software (i.e., patient reminders, practice specials, events, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 – 2 in-person events per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Years 3 - 5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$1 – 2 million projected annual revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$5,000 – $10,000/month budget&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expand digital budget for additional PPC or ad campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social media campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email marketing campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 – 3 events per year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoctorLogic specializes in marketing for plastic surgery practices. If you’d like to read more about how we’ve helped practices generate revenue in their early stages, read our &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/case-studies/morales-plastic-surgery&quot; title=&quot;Dr. Morales Case Study&quot;&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt; on a plastic surgeon in the fourth largest city in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">According to the ASPS 2018 Plastic Surgery Statistics Report, breast augmentation continues to be the top cosmetic surgical procedure and has been since 2006. Silicone implants were used in 88%, and saline implants in 12%, of all breast augmentations in 2018. The other top procedures with notable gains include tummy tuck (up 107%), liposuction (up 5%), and buttock augmentation with fat grafting (up 19%).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 12 25dental Seo Attract More Patients</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-25dental-seo-attract-more-patients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 12  25dental Seo Attract More Patients" /><published>2019-12-26T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-26T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-%2025dental-seo-attract-more-patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-12-25dental-seo-attract-more-patients.html">&lt;p&gt;Dentists are quickly learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/case-studies/emigh-dental&quot;&gt;the importance of marketing their practices online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more dentists are taking a serious look at their websites and are making decisions to redesign their sites to keep in contact with patients and attract new ones. Some of them are even adopting &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators/healthcare-content-marketing&quot; title=&quot;Dentist Blogs&quot;&gt;content marketing strategies&lt;/a&gt; to get more shares on social media. However, these creative marketing efforts will go unnoticed if they are not optimized for search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where dental search engine optimization, or SEO, comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you familiar with the Yellow Pages? Once upon a time, people would search for dentists in this infamous book, but now they go online. And with these changing times, people do not look beyond the first page of online search results, so sites that don’t rank high on search engines like Google or Bing are ignored. Whether you’re a new dental practice or have a long-established practice, SEO for dentists is essential to finding new patients—and keeping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-seo-for-dentists&quot;&gt;What’s SEO for Dentists?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEO for dentists, also known as dental SEO, focuses on optimizing a dental practice’s website for search engines and users to increase the site’s visibility in search results on Google, Yahoo!, and Bing. Optimizations can include making the site mobile-friendly, fast, and useful to prospective patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;93% of online experiences begin with a search engine, according to a Forrester study. That means a search engine is the biggest billboard there is for brands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, search engine optimization (SEO) is about increasing your website’s visibility in the organic search results of major search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-seo-important-for-dentists&quot;&gt;Why is SEO important for Dentists?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way people use technology today is far different than how it was used 10-years ago. From smartphones, laptops, or AI devices (Google Home or Alexa), people are constantly interacting with technology, so much so, the phrase “let me Google that” is now integrated into people’s vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a dentist, SEO marketing might not be high on your list of priorities. Then again, without search engine optimization, almost no one will be able to find your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for your dental practice to succeed online, you need to recognize the importance of search engine optimization. Marketing has always been about connecting with your audience in the right place and time. Today, your audience is spending their time online. You need to meet them where they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-needed-to-develop-a-strong-dental-seo&quot;&gt;What’s needed to develop a strong Dental SEO?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any marketing plan requires knowing where to reach your target audience and how to reach them. SEO is no exception. When you address the needs of dental patients, you get their attention. This attention raises your rankings, which garners even more attention, and the cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some things your practice can do to begin the process of developing a good dental search engine optimization strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Learn How Emigh Dental.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn how&lt;/em&gt; [**&lt;em&gt;Emigh Dental Care _**](https://doctorlogic.com/case-studies/emigh-dental “Dental Case Study”)_grew their website leads and conversion rate with SEO.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;adding-keywords-for-seo&quot;&gt;Adding Keywords for SEO&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is a marketplace. And your website is competing with other dentist websites for search engine attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding relevant keywords to your website helps search engines match your site to specific search terms. And using those keywords strategically helps search engines see your site as relevant to the people looking for those search terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;types-of-keywords&quot;&gt;Types of keywords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;keywords-fall-into-two-categories&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords fall into two categories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Head&lt;/strong&gt; - Shorter keywords with a larger search volume, such as “dentist” or “dental services”. These target a wide audience and are usually more difficult to rank for.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-tail&lt;/strong&gt; - These are more descriptive, multi-word search terms, like “dentist in [your city]” or “children’s dentist in [your area], or even “broken tooth repair in [city], [state].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When optimizing your website, make sure to include keywords and phrases that describe all the services you provide. For example, don’t just use words like “dentist” or “dental services” in your website’s copy and URLs. Use words like “root canal,” “porcelain crown,” and the names of procedures you perform or products you offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publish High-Quality Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality content still reigns as king. And with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-11-05what-is-bert-latest-google-update&quot; title=&quot;Google Updates for Dentist&quot;&gt;launch of the Artificial Intelligence (AI) based system BERT&lt;/a&gt;, quality content and user experience continue to be key to a strong SEO strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-quality content is about creating pages that increase time on page, lower bounce rate, and provide helpful content for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog&quot;&gt;Blog pages&lt;/a&gt; are the types of high-quality content search engines, and users want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content pages must be more than high-quality for today’s SEO. They also must cover the following areas to increase presence in search engine results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search Intent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to reshape your SEO content strategy and increase traffic you should be more aligned with searched intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dive into Google Analytics to understand what your target searcher is searching for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Search Intent.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research supports quality content creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through competitor research and data mining, you can uncover keyword gems that have average search volume, but a high click-through rate for your audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to identify your primary keywords and bucket them into topics suited for your search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stat:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/just-say-it-future-search-voice-personal-digital-assistants/1392459&quot;&gt;According to Comscore,&lt;/a&gt; by 2020 50% of search is expected to be driven by voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the existence of innovative smartphones, people searched by plugging words into search engine boxes on their desktop computers. And this is how keywords were born. With the growing use of mobile devices, voice searches are becoming a popular trend with internet users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Google, 72 percent of people who own a voice-activated speaker say their devices are often used as part of their daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-you-need-voice-search.html&quot;&gt;optimize your website for voice search&lt;/a&gt; can help you generate more organic traffic if you understand and implement conversational searches into your SEO strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-more-patients-with-dental-seo-services&quot;&gt;Reach more patients with dental SEO services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization, when done effectively, can prove significant value to your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google is a search engine that processes information based on how search users behave and it’s getting more accurate, which means that each year new trends appear that change the way information is published on the internet. This means all users can get their questions answered in a matter of minutes or even seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re ready to start improving your SEO but don’t have the time or staff, let us know. Our dental SEO service will give you the presence you need to attract more patients. Contact DoctorLogic to help solve your SEO challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Dentists are quickly learning the importance of marketing their practices online.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 11 05what Is Bert Latest Google Update</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-11-05What-is-BERT-latest-Google-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 11 05what Is Bert Latest Google Update" /><published>2019-11-05T19:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T19:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-11-05What-is-BERT-latest-Google-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-11-05What-is-BERT-latest-Google-update.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed (2).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(No, not this Bert)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 2019, Google has been very busy with multiple algorithm updates and last week contained the biggest news in the landscape in the past 5 years. Specifically, BERT will impact one in 10 searches (10%) in the U.S. for English related searches with future plans to expand it across the entire search landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, what’s  BERT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put BERT stands for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In layman’s terms, BERT is an Artificial Intelligence (AI) based system that will return results based on what it thinks the searcher is specifically looking for when conducting a search for any keyword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means BERT models can interpret the appropriate meaning of a word by looking at the words that come before and after. This will lead to a better understanding of queries, compared to processing words one-by-one in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, Google has made it a priority to return information as quickly and efficiently as possible so it was important to create a tool that can read and interpret an ever-growing source of content across the entire Internet. More specifically, BERT will be able to better understand the meaning or context behind searches or specifically when certain words are used in the search query and then return the most relevant website in a search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BERT in Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example below, the old page simply did not return the most relevant page related to “standing”. This new page specifically mentions “physical demands” making it easier for the searcher to find the correct information related to the search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/pasted image 0 (1).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When compared, the new results are very clear on why the impact is big. In this example, the old result did not relay the page which specifically answered the search. The old page appears to be more of a generic page on how to get your prescription filled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/pasted image 0 (2).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BERT also makes an impact on featured snippets and answer boxes. In this example, “curb” had the wrong emphasis placed on it with Google ignoring the “no” in the search query. As a result of BERT, the more relevant information is displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/unnamed (4).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(images from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.google/products/search/search-language-understanding-bert/&quot; title=&quot;https://blog.google/products/search/search-language-understanding-bert/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;https://blog.google/products/search/search-language-understanding-bert/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google admits BERT still isn’t perfect when it comes to displaying the right results, but it’s easy to expect it will get better over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does BERT impact me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the short term, there may be fluctuations in rankings meaning you might see either a temporary drop or an increase in performance. There is no reason to be alarmed here. Whenever an update is announced volatility happens throughout the search landscape as things settle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long term, websites with poorly written content are likely to lose a lot of ground from BERT. Poor content makes it harder for AI to read and interpret the content–let alone correctly. As a result, this content will also be harder for the searcher to read so Google will deem it less worthy than another website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content-multiplier&quot; title=&quot;Medical Marketing Content&quot;&gt;content on each of our websites &lt;/a&gt;is written by a team of professionals to ensure quality and we write content based on what searchers are searching. This includes researching the latest news and trends on a specific keyword level. It’s important to remember that quality is more important than quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Early Impact from BERT So Far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very early data so far has shown the update to not be overly significant despite Google announcing it impacts 10% of all searchers. For reference, there have been much bigger impacts throughout the 2019 calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing we’ve seen which is similar to some industry trends is around informational and long-tail related searches. These typically include more of the longer-tail keywords for searchers trying to find more specific information such as “what is” or “how-to” related questions. These questions are often best answered on blog-related posts too which is something many of our websites utilize. &lt;em&gt;If you’re interested in finding out more about our&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;blog services&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, feel free to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;contact us&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following example for the keyword “How to fix a gummy smile”, we see changes to the website listed in position 2. Below the post from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newbeauty.com/hottopic/blogpost/11232-botox-cosmetic-nonsurgical-gummy-smile-correction/&quot;&gt;New Beauty&lt;/a&gt; targets and has an opinion that Botox is the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Screen Shot 2019-10-29 at 11.49.08 AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page now ranking in position 2 is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dentistryformadison.com/how-to-fix-a-gummy-smile/&quot;&gt;Dentistry For Madison&lt;/a&gt;. (see below). It doesn’t read like an opinion piece and is more factual information for the searcher. This page is also older with a publish date in 2018 meaning &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;quality content can outrank newer content.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Screen Shot 2019-10-29 at 11.49.16 AM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also to note these more informational &amp;amp; long-tail related queries have less search volume. This means the overall traffic and performance of a website is likely to be unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can we do to optimize for BERT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When DoctorLogic builds content, we identify the correct keywords to target based on search trends. When we specifically place these keywords within the important SEO elements, we succeed because we help BERT and Google better identify the topic(s) of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember, we can’t include too many topics or procedures on the same page. Otherwise, Google will get confused and now know how to interpret the page. In this case, that’s why it’s important to have more content to cover multiple topics. The opposite also has problems where we have too many pages talking about the same topic or procedure. Then Google won’t know which page is better or what page we want to be shown in search results. In this case, we need to consolidate to make one page the most powerful it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a regular basis, we keep up with search trends and follow SEO best practices allowing us to stay ahead of our competition. Very soon, we’ll have much more information to share about some SEO platform updates as well. All of these things make a huge positive impact on rankings while future-proofing our websites to be more resistant to any future Google updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep in mind SEO does not happen overnight. It takes time before the impact is fully realized so patience is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoctorLogic uses our software to help turn all of your practice content into 100x more data and we present it to Google exactly how Google wants it. And that makes Google happy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><category term="Website" /><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><summary type="html">(No, not this Bert)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Build A Profitable Practice</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-a-profitable-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Build A Profitable Practice" /><published>2019-10-24T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-24T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-a-profitable-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-a-profitable-practice.html">&lt;p&gt;Driving traffic to your practice website is essential. But not all visitors prove profitable. 80% of your revenue comes from only 20% of your patients. The key to building a profitable practice begins with identifying and resembling high-value patients, like those similar to your 20%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/cosmetic-3up-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are 5 tips for identifying profitable visitors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create an Ideal Patient Profile:&lt;/strong&gt; Identify common characteristics in patients who generate the most revenue. What do they have in common? Once your Ideal Patient Profile is complete, that’s where you need to focus your marketing dollars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Messaging:&lt;/strong&gt; Your practice must indicate high-quality. Determine which type of messaging attracts high-value patients. Is it the perception of exclusive service? Perhaps it’s broadcasting you use the most advanced technology. Understanding which type of messaging drives high-value appointment scheduling is the key to bringing in ideal patients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt; Your website is a magnet for judgment that carries over towards the way patients perceive your practice as a whole. Your website needs to exude credibility in every manner possible. Your ideal patients are most likely impatient and will not tolerate a slow-loading site. Also, verify your website matches the messaging you determined in #2. If patients are after exclusivity, they’re expecting to see providers who match that term on search engines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing:&lt;/strong&gt; Once you’ve established your Ideal Patient Profile, the type of messaging required, and redesigned (or refreshed) your website, the next step is to put a marketing strategy together on how you plan to attract those patients. A great place to start is with patient referrals. High-value patients, typically know a few others they can refer to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-house services:&lt;/strong&gt; Attracting high-value patients doesn’t end once they’ve scheduled an appointment. Establishing unification for everything, from your online presence to your practice services, is vital to your success.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Contact us to learn how DoctorLogic builds profitable practices through a proprietary software invented exclusively for healthcare providers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Driving traffic to your practice website is essential. But not all visitors prove profitable. 80% of your revenue comes from only 20% of your patients. The key to building a profitable practice begins with identifying and resembling high-value patients, like those similar to your 20%.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 10 22 search And Social Increase Patient Leads</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-22-Search-and-Social-Increase-Patient-Leads.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 10 22 search And Social Increase Patient Leads" /><published>2019-10-22T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-22T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-22%20Search-and-Social-Increase-Patient-Leads</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-22-Search-and-Social-Increase-Patient-Leads.html">&lt;p&gt;Looking to increase patient leads that your website brings in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve mentioned on the blog, a practice’s website is where a lot of new business comes from these days, which is why having a user- and search-friendly website and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/reputation-management-for-doctors-in-a-digital-world.html&quot;&gt;good online reputation&lt;/a&gt; are so important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the more traffic you generate, the more people visit and explore your site, the more they read your patient reviews, helpful content, and see your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/leveraging-before-and-after-galleries.html&quot;&gt;Before and After photo galleries&lt;/a&gt;, and ultimately, the more those visitors become actual patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you generate that precious traffic and ultimately increase patient leads? Utilizing search and social is a surefire way to get things kicked off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-get-in-the-search-gods-favor&quot;&gt;How to Get in the Search Gods’ Favor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how important &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-things-every-website-must-have.html&quot;&gt;user-friendliness&lt;/a&gt; is to your website, but what about search-friendliness? What can you do to your site to make search engines favor it more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve discussed before, keyword-rich content can help position your website as more authoritative, valuable, and relevant, three things search engines &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of content should be leveraged throughout your site, from web pages and patient reviews to blog posts and procedure descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of your site you can improve to increase your search ranking is to speed up your page load time. This is the amount of time your website takes to load all elements when someone navigates to your site. People like when sites load fast, which means search engines do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you find out how fast your website’s load time is and what’s slowing it down? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.pingdom.com/#5aee68dfd4c00000&quot;&gt;Pingdom&lt;/a&gt; and input your URL, then you’ll be able to see your performance grade, page size, load time, requests, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;utilizing-social-to-increase-traffic&quot;&gt;Utilizing Social to Increase Traffic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media pages are another excellent way to increase traffic to, and patient leads coming from, your practice website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s because social shows the human side of your practice. This is where you really want to showcase your patients and what they have to say. Encourage them to leave reviews on your Facebook page, and connect to you on sites like LinkedIn and Twitter. With their permission, you can even share their stories and before and after photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only can social reach prospective patients on a human level, but it can also reach the search gods on a search engine optimization (SEO) level. That’s because &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hootsuite.com/social-media-seo-experiment/&quot;&gt;it’s been found&lt;/a&gt; that there’s a strong correlation between social activity and rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/04-ChangeinRankVSocialEngage_ProjectElephant.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;via&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hootsuite.com/social-media-seo-experiment/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hootsuite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;: “We can observe a positive linear trendline, indicating a positive relationship between the number of social engagements and change in rank.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hat means social can help your search rankings, further boosting traffic to your site, further increasing the number of conversions from website visitors to patient leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-time-to-prioritize-your-seo&quot;&gt;It’s Time to Prioritize Your SEO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, making your website appealing to search engines &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; utilizing your social media pages to connect with patients both help improve your SEO. That means if you’re still not making digital marketing and whitehat SEO practices a priority at your practice, you’re falling behind the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure where to start? &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/&quot;&gt;We &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/search-amplifier&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Medical SEO&quot;&gt;can&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/&quot;&gt; help&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Looking to increase patient leads that your website brings in?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 10 01do And Dont Google Business</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-01do-and-dont-google-business.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 10 01do And Dont Google Business" /><published>2019-10-01T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-01T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-01do-and-dont-google-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-10-01do-and-dont-google-business.html">&lt;p&gt;Google My Business is an important tool in any business owner’s toolbox, especially if you’re managing a physical location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s because a practice’s Google My Business profile is what appears when people are searching for that business, or a business like it, on Google Search or in Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s first take a look at how to set up a Google My Business Listing, then we’ll dive into the do’s and don’ts for your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-my-business-listing&quot;&gt;Google My Business Listing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, Google makes it easy to both create and update your Business Profile on their platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt;go to this site&lt;/a&gt;, type in your practice name, identify the proper listing, and hit “Manage Now” to confirm you own the business. From there, you’ll have the power to easily create ads, upload a virtual tour of your practice, and ensure business information like hours of operation, address, and contact information is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dos&quot;&gt;Do’s&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-add-as-much-pertinent-information-as-possible&quot;&gt;1. Add as much pertinent information as possible.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more information you add, the easier it will be for prospective patients to find and contact you. Fill in your listing information until you hit 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-respond-to-reviews&quot;&gt;2. Respond to reviews.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve mentioned in a previous post, it’s important to &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/doctor-reputation-management.html&quot;&gt;respond to reviews of your practice&lt;/a&gt;, whether negative or positive. Doing so on your Google My Business Listing will allow people searching for your practice to read reviews–and your replies–directly in Maps or from Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-download-the-app&quot;&gt;3. Download the app.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google My Business has both Android and iOS apps that allow you to manage your listing on the go! You’ll receive instant alerts when customers leave reviews, be able to send messages, upload photos, post-practice updates, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;donts&quot;&gt;Don’ts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-set-it-and-forget-it&quot;&gt;1. Set it and forget it.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of businesses claim their listing only to never log in to their account again. This is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; no-no! That’s because any Google user can suggest edits to your listing, and if those changes are inaccurate, your practice could suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-exceed-750-characters-in-the-description-field&quot;&gt;2. Exceed 750 characters in the description field.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing your practice description, make sure not to exceed 750 characters. Even better, try to keep the most pertinent information in the first 250, as only 250 characters are displayed before they’re cut off in the Knowledge Panel. &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/business/answer/3038177#description&quot;&gt;Go here&lt;/a&gt; for more description guidelines from Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-fail-to-respond-to-patient-messages&quot;&gt;3. Fail to respond to patient messages.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prospective patients can contact your practice directly through your listing, so make sure someone is tasked with responding to these messages. After you set up your listing to receive and respond to SMS messages from potential patients, remember to reply to them and to do so promptly, as your listing will display your average response time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, claiming your practice on Google My Business and managing it effectively can help you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Display and control pertinent practice information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manage your online reputation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interact with prospective patients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curate patient photos, videos, and other user-generated content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gather insights on how patients get to your site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/search-amplifier&quot;&gt;local SEO strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s not to love about that? Start by claiming your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt;Google My Business account&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Google My Business is an important tool in any business owner’s toolbox, especially if you’re managing a physical location.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Need Voice Search</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-you-need-voice-search.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Need Voice Search" /><published>2019-09-12T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-12T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-you-need-voice-search</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-you-need-voice-search.html">&lt;p&gt;As technology advances, the ways to search for and find information are multiplying. One of the more relatively recent methods quickly gaining popularity is voice search. This means in order to stay on top of the optimization game, websites must now also account for voice searches in their strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll look at why you need to start optimizing your website for Google voice search and how to do it. Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-numbers&quot;&gt;The Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost: how popular &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; voice search?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/data/voice-search-statistics/&quot;&gt;Think with Google&lt;/a&gt;, a “one-stop shop for consumer trends, marketing insights and industry research,” as of May 2016, 20% of searches in the Google App were done by voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/21Yx3-data-voice-search-statistics-download.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This number has only increased in recent years, and will continue to grow as time wears on, especially given that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/787382/worldwide-voice-technology-utilization/&quot;&gt;31%&lt;/a&gt; of smartphone users worldwide use voice tech at least once a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The total voice searching user base among US adults is &lt;a href=&quot;https://voicebot.ai/2018/04/03/over-half-of-smartphone-owners-use-voice-assistants-siri-leads-the-pack/&quot;&gt;42.7%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.comscore.com/Insights/Presentations-and-Whitepapers/2017/The-Future-of-Voice-From-Smartphones-to-Smart-Speakers-to-Smart-Homes&quot;&gt;50%&lt;/a&gt; of all online searches will be voice-based by 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.occstrategy.com/media/1285/the-talking-shop_uk.pdf&quot;&gt;55%&lt;/a&gt; of households are expected to own smart speaker devices by 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, how do we take advantage of this growing trend?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;location-based-search&quot;&gt;Location-Based Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchengineland.com/voice-search-explosion-will-change-local-search-251776&quot;&gt;Search Engine Land&lt;/a&gt;, 22% of voice search queries were looking for location-based content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hound-voice-graphic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other reports put it as high as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brightlocal.com/research/voice-search-for-local-business-study/&quot;&gt;58%&lt;/a&gt;. This is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; opportunity for businesses with a physical location, especially medical practices, as potential patients will be voice searching for practices, procedures, and specialists within their immediate area&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note: most people conducting voice search to find local businesses will use the phrase “near me”, so you may want to start including that key phrase in some of your website content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, to give accurate responses, many search bots will use Business Listings information, so make sure your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/business/&quot;&gt;Google My Business&lt;/a&gt; page is up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;typing-vs-speaking&quot;&gt;Typing vs. Speaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When optimizing your content for voice-based search, it’s important to take into account the difference between how people type and how people speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by thinking about what questions people might ask related to your target keywords. For example, instead of typing “dermatologist Boca Raton, Fl”, people would voice search “Who’s the best dermatologist in Boca Raton, Florida?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make your life easier, you can use a free online tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://answerthepublic.com&quot;&gt;Answer the Public&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to enter any given keyword and receive a map and a list of commonly asked questions related to that keyword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typed in dermatologist, and here’s what was returned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/fd959fb9-87d3-46db-9110-3ff516bccea9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also take a look at the “People also ask” section that appears in Google Search results after you use voice search to ask it a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve found the most relevant questions based on voice queries, you can create content using those questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you could create web pages or blog posts based on the following queries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Who’s the top dermatologist in Boca Raton, Florida?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What’s the difference between dermabrasion and microdermabrasion?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What’s more effective, botox or acupuncture?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“How much does acne treatment cost?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-things-to-keep-in-mind&quot;&gt;Other Things to Keep in Mind&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How else can you make your website voice-search friendly? We’ve mentioned this is some of our other &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/blog/market-healthcare-practice-online.html&quot;&gt;SEO posts&lt;/a&gt;, but ensuring your website loads fast is key to taking advantage of any search queries–whether traditional (i.e. typed) or via voice. This is especially important for voice search, as users will likely be opting for voice queries because they’re on the go or otherwise occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/&quot;&gt;PageSpeed Insights&lt;/a&gt; to see how your website performs, both on the desktop &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; mobile, and get recommendations for how to make it load even faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Want to learn how DoctorLogic can help you optimize your practice’s website for voice search?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/get-a-demo.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Request a demo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">As technology advances, the ways to search for and find information are multiplying. One of the more relatively recent methods quickly gaining popularity is voice search. This means in order to stay on top of the optimization game, websites must now also account for voice searches in their strategy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Often Should Doctors Blog</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-often-should-doctors-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Often Should Doctors Blog" /><published>2019-09-09T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-often-should-doctors-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-often-should-doctors-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;It takes a well thought-out content strategy to appeal to both patients and search engines, but how much content should you be creating, and how often should doctors blog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll lay out why content is important, how often you should blog, and what types of content you can create to easily fill up your queue. These tips will give you a better idea of how you should be incorporating content into your overall digital marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-content-is-important&quot;&gt;Why Content is Important&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now you probably know that content is good for &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Blog SEO&quot;&gt;search engine optimization (SEO)&lt;/a&gt; purposes, as well as for patients looking for more information about your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s important to have a content strategy in place. First, create buckets based on goals you have for your strategy. For example, do you want more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Website visitors?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visitors converting into leads?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People physically walking into your practice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use these goals to start generating content ideas for each bucket. For example, website visitors would be more interested in top of the funnel (TOFU) content, getting conversions from website visitors to leads would require middle of the funnel (MOFU) content, and having people walk into your practice would most likely be precipitated by them consuming bottom of the funnel (BOFU) content. The deeper into the funnel you get, the more in-depth your content should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-often-you-should-blog&quot;&gt;So, How Often You Should Blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know your goals and have content ideas for each, what should be the frequency of publication?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, posting once to three times a week is best, but for some people this is too much to commit to at the start. At the very least, post once every two weeks. The reason publishing frequently on your website is so important is because it signals to search engines that your website is relevant and publishing new, fresh pages of information for visitors on a consistent basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t worry, not all the content creation is up to the doctor, other professionals that are a part of the practice can create content as well, like practice administrators and nurses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-types-of-content-to-create&quot;&gt;What Types of Content to Create&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve already talked about TOFU, MOFU, and BOFU content, but not all of that content has to be in the form of blog posts. Other content types that are good for these buckets are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOFU&lt;/strong&gt;: How-tos, list posts, fun/lighthearted slide decks providing basic information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOFU&lt;/strong&gt;: Infographics, ‘what to expect’ comic strips and other content about specific procedures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOFU&lt;/strong&gt;: Whitepapers, eBooks, professional publications, in-depth procedure descriptions, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-time-to-get-started&quot;&gt;It’s Time to Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not blogging yet, the time to start is now! Come up with a list of goals for your content and outline a strategy ASAP, then get into the nitty gritty of content types you want to produce, topics you want to cover, and what you’ll need from whom to get it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having trouble getting started? &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators/content-marketing&quot;&gt;We can help.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Content-Marketing" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">It takes a well thought-out content strategy to appeal to both patients and search engines, but how much content should you be creating, and how often should doctors blog?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Signs your medical practice needs a new website</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Signs-Your-Medical-Practice-Needs-A-New-Website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signs your medical practice needs a new website" /><published>2019-09-03T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-03T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Signs%20Your%20Medical%20Practice%20Needs%20A%20New%20Website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Signs-Your-Medical-Practice-Needs-A-New-Website.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re often asked how often you should update or redesign your website. The answer isn’t as straightforward as you might think. So, to help with this question, here are 6 signs to look for when asking if your practice needs a new website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Site Looks Out of Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, looks do matter. As a matter of fact, 81% of internet users think less of a business if the website is not updated. It’s important your website function seamlessly, but it also needs to look &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/medical-website-design&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Medical Website&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fresh and modern&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Compare your website to the websites of your most prominent competitors. While it’s true you should do what’s right for you rather than follow the Joneses, if your design is far behind the quality of your competitors, customers may overlook your practice. Your website’s design is frequently the first or only impression a potential patients may have of your practice - make sure it looks good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Dental Image Variation.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Patient Volume Has Gone Down&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your website is getting “a little long in the tooth” and you’ve seen significant drop in traffic and leads, you’re clearly not being found. Hopefully you have a good way of tracking how many leads you get from your website. If not, that’s a sign too. If you can track it and you see a trend of sales or leads going down, it’s time to figure out why and make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/seo-performance (3).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Site Doesn’t Look Good On a Mobile Device&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all guilty of spending a lot of time on our phones. According to Statistica, 52% of all website traffic comes from mobile devices. You want potential customers to have a good experience when they visit your website on their phone or tablet. You also want to do it because Google cares. Google bases its rankings on mobile rather than desktop version of a website. If you have a separate mobile website or a site that does not utilize responsive design, it makes sense to build a new website using a mobile-first approach rather than trying to force it with mobile-friendly elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Have To Pay For Updates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With today’s content management and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/website-management&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Website Mangement&quot;&gt;**web management technology **&lt;/a&gt;here’s no reason, other than time or not wanting the hassle yourself, to have to pay a web master an hourly rate to change simple things like product prices, photos in a gallery, adding testimonials or updating information about your services. Making small changes or updates to your site, like adding blog post or updating an event should be easy for anyone on your staff to accomplish. If your website is built on a difficult platform or requires a third party to make even the simplest updates, consider a new website built in an easy-to-use content management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People Don’t Stay Long&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A successful website is all about pleasing your users. If your website is difficult to navigate and doesn’t offer valuable content, your users will leave. Statistics show 39% of internet users would think twice about using a product or service if the website is not fresh, user friendly and current. Programs like Google Analytics will show you a lot about how people interact with your website. If you’re not &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/success-insights&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tracking Users, Sessions, Page Views, Time on Site and Bounce Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, now is the time to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users is how many people came to your website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sessions is how many times they came to your site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page views is how many pages they looked at while on your site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bounce rate tell you how many people didn’t look at more than one page when they came to your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re watching these numbers and see them going in the wrong direction then you know it’s time for something fresh and more effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Content Is Old&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your website is a living, breathing entity on the internet. Every update you make to your website plays a part in an interaction with visitors, customers and search engines. A static website without updates of any kind is viewed by the search engines as “dead”. If your site doesn’t get updated, it’s bad all around. People don’t want to see the same old info and neither does Google. Search engines look at your website more frequently, when you update with content like articles, downloads and new web pages. If you want to keep people interested and Google showing people your website then you need to keep your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content-multiplier&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Content Multiplier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;content fresh and current&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/content-marketing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take the Test&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsure if you’re website is up to date? Take this &lt;a href=&quot;https://resources.doctorlogic.com/is-your-website-up-to-date-assessment?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=outgrow&amp;amp;utm_campaign=signs_you_need_new_website&quot; title=&quot;Is Your Practice Website Up to Date?&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 question assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and learn if you’re rockin’ it or can do better with your practice website. If you have any, or lot’s of the above issues don’t stress out. Getting your website updated is easier and more affordable than think. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;www.doctorlogic.com&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Home Page&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;www.doctorlogic.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Screen Shot 2019-09-02 at 8.24.00 PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Assessment&quot; title=&quot;Is Your Website Up To Date&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">We’re often asked how often you should update or redesign your website. The answer isn’t as straightforward as you might think. So, to help with this question, here are 6 signs to look for when asking if your practice needs a new website.</summary></entry></feed>