<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-15T17:30:06+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>DoctorLogic provides online marketing tools for the medical industry, primarily to specialty doctors and dentists who own their practice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients" /><published>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hour later, and no call back, so I called again. After the second ring, I was greeted with, “Dentist office, can you please hold.” Before I could respond I was put on hold. This was not a great experience…needless to say I hung up and did not call back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your front desk staff and the way they handle the first phone conversation can quite literally mean the difference between a thriving practice full of referrals and delighted patients and a practice struggling just to get by. Having friendly and sincere people representing your practice is the thing that will leave the most lasting impression on patients, especially new patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at a few behaviors that should be a part of your front desk process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;efficient-system-for-phone-calls-and-patient-arrivals&quot;&gt;Efficient system for phone calls and patient arrivals.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the voice and face of a doctor’s front office can be overwhelming, especially if your team is dealing with high call volume, and patient arrivals all at the same time. This is an opportunity to revisit your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;every-call-should-be-answered-before-the-third-ring&quot;&gt;Every call should be answered before the third ring.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure the phone is answered on brand, have a little script available. And if your staff has to put a caller on hold, it’s okay. First, make them feel comfortable by having your phone attendees introduce themselves, then ask permission to put the caller on hold or ask if they would prefer a call back. If a patient arrives while your attendant is on the phone, simply give them a nod and a smile and let them know you’ll be right with them. They will feel acknowledged and will wait to interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-about-first-impression&quot;&gt;It’s About First Impression.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While searching for an orthopaedic in my area, I called several offices. I made a decision on one particular office based on the phone attendee. She asked open ended questions and had a genuine interest in me and my symptoms. She acknowledged my reason for calling, showed empathy and expressed compassion for my situation. Because of these reasons I made the appointment because I figured the doctor would also be this way. When I visited the office, the reception used my name several times, came from behind the window to hand me the forms and showed me how to work the kiosk to sign in. I walked out of there feeling like this practice is truly committed to their patients and I even mentioned to the doctor this was the best experience I have ever had in an office…this was after a SHOT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-smiling-over-the-phone&quot;&gt;The Power of Smiling Over The Phone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a smile widens on a phone call, and no one is there to see it, does it make a sound? Yes, it does. The advice of smiling over the phone has been around for years, but it’s amazing how many people don’t put it into practice. Besides teaching your team the importance of smiling, set little things to help them develop the habit. Like having a mirror on their computer or having little reminders near the phone…”Shoulders Back. Smile” is an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the telephone is more than likely the first “voice” experience potential patients have with your medical practice. So needless to say the experience must be an exceptional one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone by the third ring to avoid patients going to voicemail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Script a greeting for your staff to use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone with a big smile on your face…the caller on the other end will appreciate it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train your staff to encourage the caller to schedule an appointment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no mystery when it comes to converting phone calls to new patients. It’s as easy as having empathy for the person on the other end of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsites For Medical Seo</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsites For Medical Seo" /><published>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html">&lt;p&gt;Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-microsite&quot;&gt;What is a Microsite?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to HubSpot, a microsite is an individual web page or small cluster of web pages that act as a separate entity for a brand. A microsite typically lives on its own domain, but some exist as a subdomain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsites can be used to help brands achieve a number of things. For example, some companies have used them to highlight a specific campaign or target specific buyer personas. Others have used them to tell a short story, or to inspire a specific call-to-action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-launch-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Launch Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not your practice should launch a microsite will really depend on its purpose. There are some instances where a microsite is a good idea, such as when a site is created to support a brand that is an extension of a parent company or when a company is running a special event or promotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s enough content available to make the microsite worthwhile, launching a separate microsite can be a great direction. However, if there isn’t enough content, this can hurt your goals rather than help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-seo-microsite-game&quot;&gt;The SEO Microsite Game.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some website owners think you can create a microsite, link back to the main website, get some traffic, and increase conversions. Seems like an easy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has determined sites created for the sole purpose directing back to website with back links, or to boost certain keywords, is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/black-hat-seo&quot;&gt;black hat SEO&lt;/a&gt; tactic and looks spammy. Not only that, but Google considers sites like this to be extremely low quality. And remember, Google penalizes sites they deem to be low quality. To avoid a penalty, it’s best to avoid setting up microsites unless it’s for branding purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-say-no-to-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Say No to Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes time and effort to create and optimize the content for microsites. Basically the same steps you took to set up your main site still applies, and they can take just as long. Imagine going through that for more than one site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search engines rank sites that have lots of good, quality content. If you’re creating microsites your practice’s content will be spread out. Your content is better off gaining traction on your main website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While microsites can serve legitimate purposes, it’s not recommended to use them solely for SEO. For SEO, focus on getting your main website rank high by producing quality, well optimized content and building relevant links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save yourself time and avoid the headache of creating tons of mini sites to boost your SEO. Get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about our platform to help you grow your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will design your website so you can showcase your work with a video or photo gallery. Additionally, we can add our review tool to help you get reviews from your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make your practice stand out from the rest of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Are Medical Keywords Important</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Are Medical Keywords Important" /><published>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall the days where if I said I was looking up symptoms I would have been deemed a hypochondriac. It’s okay…I’m not alone. Statistics show &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchengineland.com/77-percent-of-online-health-seekers-start-at-search-engines-pew-study-145105&quot;&gt;77% of consumers now use search engines&lt;/a&gt; to conduct research before consulting a doctor and a surprising number of these people see a doctor about the results they find during their search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Google accommodating billions of users with top-notch, reliable medical information in certain search results, it’s never been more important for practices to provide exceptional medical content to compete for common, high-volume search terms in your field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re evaluating how to stand out in these search terms, one of the key factors you should be considering is a keyword or keyword phrase strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-a-keyword&quot;&gt;What’s a Keyword?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact definition states a &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/learn/seo/what-are-keywords&quot;&gt;keyword or keyword phrase&lt;/a&gt; is a query term entered into a search engine or website by patients. A keyword can be a single word or a series of words. It’s the search term you want to rank for with a certain page. So when people search for a keyword or phrase in Google or other search engines, they should find the page on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone searches Google for “how to fix gap teeth without braces” Google works to discern what the user is looking for, and it returns a list of web pages with this topic. If your website uses the exact phrase the user searched for as a keyword, part of the phrase (“gap teeth”), or a related phrase (i.e. “teeth gaps,” “braces”) Google is more likely to show the user your websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/Keywords3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google works to discern what the user is looking for.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-keywords-so-important&quot;&gt;Why Are Keywords So Important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put…ROI. Choosing the right keyword phrases and using them correctly for SEO is quite frankly the easiest and most effective way to get more users to your website. SEO is important to your practice’s success, and keywords play a major role in the SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/Keywords2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SEO is important to your practice’s success.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People will find their way onto your pages in a variety of ways, including social media and direct traffic to name a few. But, in today’s market, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/search-engines-more-traffic-publishers-social-media-2017-2018-2&quot;&gt;search generates the biggest share of traffic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-should-your-practice-start&quot;&gt;Where Should Your Practice Start?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless if you’re taking the first step to or making adjustments to an up and running SEO strategy, the best place to start is to find the right long-tail keywords. Long-tail keywords allow small and medium sized practices to stand out and boost your medical practice’s ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-short-taillong-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;What are Short-Tail/Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanised.co.uk/seo/short-tail-vs-long-tail-keywords/&quot;&gt;Short-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are limited to one or two words that cover a general topic, such as “breast lift”. Very general term, right? Yes, it will attract lots of search traffic, but it’s expensive and difficult to rank for especially if you’re new to the keyword/SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;Long-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are specific terms or phrases such as “best breast lift surgeon near me”. You may see less traffic, but if a patient is searching for this term then they are most likely closer to making a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short-tail keywords are still very useful to the growth of your practice. Long-tail keywords can help your medical practice play to your SEO strengths while building the authority to rank for short-tail keywords in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-should-medical-practices-choose-long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;How Should Medical Practices Choose Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start by utilizing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/search/how-google-autocomplete-works-search/&quot;&gt;Google’s search bar recommendations&lt;/a&gt; to understand how it suggests possible long tails. By checking out what potential keywords are most popular and what’s applicable to what you provided in terms of care, your practice can narrow down your list or add possibilities you have missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have time to walk through all of the items needed to plan and implement a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/ppc/&quot;&gt;paid advertising strategy&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to connect with us at DoctorLogic. Our software generates on average 30,000 relevant, unique exact match, long-tail keyword combinations for every campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Medical-PPC" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working" /><published>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html">&lt;p&gt;If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-do-you-actually-have-a-strategy&quot;&gt;1. Do you actually have a strategy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure or not feeling confident in what you think you have then you don’t have a strategy. To get started first and foremost, develop a plan of action. Without a plan, your setting your initiatives up for failure. Try not to throw out initiatives without developing a strategy first, and be sure to clearly define your objectives and ROI (return on investment) metrics… which leads me to my second point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-youre-not-tracking-kpi-metrics&quot;&gt;2. You’re not tracking KPI metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to prove your marketing strategy works, data has to back it up. Every successful marketing strategy needs expectations set and frequent monitoring on what, when, and how; what got launched, when it went live, and how it performed. Data-driven decision making is the key to successful marketing. Here’s a great reference for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.impactbnd.com/the-10-marketing-kpis-you-should-be-tracking&quot;&gt;which KPIs you should be tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-youre-wanting-results-now&quot;&gt;3. You’re wanting results NOW.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of the phrase, you need to learn how to crawl before you walk? The same applies for marketing initiatives. Marketing is powerful but results don’t happen overnight. To prove success for a marketing plan, focus on KPIs at the beginning and throughout the campaign, and ROI at the end. Often times, campaigns get shut down early because they didn’t prove value within the first few days. The key to avoiding this is to set attainable goals and learn from the results for your next campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-your-marketing-budget-is-mia&quot;&gt;4. Your marketing budget is M.I.A.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare practices are apprehensive towards spending marketing dollars. With the industry being highly competitive, allocating a certain percentage to marketing is a must. Additionally, when you track KPIs and ROI, you can make data-driven decisions to increase marketing dollars where it makes sense. For more help on how to allocate a marketing budget, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webascender.com/blog/how-to-allocate-your-digital-marketing-budget-in-2019/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-youre-living-the-definition-of-insanity&quot;&gt;5. You’re living the “Definition of Insanity”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of insanity is doing the same thing and expecting different results. Marketing initiatives are not one-and-done or set-it-and-forget-it. Constant optimization is required for optimal success. Try different initiatives as well. The more data you can collect on what worked and what didn’t, the more you can leverage it for your success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Types Content For Medical Practice</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Types Content For Medical Practice" /><published>2019-03-28T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-28T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blog-series&quot;&gt;Blog Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog series are great for multiple reasons. First of all, they allow you to offer your audience a ton of value by exploring a topic in-depth over a span of time. Second, they’re great for search engines, as you’ll have multiple pages/posts of content on a topic, increasing your authority in said topic in the eyes of search engine spiders (the bots that scan websites in order to properly rank them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what types of subjects should you write blog series on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for a specific procedure:&lt;/strong&gt; What the patient can do physically to prepare, what the procedure itself will entail, what s/he should purchase to have at home after the procedure, what drugs s/he will be taking, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At-home treatments:&lt;/strong&gt; Are there DIY, at-home, or natural treatments prospective patients can try in addition to the services you provide?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient testimonials:&lt;/strong&gt; Interview multiple patients who have had your most popular procedure. Ask them the same questions so prospective patients can get an idea of the different experiences people have had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;infographics&quot;&gt;Infographics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are visual learners, which is why infographics are so popular. Consider creating infographics based on statistics relevant to your practice (recovery time based on procedure, number of procedures+which types performed annually), as well as ones that are more instructional (what to expect during your recovery, how family+friends can help, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebooks&quot;&gt;EBooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer-form content should be “gated”, or only accessible when people enter their email address. This way you can move more people into your marketing funnel and move them down the pipeline to becoming actual patients. Ebooks can be extensions of blog series (in which you expand even further upon each individual subject) or more technical explanations of procedures from your practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video content is becoming increasingly popular because it’s incredibly effective: Videos are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vidyard.com/blog/science-behind-why-video-works/&quot;&gt;12 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to be watched than text is to be read, and content is &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.forrester.com/blogs/09-01-08-the_easiest_way_to_a_first_page_ranking_on_google/&quot;&gt;50 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to make it to the first page of Google results if it includes video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage video via:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doctor and staff introduction videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How certain machines are used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tour of your practice’s office/facilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patient testimonials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;newsletters&quot;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem old school to some, especially given strides in technology like virtual reality and artificial intelligence, but email is still one of the most effective forms of digital marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilize your email list by keeping both past and prospective patients in the loop. Highlight recent patient testimonials, popular blog posts, a staff member introduction video, and other content you’ve put hard work into making! This will help keep your practice top of mind, even if your recipients aren’t regularly visiting your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it: the 5 types of content needed to boost the brand for your medical practice. Content not only helps improve SEO rankings, it increases leads and gets prospects to convert into customers. Allow DoctorLogic to help you with your content marketing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Content-Marketing" /><summary type="html">Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Positive Patient Experience</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positive Patient Experience" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout and cleanliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workspace-resource.com/office-furniture/crucial-design-tips-for-creating-a-patient-focused-healthcare-facility/&quot;&gt;design tips&lt;/a&gt; to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with staff:&lt;/strong&gt; Friendliness can go a long way. When staff members are welcoming and inviting, patients feel valued and cared for. The front-desk staff must be well-trained and willing to provide information to the patient, such as expected wait time, bathroom location, any complimentary beverages, etc., Also keep in mind interactions with staff can be via phone as well. Finding ways to translate that sense of welcomeness through the phone can have the same affect towards their overall experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theberylinstitute.org/blogpost/947424/302264/Phone-Skills-Making-or-Breaking-The-Patient-Experience&quot;&gt;Here’s a great reference&lt;/a&gt; for scripting and guiding phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait times:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to wait. Restaurants and grocery stores have transformed online and mobile ordering so items are ready for pickup upon arriving. Amazon Prime ships same-day or two-day packages. Websites have to be speedy-quick or consumers will bounce due to loading time… it’s the new trend. When they’re used to skipping lines, sitting in a waiting area for minutes to hours on end, tries their patience. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.medicalgps.com/how-long-will-you-wait-4-simple-tips-for-easing-the-wait-experience/&quot;&gt;97% of patients&lt;/a&gt; get frustrated over wait times, and overall patient satisfaction decreases as wait time increases. If your wait times cannot be avoided, try finding ways to occupy their time. Some ideas are: free internet, TV, or latest up-to-date magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with the doctor(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Patients remember the way their doctor treated them. Friendliness doesn’t begin and end with the front-desk. Doctors need to be friendly and accommodating as well. Being personable makes patients feel valued. Take time to thoroughly explain their medical condition and open the discussion for questions. When a patient openly discusses their questions with you, it’s important to reciprocate the same openness and honesty by replying “that’s a great question, I’m glad you asked.” Providing a sense of partnership to patients promotes positive patient experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusively, there are many ways to create memorable experiences. It might be fun to switch up the experiences every now and then and ask for patient feedback. Ultimately, providing a positive, memorable experience not only benefits your patients, it benefits your practice as well. Positive experiences translate to patient retention and practice growth. The ultimate practice goal, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><category term="Reputation-Management" /><summary type="html">Layout and cleanliness: The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some design tips to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build Brand For Medical Practice</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/build-brand-for-medical-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build Brand For Medical Practice" /><published>2019-03-22T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/build-brand-for-medical-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/build-brand-for-medical-practice.html">&lt;p&gt;Branding your practice will affect everything from language and marketing to your website, office and promotional materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you start defining your brand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;branding-your-practice&quot;&gt;Branding Your Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of branding, do you think only of a business logo, flyers, brochures and a mission statement? Yes, these items should be a part of your branding strategy, but they are not the only things that make up a brand. When you are creating your brand, you must ask yourself, “What makes me stand out from other doctors? Do I have special equipment or have a special technique?” These are things that will set you apart. You must use your uniqueness to create your branding position. Other things you should include while building your brand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is your target audience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have a logo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does your SEO strategy look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;define-a-feeling&quot;&gt;Define a Feeling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What feeling do you want to convey to patients? Is your practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formal?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down to earth?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playful/tongue-in-cheek?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High-tech focused?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First pinning down the feeling or vibe you want to convey is important, as this will guide the rest of your branding exercise. One way to determine this feeling for your practice is to define your unique value proposition: What makes you different from other, similar practitioners? What compliments do you consistently receive from current or former patients? What is the common, positive thread between this feedback?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;choose-colors--typefaces&quot;&gt;Choose Colors &amp;amp; Typefaces&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve determined how you want your patients to see you, think visually. What colors will help portray that feeling? Choose two to three colors at most and save the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.color-hex.com/&quot;&gt;hex codes&lt;/a&gt; for future use. Next, do the same with &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontjoy.com/&quot;&gt;typefaces&lt;/a&gt;, choose two to three at most as well. Be consistent with how you’re using colors and typefaces throughout your practice. For example, what color and typeface will H1 headers be? What about H2 headers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;compile-an-image-library&quot;&gt;Compile an Image Library&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, start to compile an image library with images that are aligned with your brand. You can find some stunning images on the following stock photo sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free Sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thestocks.im/&quot;&gt;The Stocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paid sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shutterstock.com/&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.istockphoto.com/mx/en&quot;&gt;iStock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigstockphoto.com/&quot;&gt;BigStock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images you select for your library should align with your brand in terms of content, composition, and color scheme. Want your images to look more cohesive? Try applying the same filter to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-will-this-be-used&quot;&gt;Where Will This Be Used?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All aspects of your brand should be used throughout your practice, including your:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt; Web pages, blog posts, call-to-action buttons, downloadable assets like white papers, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Outlets:&lt;/strong&gt; Social media sites, email marketing banners, paid ads, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literature:&lt;/strong&gt; Brochures, checklists, patient registration forms, direct mail, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office:&lt;/strong&gt; Artwork, furniture, signage, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-perks-of-building-a-high-impact-brand&quot;&gt;The Perks of Building a High Impact Brand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing a brand for your practice and ensuring it’s consistent throughout all outlets will increase brand awareness and ultimately make your practice more recognizable and appealing to prospective patients. That’s because consistency builds confidence–an important factor especially when it comes to the medical field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this patient confidence and trust also comes loyalty and referrals, which can be incredibly important in today’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/reputation-management-for-doctors-in-a-digital-world.html&quot;&gt;digital world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-importance-of-delivery&quot;&gt;The Importance of Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t realize any of these benefits, however, if you don’t deliver on the brand promise you instill in your practice. Branding and consistency only go so far–you have to ensure you and your team members are committed to providing patients with the experience you market to them in order to have a truly high impact brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-closing&quot;&gt;In Closing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a strong brand will help with the growth of your practice. Your brand is a unique entity that is an unspoken promise about your practice. If you have any questions on the factors needed to build a strong web presence, contact us. We love to help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Branding your practice will affect everything from language and marketing to your website, office and promotional materials.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 03 20 healthcare digital marketing metrics</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-03-20-Healthcare-Digital-Marketing-Metrics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 03  20 healthcare digital marketing metrics" /><published>2019-03-20T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-03-%2020%20Healthcare%20Digital%20Marketing%20Metrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-03-20-Healthcare-Digital-Marketing-Metrics.html">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to marketing your business, how do you know what’s effective and what isn’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to digital marketing, knowing if your efforts are worthwhile can be a mystery if you don’t know what marketing metrics you should be measuring. These metrics are important because they help demonstrate ROI, and proving there’s a return on your marketing strategy is important if you want to keep your marketing budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, let’s run through what you need to consider before measuring, as well as some of the most important healthcare digital marketing metrics to monitor so that you can prove ROI and fine tune your marketing activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before-you-measure-what-to-consider&quot;&gt;Before You Measure: What to Consider&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, you need to have a clear picture of what you want visitors to do when they’re on your website. Create a funnel of specific actions you ideally want visitors to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, maybe you want new visitors who land on your site or read a blog post for the first time to sign up for your newsletter. A bit further down the funnel, you’ll probably want them to download a gated asset (think checklist, white paper, etc.), and finally, you’d like them to book an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a more specific example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You work for an orthopedic surgeon who specializes in sports medicine. You write a series of blog posts on the most common sports injuries, all of which have a call to action (CTA) at the end urging people to sign up for the practice’s newsletter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Within the newsletter, you promote a white paper on “What to Expect Before and After Knee Surgery” that gives detailed insight into pre-op procedures, the actual surgery, and what patients can expect post-op, including recovery time. Newsletter recipients are encouraged to download this white paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On your website and within your newsletter, you have a button that says “Schedule a Consultation” where people can easily make an appointment with the surgeon. Now that your audience is more informed, you hope they will finally decide to come into the office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a well-thought out funnel with specific actions you want prospects to take, you can measure them. This will help you avoid a common problem in the marketing world: measuring metrics but not knowing why they’re being measured. This is a waste of time and budget! Knowing exactly what to measure and why you’re measuring it will help your marketing team be more efficient and effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plan-in-place-metrics-to-keep-an-eye-on&quot;&gt;Plan in Place: Metrics to Keep an Eye On&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the steps in your funnel solidified, here are the metrics you want to keep an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lead-generation&quot;&gt;Lead Generation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many new leads are you generating? It’s important to keep people in your marketing funnel, but it’s also important to keep bringing in new blood. Is your strategy successfully attracting new prospects? If so, where are they coming from? What channel is the best at bringing them to your site and getting them to convert?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;click-through-rate-ctr&quot;&gt;Click Through Rate (CTR)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people are actually clicking on the things you want them to? In the example above, this would be the “Sign Up for Our Newsletter”, “Download the White Paper”, and “Schedule a Consultation” buttons. This will show you if your content is moving people enough to take action. If not, it’s time to reassess your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-foundational-elements-of-content-marketing.html&quot;&gt;content strategy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cost-per-lead-cpl&quot;&gt;Cost Per Lead (CPL)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much is all of this costing you? Cost per lead should be broken down by channel and campaign (this applies not only to your digital marketing strategy, but to all marketing efforts including direct mail, referrals, etc.). With regards to digital marketing, see what campaigns and channels (social media, email marketing, etc.) are giving you the most bang for your buck (i.e. the most leads for the least amount of money).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-final-word&quot;&gt;The Final Word&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, knowing what to measure and why you’re measuring it will give you and your team better visibility into which digital marketing activities are most effective at acquiring new prospects and converting them into actual patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">When it comes to marketing your business, how do you know what’s effective and what isn’t?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Doctor Reputation Management</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/doctor-reputation-management.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doctor Reputation Management" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/doctor-reputation-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/doctor-reputation-management.html">&lt;p&gt;For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do to better manage your online reputation and how do you respond when you do in fact receive a negative review?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-your-reputation-from-the-get-go&quot;&gt;Managing Your Reputation from the Get Go&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of your business lives online, so you should be prepared to take the proper steps to ensure you’re putting your best foot forward from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-website&quot;&gt;Your Website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Populate your website with positive reviews from happy patients. You can have a dedicated testimonials page if you like, but I recommend having them sprinkled throughout your website. A few on your About page, a couple more on your Contact page, etc. will make them visible no matter where a visitor goes on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-social-profiles&quot;&gt;Your Social Profiles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important social network to pay attention to in terms of reviews is Facebook. That’s because Facebook has a built-in section where people can review you. When it comes to these reviews, &lt;em&gt;respond to them immediately&lt;/em&gt;, both positive and negative. There’s nothing worse than leaving a negative review unanswered, and for a long amount of time, on a popular social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;review-websites&quot;&gt;Review Websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review websites include the sites I mentioned before, Yelp and Google, but also physician-specific review websites like RateMDs, HealthGrades, and Vitals. First of all, if you haven’t claimed your profile on one of these sites yet, do so now. You want to be able to manage your information on all of these sites before someone tarnishes your name without you even knowing about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responding-to-a-negative-review&quot;&gt;Responding to a Negative Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, at least one negative review is bound to come your way. This can be disheartening and feel personal, but it’s important to &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; respond in a professional manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a recommended course of action when you see you’ve received a negative review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond ASAP:&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you respond, the less harm will be done. Instead of someone solely reading the negative review, they also get to see your response. In the case I mentioned earlier, if someone were to read the negative review of the doctor’s office, the office manager or doctor could quickly respond that it was a problem with that person’s individual insurance plan, not the doctor. These quick responses and resolutions may even move the reviewer to remove the review entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always be professional:&lt;/strong&gt; As I mentioned earlier, we are human; we take things personally even if we maybe shouldn’t. Don’t let that turn you into a raging internet troll! Take a few hours, maybe even a day, to absorb the review and formulate a response. I know in #1 I said respond ASAP, but it’s always better to take a little bit longer and respond appropriately than to respond immediately and unprofessionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a professional in today’s world can mean people splashing your name around the internet, saying whatever they want with impunity. Don’t take it to heart, and don’t let it affect your business. Try your best to be on top of your digital reputation management from the get go, and when that inevitable negative review does come your way, take it in stride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reputation-Management" /><summary type="html">For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drive More Bariatric Patients</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/drive-more-bariatric-patients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drive More Bariatric Patients" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/drive-more-bariatric-patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/drive-more-bariatric-patients.html">&lt;p&gt;Only 1% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bariatricsurgerynewjersey.com/why-only-1-percent-patients-choose-bariatric-surgery/&quot;&gt;eligible patients&lt;/a&gt; choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, when I’m nervous about something I have a tendency to research to ease my nervousness. I’m not an anomaly. Today’s consumer is digital savvy and turn to Google to find everything. Potential patients are not ignoring Google when it comes to important searches and this includes weight loss surgery. And if you’re Bariatric practice is not sitting at the &lt;strong&gt;top&lt;/strong&gt; of Google’s search ranking, then it’s &lt;strong&gt;buried&lt;/strong&gt; under a list of other Bariatric providers and needless to say, &lt;em&gt;that’s not good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-fix-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you fix this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient acquisition strategy is a great place to start. In order to acquire new Bariatric patients you need to address the process of finding a lead, turning the lead into a prospect and then turning them into patients. I know this sounds like a long process, but actually finding lead and prospects isn’t as difficult as it may seem. There’s really no shortage, the challenge is getting them through the final stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-get-on-the-same-digital-page&quot;&gt;Let’s Get On The Same Digital Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-healthcare-marketing-trends.html&quot;&gt;January 15 blog&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the healthcare marketing trend providers should look at to grow their practice in 2019. These tips are a great direction when you’re looking to build your marketing plan. Today, let’s dive into some items related to patient acquisition. From educating the right Bariatric patient, interacting with them and of course following up properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve all heard “Content is King”. This is not going away. As matter of fact, having more unique and quality content gives opportunity to rank well in search. Add useful content to your website that your visitors will consider valuable, such as downloadable tip sheet, blogs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries/&quot;&gt;before and after photo galleries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often do you get frustrated with trying to find information on a website and decide it would be easier to refine your search in Google? Personally, I’m guilty of this. Adding call to actions can ease this frustration and is the best approach to meet patients where they are in the purchasing journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patient has found your website. Now make it easy for them to click to your contact page where they can ask for more information, or participate in a live chat. Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/chat/&quot;&gt;managed chat service&lt;/a&gt; to connect with visitors to your site 24/7. Providers who use chat are seeing a 40% increase in leads!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educating potential patients should not stop once they leave your website. And part of the buyer journey is following up properly. Give your site visitors opportunity to share their email addresses by offering free content that is engaging and can be used often, like a downloadable recipe book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide all the facts they need about bariatric surgery in an online bariatric surgery seminar. This is a great introduction and helps with providing the right content to the patient. Of course, this is a not meant to be a replacement for the in-person seminar, but a great introduction to your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And of course, the foundation of your strategy is your website. If your website is not &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-things-every-website-must-have.html&quot;&gt;optimized properly&lt;/a&gt;, it will miss the mark on being found and providing the right experience discussed in the other 5 tips. Check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot;&gt;website’s SEO&lt;/a&gt; to make sure potential patients are finding you when they conduct online searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><summary type="html">Only 1% of eligible patients choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.</summary></entry></feed>