<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-10T02:23:54+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>DoctorLogic provides online marketing tools for the medical industry, primarily to specialty doctors and dentists who own their practice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Healthcaremarketingplan</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HealthcareMarketingPlan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Healthcaremarketingplan" /><published>2019-05-03T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HealthcareMarketingPlan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HealthcareMarketingPlan.html">&lt;p&gt;If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-do-you-actually-have-a-strategy&quot;&gt;1. Do you actually have a strategy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure or not feeling confident in what you think you have then you don’t have a strategy. To get started first and foremost, develop a plan of action. Without a plan, your setting your initiatives up for failure. Try not to throw out initiatives without developing a strategy first, and be sure to clearly define your objectives and ROI (return on investment) metrics… which leads me to my second point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-youre-not-tracking-kpi-metrics&quot;&gt;2. You’re not tracking KPI metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to prove your marketing strategy works, data has to back it up. Every successful marketing strategy needs expectations set and frequent monitoring on what, when, and how; what got launched, when it went live, and how it performed. Data-driven decision making is the key to successful marketing. Here’s a great reference for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.impactbnd.com/the-10-marketing-kpis-you-should-be-tracking&quot;&gt;which KPIs you should be tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-youre-wanting-results-now&quot;&gt;3. You’re wanting results NOW.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of the phrase, you need to learn how to crawl before you walk? The same applies for marketing initiatives. Marketing is powerful but results don’t happen overnight. To prove success for a marketing plan, focus on KPIs at the beginning and throughout the campaign, and ROI at the end. Often times, campaigns get shut down early because they didn’t prove value within the first few days. The key to avoiding this is to set attainable goals and learn from the results for your next campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-your-marketing-budget-is-mia&quot;&gt;4. Your marketing budget is M.I.A.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare practices are apprehensive towards spending marketing dollars. With the industry being highly competitive, allocating a certain percentage to marketing is a must. Additionally, when you track KPIs and ROI, you can make data-driven decisions to increase marketing dollars where it makes sense. For more help on how to allocate a marketing budget, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webascender.com/blog/how-to-allocate-your-digital-marketing-budget-in-2019/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-youre-living-the-definition-of-insanity&quot;&gt;5. You’re living the “Definition of Insanity”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of insanity is doing the same thing and expecting different results. Marketing initiatives are not one-and-done or set-it-and-forget-it. Constant optimization is required for optimal success. Try different initiatives as well. The more data you can collect on what worked and what didn’t, the more you can leverage it for your success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highimpactbrand</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HighImpactBrand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highimpactbrand" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HighImpactBrand</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/HighImpactBrand.html">&lt;p&gt;Branding your practice will affect everything from language and marketing to your website, office and promotional materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you start defining your brand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;branding-your-practice&quot;&gt;Branding Your Practice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think of branding, do you think only of a business logo, flyers, brochures and a mission statement? Yes, these items should be a part of your branding strategy, but they are not the only things that make up a brand. When you are creating your brand, you must ask yourself, “What makes me stand out from other doctors? Do I have special equipment or have a special technique?” These are things that will set you apart. You must use your uniqueness to create your branding position. Other things you should include while building your brand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is your target audience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have a logo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does your SEO strategy look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;define-a-feeling&quot;&gt;Define a Feeling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What feeling do you want to convey to patients? Is your practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formal?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down to earth?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playful/tongue-in-cheek?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High-tech focused?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First pinning down the feeling or vibe you want to convey is important, as this will guide the rest of your branding exercise. One way to determine this feeling for your practice is to define your unique value proposition: What makes you different from other, similar practitioners? What compliments do you consistently receive from current or former patients? What is the common, positive thread between this feedback?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;choose-colors--typefaces&quot;&gt;Choose Colors &amp;amp; Typefaces&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve determined how you want your patients to see you, think visually. What colors will help portray that feeling? Choose two to three colors at most and save the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.color-hex.com/&quot;&gt;hex codes&lt;/a&gt; for future use. Next, do the same with &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontjoy.com/&quot;&gt;typefaces&lt;/a&gt;, choose two to three at most as well. Be consistent with how you’re using colors and typefaces throughout your practice. For example, what color and typeface will H1 headers be? What about H2 headers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;compile-an-image-library&quot;&gt;Compile an Image Library&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, start to compile an image library with images that are aligned with your brand. You can find some stunning images on the following stock photo sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free Sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thestocks.im/&quot;&gt;The Stocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paid sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shutterstock.com/&quot;&gt;Shutterstock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.istockphoto.com/mx/en&quot;&gt;iStock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigstockphoto.com/&quot;&gt;BigStock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images you select for your library should align with your brand in terms of content, composition, and color scheme. Want your images to look more cohesive? Try applying the same filter to all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-will-this-be-used&quot;&gt;Where Will This Be Used?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All aspects of your brand should be used throughout your practice, including your:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website:&lt;/strong&gt; Web pages, blog posts, call-to-action buttons, downloadable assets like white papers, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Outlets:&lt;/strong&gt; Social media sites, email marketing banners, paid ads, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literature:&lt;/strong&gt; Brochures, checklists, patient registration forms, direct mail, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office:&lt;/strong&gt; Artwork, furniture, signage, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-perks-of-building-a-high-impact-brand&quot;&gt;The Perks of Building a High Impact Brand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing a brand for your practice and ensuring it’s consistent throughout all outlets will increase brand awareness and ultimately make your practice more recognizable and appealing to prospective patients. That’s because consistency builds confidence–an important factor especially when it comes to the medical field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with this patient confidence and trust also comes loyalty and referrals, which can be incredibly important in today’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/reputation-management-for-doctors-in-a-digital-world.html&quot;&gt;digital world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-importance-of-delivery&quot;&gt;The Importance of Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t realize any of these benefits, however, if you don’t deliver on the brand promise you instill in your practice. Branding and consistency only go so far–you have to ensure you and your team members are committed to providing patients with the experience you market to them in order to have a truly high impact brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-closing&quot;&gt;In Closing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a strong brand will help with the growth of your practice. Your brand is a unique entity that is an unspoken promise about your practice. If you have any questions on the factors needed to build a strong web presence, contact us. We love to help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><summary type="html">Branding your practice will affect everything from language and marketing to your website, office and promotional materials.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5typesofcontent</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5TypesofContent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5typesofcontent" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5TypesofContent</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5TypesofContent.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blog-series&quot;&gt;Blog Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog series are great for multiple reasons. First of all, they allow you to offer your audience a ton of value by exploring a topic in-depth over a span of time. Second, they’re great for search engines, as you’ll have multiple pages/posts of content on a topic, increasing your authority in said topic in the eyes of search engine spiders (the bots that scan websites in order to properly rank them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what types of subjects should you write blog series on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for a specific procedure:&lt;/strong&gt; What the patient can do physically to prepare, what the procedure itself will entail, what s/he should purchase to have at home after the procedure, what drugs s/he will be taking, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At-home treatments:&lt;/strong&gt; Are there DIY, at-home, or natural treatments prospective patients can try in addition to the services you provide?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient testimonials:&lt;/strong&gt; Interview multiple patients who have had your most popular procedure. Ask them the same questions so prospective patients can get an idea of the different experiences people have had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;infographics&quot;&gt;Infographics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are visual learners, which is why infographics are so popular. Consider creating infographics based on statistics relevant to your practice (recovery time based on procedure, number of procedures+which types performed annually), as well as ones that are more instructional (what to expect during your recovery, how family+friends can help, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebooks&quot;&gt;EBooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer-form content should be “gated”, or only accessible when people enter their email address. This way you can move more people into your marketing funnel and move them down the pipeline to becoming actual patients. Ebooks can be extensions of blog series (in which you expand even further upon each individual subject) or more technical explanations of procedures from your practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video content is becoming increasingly popular because it’s incredibly effective: Videos are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vidyard.com/blog/science-behind-why-video-works/&quot;&gt;12 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to be watched than text is to be read, and content is &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.forrester.com/blogs/09-01-08-the_easiest_way_to_a_first_page_ranking_on_google/&quot;&gt;50 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to make it to the first page of Google results if it includes video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage video via:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doctor and staff introduction videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How certain machines are used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tour of your practice’s office/facilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patient testimonials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;newsletters&quot;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem old school to some, especially given strides in technology like virtual reality and artificial intelligence, but email is still one of the most effective forms of digital marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilize your email list by keeping both past and prospective patients in the loop. Highlight recent patient testimonials, popular blog posts, a staff member introduction video, and other content you’ve put hard work into making! This will help keep your practice top of mind, even if your recipients aren’t regularly visiting your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it: the 5 types of content needed to boost the brand for your medical practice. Content not only helps improve SEO rankings, it increases leads and gets prospects to convert into customers. Allow DoctorLogic to help you with your content marketing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Positivepatientexperience</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positivepatientexperience" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/PositivePatientExperience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout and cleanliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workspace-resource.com/office-furniture/crucial-design-tips-for-creating-a-patient-focused-healthcare-facility/&quot;&gt;design tips&lt;/a&gt; to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with staff:&lt;/strong&gt; Friendliness can go a long way. When staff members are welcoming and inviting, patients feel valued and cared for. The front-desk staff must be well-trained and willing to provide information to the patient, such as expected wait time, bathroom location, any complimentary beverages, etc., Also keep in mind interactions with staff can be via phone as well. Finding ways to translate that sense of welcomeness through the phone can have the same affect towards their overall experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theberylinstitute.org/blogpost/947424/302264/Phone-Skills-Making-or-Breaking-The-Patient-Experience&quot;&gt;Here’s a great reference&lt;/a&gt; for scripting and guiding phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait times:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to wait. Restaurants and grocery stores have transformed online and mobile ordering so items are ready for pickup upon arriving. Amazon Prime ships same-day or two-day packages. Websites have to be speedy-quick or consumers will bounce due to loading time… it’s the new trend. When they’re used to skipping lines, sitting in a waiting area for minutes to hours on end, tries their patience. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.medicalgps.com/how-long-will-you-wait-4-simple-tips-for-easing-the-wait-experience/&quot;&gt;97% of patients&lt;/a&gt; get frustrated over wait times, and overall patient satisfaction decreases as wait time increases. If your wait times cannot be avoided, try finding ways to occupy their time. Some ideas are: free internet, TV, or latest up-to-date magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with the doctor(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Patients remember the way their doctor treated them. Friendliness doesn’t begin and end with the front-desk. Doctors need to be friendly and accommodating as well. Being personable makes patients feel valued. Take time to thoroughly explain their medical condition and open the discussion for questions. When a patient openly discusses their questions with you, it’s important to reciprocate the same openness and honesty by replying “that’s a great question, I’m glad you asked.” Providing a sense of partnership to patients promotes positive patient experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusively, there are many ways to create memorable experiences. It might be fun to switch up the experiences every now and then and ask for patient feedback. Ultimately, providing a positive, memorable experience not only benefits your patients, it benefits your practice as well. Positive experiences translate to patient retention and practice growth. The ultimate practice goal, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Layout and cleanliness: The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some design tips to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Micrositesseo</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/MicrositesSEO.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Micrositesseo" /><published>2019-03-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/MicrositesSEO</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/MicrositesSEO.html">&lt;p&gt;asy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has determined sites created for the sole purpose directing back to website with back links, or to boost certain keywords, is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/black-hat-seo&quot;&gt;black hat SEO&lt;/a&gt; tactic and looks spammy. Not only that, but Google considers sites like this to be extremely low quality. And remember, Google penalizes sites they deem to be low quality. To avoid a penalty, it’s best to avoid setting up microsites unless it’s for branding purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-say-no-to-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Say No to Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes time and effort to create and optimize the content for microsites. Basically the same steps you took to set up your main site still applies, and they can take just as long. Imagine going through that for more than one site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search engines rank sites that have lots of good, quality content. If you’re creating microsites your practice’s content will be spread out. Your content is better off gaining traction on your main website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While microsites can serve legitimate purposes, it’s not recommended to use them solely for SEO. For SEO, focus on getting your main website rank high by producing quality, well optimized content and building relevant links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save yourself time and avoid the headache of creating tons of mini sites to boost your SEO. Get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about our platform to help you grow your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will design your website so you can showcase your work with a video or photo gallery. Additionally, we can add our review tool to help you get reviews from your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make your practice stand out from the rest of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">asy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bariatric</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Bariatric.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bariatric" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Bariatric</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Bariatric.html">&lt;p&gt;Only 1% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bariatricsurgerynewjersey.com/why-only-1-percent-patients-choose-bariatric-surgery/&quot;&gt;eligible patients&lt;/a&gt; choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, when I’m nervous about something I have a tendency to research to ease my nervousness. I’m not an anomaly. Today’s consumer is digital savvy and turn to Google to find everything. Potential patients are not ignoring Google when it comes to important searches and this includes weight loss surgery. And if you’re Bariatric practice is not sitting at the &lt;strong&gt;top&lt;/strong&gt; of Google’s search ranking, then it’s &lt;strong&gt;buried&lt;/strong&gt; under a list of other Bariatric providers and needless to say, &lt;em&gt;that’s not good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-fix-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you fix this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient acquisition strategy is a great place to start. In order to acquire new Bariatric patients you need to address the process of finding a lead, turning the lead into a prospect and then turning them into patients. I know this sounds like a long process, but actually finding lead and prospects isn’t as difficult as it may seem. There’s really no shortage, the challenge is getting them through the final stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-get-on-the-same-digital-page&quot;&gt;Let’s Get On The Same Digital Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-healthcare-marketing-trends.html&quot;&gt;January 15 blog&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the healthcare marketing trend providers should look at to grow their practice in 2019. These tips are a great direction when you’re looking to build your marketing plan. Today, let’s dive into some items related to patient acquisition. From educating the right Bariatric patient, interacting with them and of course following up properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve all heard “Content is King”. This is not going away. As matter of fact, having more unique and quality content gives opportunity to rank well in search. Add useful content to your website that your visitors will consider valuable, such as downloadable tip sheet, blogs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries/&quot;&gt;before and after photo galleries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often do you get frustrated with trying to find information on a website and decide it would be easier to refine your search in Google? Personally, I’m guilty of this. Adding call to actions can ease this frustration and is the best approach to meet patients where they are in the purchasing journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patient has found your website. Now make it easy for them to click to your contact page where they can ask for more information, or participate in a live chat. Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/chat/&quot;&gt;managed chat service&lt;/a&gt; to connect with visitors to your site 24/7. Providers who use chat are seeing a 40% increase in leads!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educating potential patients should not stop once they leave your website. And part of the buyer journey is following up properly. Give your site visitors opportunity to share their email addresses by offering free content that is engaging and can be used often, like a downloadable recipe book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide all the facts they need about bariatric surgery in an online bariatric surgery seminar. This is a great introduction and helps with providing the right content to the patient. Of course, this is a not meant to be a replacement for the in-person seminar, but a great introduction to your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And of course, the foundation of your strategy is your website. If your website is not &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-things-every-website-must-have.html&quot;&gt;optimized properly&lt;/a&gt;, it will miss the mark on being found and providing the right experience discussed in the other 5 tips. Check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot;&gt;website’s SEO&lt;/a&gt; to make sure potential patients are finding you when they conduct online searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Only 1% of eligible patients choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post List 2</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Post-List-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post List 2" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Post-List-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Post-List-2.html">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="healthcare-marketing" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation Test</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Reputation-Test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation Test" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Reputation-Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/Reputation-Test.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with this premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy teams are all alike; every unhappy team is unhappy in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the Anna Karenina principle? It’s derived from the famous first sentence of Leo Tolstoy’s seminal novel: “Happy families are all alike; every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is as follows: in order for a marriage to thrive, it must succeed in many different respects. If you and your partner argue about money, clash about parenting, or differ in political ideology, you’re doomed to unhappiness — no matter how happy you are in other areas of your relationship. Back in 340 BC, Aristotle emphasized the same principle a bit differently: “Men are good in but one way, but bad in many.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/christopher-ayme-157131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, success is not about doing just one thing correctly, but about avoiding many possible ways to fail. The Anna Karenina principle, popular in science and math, holds true for a lot of things in life — including effective teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If teams want to hit their goals, meet their deadlines, and surpass their KPIs, they need to succeed in all the critical ways — and avoid all the common pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is this magical recipe for effective teamwork? In the early days of building monday.com, we spoke with hundreds of managers and discussed all the unique reasons that teams are unhappy. We discovered seven factors that make or break a team’s success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Let’s start with this premise:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputationmanagementdoctors</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputationmanagementdoctors" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors.html">&lt;p&gt;For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do to better manage your online reputation and how do you respond when you do in fact receive a negative review?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-your-reputation-from-the-get-go&quot;&gt;Managing Your Reputation from the Get Go&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of your business lives online, so you should be prepared to take the proper steps to ensure you’re putting your best foot forward from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-website&quot;&gt;Your Website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Populate your website with positive reviews from happy patients. You can have a dedicated testimonials page if you like, but I recommend having them sprinkled throughout your website. A few on your About page, a couple more on your Contact page, etc. will make them visible no matter where a visitor goes on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-social-profiles&quot;&gt;Your Social Profiles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important social network to pay attention to in terms of reviews is Facebook. That’s because Facebook has a built-in section where people can review you. When it comes to these reviews, &lt;em&gt;respond to them immediately&lt;/em&gt;, both positive and negative. There’s nothing worse than leaving a negative review unanswered, and for a long amount of time, on a popular social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;review-websites&quot;&gt;Review Websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review websites include the sites I mentioned before, Yelp and Google, but also physician-specific review websites like RateMDs, HealthGrades, and Vitals. First of all, if you haven’t claimed your profile on one of these sites yet, do so now. You want to be able to manage your information on all of these sites before someone tarnishes your name without you even knowing about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responding-to-a-negative-review&quot;&gt;Responding to a Negative Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, at least one negative review is bound to come your way. This can be disheartening and feel personal, but it’s important to &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; respond in a professional manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a recommended course of action when you see you’ve received a negative review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond ASAP:&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you respond, the less harm will be done. Instead of someone solely reading the negative review, they also get to see your response. In the case I mentioned earlier, if someone were to read the negative review of the doctor’s office, the office manager or doctor could quickly respond that it was a problem with that person’s individual insurance plan, not the doctor. These quick responses and resolutions may even move the reviewer to remove the review entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always be professional:&lt;/strong&gt; As I mentioned earlier, we are human; we take things personally even if we maybe shouldn’t. Don’t let that turn you into a raging internet troll! Take a few hours, maybe even a day, to absorb the review and formulate a response. I know in #1 I said respond ASAP, but it’s always better to take a little bit longer and respond appropriately than to respond immediately and unprofessionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a professional in today’s world can mean people splashing your name around the internet, saying whatever they want with impunity. Don’t take it to heart, and don’t let it affect your business. Try your best to be on top of your digital reputation management from the get go, and when that inevitable negative review does come your way, take it in stride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="online-reviews" /><summary type="html">For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contentmarketing</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ContentMarketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contentmarketing" /><published>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ContentMarketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/ContentMarketing.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;valuable-content-targets-ideal-customers&quot;&gt;Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a healthcare provider, you want to be sure the content on your website provides value to potential and existing patients. Content can be used to drive patients where you would like them to visit on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dentist presenting a case study on a patient, and the struggle the patient faced before coming in contact with them will be a memorable way a reader can relate with the practice. This will create a positive image of your brand to a potential patient who may be struggling with the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/blog/visual-content-you-need-to-use-in-your-marketing-campaign/&quot;&gt;65% of people are visual learners&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also a good idea to use plenty of visual content on your site to target ideal patients and improve your online patient experience. A great example of this is a plastic surgeon using before and after galleries to display their procedure results, and videos of them discussing a specific procedure to better educate their patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the content on your website is boring, unorganized, and irrelevant, you will leave a bad first impression on your visitors thus leaving a negative view of your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boost-traffic-to-your-medical-site&quot;&gt;Boost Traffic to Your Medical Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a high rank in major search engine results is quality exposure for your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using frequently searched keywords in your industry will also help convert potential patients and increase the visibility of your brand. For instance, a woman in Dallas has a desire for fuller breasts. She searches “Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the title of a before and after photo in your site gallery reads “Amazing Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”. There is a high chance when she completes her search, your site could be at the top of the search results as the keyword in your gallery matches her search phrase. Not only will she head straight for the photo, but she’ll also check out your reviews page and possibly schedule a consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relevant content and keywords will help boost traffic to your site. Content is displayed the second those 590,000 search results pop up. If visitors are unable to find your site due to poor content on your website, then your patient volume is not where it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, give your patients a sense of assurance your practice is the right solution to their healthcare needs. After all, if patients are finding their way to your site, you need to find a way to keep them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in content marketing for your medical practice, contact us today to learn more. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers</summary></entry></feed>