<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-03T01:34:34+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>DoctorLogic provides online marketing tools for the medical industry, primarily to specialty doctors and dentists who own their practice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How To Build Dental Website Like Dso</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-dental-website-like-dso.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Build Dental Website Like Dso" /><published>2019-08-21T19:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T19:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-dental-website-like-dso</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-build-dental-website-like-dso.html">&lt;p&gt;Your website is a combination of the explanation of your culture, your business card, an old Yellow Pages ad. Review sites have now become a new and powerful “word of mouth” referral source, with many turning to such sites before choosing a new practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like your office projects your culture and image, so too should your website. Larger DSOs have figured this out and invest heavily in their digital presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you are not a DSO and want to compete on their level digitally? Jesse Barron and &lt;em&gt;DSO News&lt;/em&gt; caught up with Andre Riley, Chief Revenue Officer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt;, a company focused on building and optimizing healthcare websites, to learn more about how solo-practices, small groups, emerging groups and even mid-size DSOs can compete with even the biggest players online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Dre 350 350 (6).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Hello Andre, thank you for taking the time to sit down with &lt;em&gt;DSO News&lt;/em&gt;. As more patients arrive through digital channels, I thought it important to break down online marketing basics and help everyone, so that they can better compete online. What important features should be incorporated in every dental practice website?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Your website is a direct reflection of your business, representing a combination of your culture, mission, and image. Just like a business card, it serves to inform, direct, and create a powerful first impression. With the instant ability to educate your key audience and inform them of your offerings, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/medical-website-design&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Website Design&quot;&gt;a strategically-designed website &lt;/a&gt;can deliver compelling information, including credible reviews and photo galleries, which allows your audience to scour such sites before choosing a new practice. Larger DSOs have figured this out and invest heavily in their digital presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the basics of your website, it’s important to think like a consumer. Your website should tell who you are, what you do, and what separates you from the others. If you have an outdated, old, and hard to navigate website, consumers may question your ability to keep up with technology, which can then pass into questioning your skills and techniques. Remember you are educating and informing patients about your services, so the way your content is written needs to focus on answering questions and educating the consumer. Websites and technology are always changing. It’s important you have a website that can adapt to the market. Adaptability is key to winning in digital space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;What are the three top features popular today that you would say the majority of dental websites are not delivering?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; By far the most underutilized solution are &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content-multiplier/before-and-after-galleries&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Smile Galleries&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smile Galleries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Smile Galleries play an important role in adding fresh, unique, relevant content to a dentist’s website. Most web vendors simply add blogs, which is one way, but a Smile Gallery case gives you a detailed example of your exact patient. Detailing, the condition, treatment, age, gender, a timeline of results, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/content-multiplier-page.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smile Gallery image&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Smile Galleries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another solution is &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators/video-content&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Videos&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video designs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Adding video to the design of your website is one of the top trending design features we get several requests for. We have found a lot of other websites out there don’t incorporate this, but it’s considered a brand differentiator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/video-integration.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, incorporating &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/social-reputation&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Reputation Management&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; from across the web directly to their website. This is a feature some try to do, but it doesn’t get implemented correctly that helps for SEO. Some will use 3rd party plugins that will iframe the reviews, but it’s not actually built into the website. Creating a single place to have all your reviews and testimonials from across the web all in one place is very valuable and missing on several websites today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: Search engine optimization (SEO) is extremely important. It has been for years and will continue to be so for the years to come. Exactly what is dental specific and local SEO and explain how it is different, than say, if you were selling widgets nationwide.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; We agree that&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/search-amplifier&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic SEO&quot;&gt; SEO&lt;/a&gt; will continue to be an important strategy on the Digital Marketing landscape, but how you achieve good SEO will always continue to be a moving target. However, there are certain truths that remain constant and are especially important for Dental SEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/online-visibility.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Search&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dental patients want to find local providers that can serve them, which makes local SEO extremely important. Localized SEO efforts should focus on providing information like location, facilities, procedures, Doctors, reviews, etc. all while putting an emphasis on “in your backyard”. Also, since a majority of potential patients are using mobile devices for their searches, geo-located information and services are exponentially important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dental SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEO is SEO, right? Well not exactly. Dental SEO differs because of the 3 main factors. It must be medically accurate, it must be consumer consumable, and it must be personal. The way you achieve that is by writing content that is medical focused but can easily be understood by your average consumer. And it must be in a format that is easy to read and comprehend. You must take the technical and make it relatable, plus you must take the common and make it unique. And since Dental procedures are by nature a personal experience, it is important to combine your content with elements of social proof like “smile galleries” and “local reviews”. People will often search for images, reviews, etc. before they search for more information. They want validation first. All of these items make Dental SEO tactics unique and require an SEO practitioner/platform to be well versed in the industry and not just SEO alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: One tool that I always recommend to practices is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/products/local&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moz Local&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. What I like about the tool is that it helps ensure that practice information is correct on all of the big and important directory and review sites, of which many other websites then use the data of. The user can update addresses, phone numbers, website URLs, and mostly anything else. They have a tool for the solo business, as well as enterprises with 100+ locations. How important is it that these directories always have the correct information?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Local SEO is very important to the overall SEO strategy. When it comes to local SEO the accuracy of your local listings will have an impact. When you think of local listings, picture them as the new modern version of the yellow pages. The listings are ways the search engines know who you are, where you’re located, what you offer, and the times that you are open. When it comes to &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;**local ranking factors Google **&lt;/a&gt;looks at relevance, distance, and prominence. If your address is incorrect, it’s hard for Google to showcase your distance from the search. If your business description is wrong, this can impact your relevance to what the person is searching for. If your information is not accurate or consistent across these different sources, then you won’t rank or rank as high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: I cannot state enough the importance of generating positive online reviews for any practice. Please tell our readers some of the benefits of generating positive online reviews.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; 72% of patients say their first step in finding a new provider is checking online reviews. With 7 out 10 patients&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/social-reputation&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Reputation Management&quot;&gt; **checking reviews **&lt;/a&gt;to select a provider, it’s critical you know what those patients are seeing about you. Increasing the number of positive online reviews will have significant impact on moving those patients further down the buying journey. While it’s important to get positive reviews, it’s even more important those reviews are recent. Patients are reading the review but also looking at the date this review was posted. If you want to be in front of those patients at the early stages of the buying cycle, then you should have an ongoing review strategy implemented into your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/screen-reviews-manage (3).png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: Being able to generate and nurture online leads should be incorporated into the marketing plan of any dental practice. HIPAA compliance is super important here. Please explain how a practice or group can achieve HIPAA compliance with their website while safely generating and nurturing leads.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Protecting patient information should always be priority number 1 in your marketing. One of the first steps in doing so is making sure your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/website-management&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Website Management&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;website is HTTPS secure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; DoctorLogic did a study of 813 dental websites and found that 84% of the websites were not secure. This was staggering because this opens the opportunity for information to be stolen through your website. While practices would like to gain as much information about the patient when they submit a lead, you have to make sure you are protecting that information as its transmitted from your website to your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re laying the groundwork for your site, these are the major points you need to remember for HIPAA compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure sockets layer (SSL) protection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full data encryption (especially during transfers)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full data backup with encryption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Permanent deletion options for all data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restricted, specific access for admins and users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regular password changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data breach protocol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appointed HIPAA compliance officer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prominent, published HIPAA policy on site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HIPAA business associate agreement with site host and other vendors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more precautions you need to take for a HIPAA-compliant site, but these 10 are the most important starting points. Google stresses the importance of a secure website, so much so they give a ranking boost secure sites. If your website is not HTTPS secure you should really question who you are using as your website provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: And to be clear, since HIPAA is such a murky subject for so many dental practices and groups, are DoctorLogic solutions HIPAA compliant and do you sign a &lt;em&gt;business associate agreement&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes and yes! DoctorLogic has been providing HIPAA secure websites since we started. We take protecting patient information very seriously. So much so, every DoctorLogic employee goes through HIPAA compliance training every year. We also provide business associate agreements as well, which can easily be found on our website, doctorlogic.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: Every dental website should have a blog. The big question is how often should a new blog post be published and what should it include? For instance, if I were writing a new blog post, I’d pick and highlight a problem, describe the solution, financing options, appointment availability and focus local SEO with city/town name(s) and zip code(s). Is there anything I am leaving out?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Those are great topics but also keep in mind consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators/content-marketing&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Content Marketing&quot;&gt;**producing content relevant **&lt;/a&gt;to the consumer. To elaborate, I would produce more content around problems patients face and the solutions your practice provides. The best practice when it comes to producing blogs is producing content based on how consumers search. For example, “5 ways to whiten your teeth” or “How much does Invisalign cost?” Financing is a great topic to write about because most consumers may not know it’s an available option. This will help from an SEO and keyword standpoint as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at your blog strategy is by a method called “Topic Clusters”. Topic clusters are a collection of interlinked articles around one umbrella topic. They ultimately allow you to provide greater visibility for search engines to identify your content. So, for example, let’s take financing as the umbrella topic or also known as main topic. Your cluster topics can be “How much does X cost” “How do I get financing for smile makeover” “How do I apply for financing”. This overall strategy is strong because it allows you to produce strong relevant content rather than trying to create one single large blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should post a&lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators/content-marketing&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Content Marketing&quot;&gt; **new blog **&lt;/a&gt;once per week. Some people will say 3 times, but what we have found at DoctorLogic is our most effective results and strategies have been producing one post per week. We do offer an option for 2 posts per week, which is sometimes a better fit for a practice who offers a large number of different services and buyer personas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/content-marketing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: How important is design in 2019? I ask because I am one of those people who does their research online. I initially start with the review sites and end up on the company’s website. If I am not impressed by their website, then I do not put much faith in their business. I figure they either do not have enough business to invest in a website refresh or that they have not adapted to modern times. For instance, if I were looking for a dentist and it looks like their website was last refreshed in 2008, I am going to wonder when everything was last refreshed, too. I know I am not alone. Do you have statistics from recent website refreshes that validate my own conclusions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; You hit the nail on the head. This is absolutely right! Your website is the first visual impression you give someone when they visit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.googleblog.com/2012/08/users-love-simple-and-familiar-designs.html&quot;&gt;**Google did a study **&lt;/a&gt;in less than 50 milliseconds, users build an initial “gut feeling” that helps them decide whether they’ll stay or leave. If the website is outdated and doesn’t look similar to other modern websites consumers visit (e.g., Amazon, Zilllow, Apple, Target, Nordstrom, etc.) in their everyday lives, then they will pass judgement immediately on you. Most practices put emphasis on the decor and design inside the practice, but never put the same emphasis on their website. Patients will visit your website first before they ever step foot in your practice. In order to increase the number leads your website produces one key step is creating a web design that reaches new levels of interaction with your audience. There are 3 core things to think about when it comes to the look of your website and your audience. You must: Design for Humans, Design for Emotions, and Design to Tell a Story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/email-blast-designs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: Let’s talk white space. How great is it? Through our professional relationship, I know that you are fans of white space, too. Why is white space important? What message does it send to the visitor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; More and more designers (and clients) are moving toward the direction of giving white space the appreciation it deserves and it’s with good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White space plays an important role and serves a purpose for both design and user-experience. Though white is the common choice or color for white space, it’s not limited to just white. It can be a solid color or a blurred background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does white space give websites the simple, clean, minimalist look and feel that is so desired in current design aesthetics, but it also allows content to be more digestible and accessible to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With website layouts, sometimes the old saying “less is more” can be your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthline.com/health/left-brain-vs-right-brain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;human brain is predominantly right or left “sided.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;This means that two people are able to differently interpret the same thing while both being correct based on how their brain processes it. How important is it to address both right and left side minded people in both design and written content?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s very important to make sure your website appeals to both types of audience. Everyone has different marketing styles. Some people prefer colorful, expressive pieces and others prefer to focus on fact and reason. When it comes to marketing your practice there’s no magic formula that states leaning towards one method is more effective than the other. The ideal method depends on the product and the intended consumer base. 65% of the population are visual learners so with our websites, we include large images, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/growth-accelerators&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Growth Accelerators&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;videos and Smile Galleries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but we also write copy that tells your practice’s story for the other 35%. Your website should speak loudly as well as speak visually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: I greatly appreciate the time you’ve taken to speak with me on behalf of our readers. I reached out for an interview because I was reviewing your site before we did an email campaign. Since I am right side mind dominant, I was immediately drawn in by the designs in your portfolio. Then, as I was researching more, I realized that you can help practices of all sizes establish a &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; online presence at a reasonable price. So, in exchange for your time today, please tell our readers how DoctorLogic specifically can help them up their digital game.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AR:&lt;/strong&gt; Thank you for the compliment on our designs. Our team puts a lot of effort into designing sites that are highly appealing, follow all online best practices, and convert browsers to patients at a very high rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 important areas that all practices must consider when looking to enhance their digital footprint, and DoctorLogic is the leader in helping Doctor’s win online by focusing on these areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/optimized-marketing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Content, Content, Content&lt;/strong&gt;. All &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content-multiplier&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Content Multiplier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on site must be 100% unique per location. Unique content would (most importantly) include ALL procedures done at each location. The content should be medically accurate, but consumer focused. The content should also include procedure specific reviews, and robust before/after galleries of the Practice’s work. This would always be my #1 focus and highest priority. Our software can create up to 100X more Google-friendly content than a traditional agency website and we are able to target up to 50,000 keywords whereas most agencies target 50, 100 or maybe 300 keywords at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Conversion and Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;. DoctorLogic designs sites that are focused on &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/lead-generator&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Lead Generator&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;converting browsers into patients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This ties in directly with content and how the story is told on the site. All DoctorLogic sites have call tracking, email forms, and many have chat. The more avenues of communication available to consumers the higher conversion opportunity. And finally, you must track each lead all the way down to source and page specific conversion and provide reporting per location and in any rollup format needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;. DoctorLogic uses all &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/medical-website-design&quot; title=&quot;DoctorLogic Websites&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;web best practices like responsive design, https pages, fast loading pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (especially on mobile), A/B testing, semantic markup, before and after galleries, reviews, etc. DoctorLogic does Not use a free CMS solution like Wordpress, we invented our own healthcare specific platform with all HIPAA compliance etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Future-proofing&lt;/strong&gt;. At DoctorLogic, updates are FREE and happen frequently. We never want our Doctor Partners to be behind online. Online best practices and tactics change a lot, so we want to give our Practices an advantage in their local market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the key areas to digital success, and DoctorLogic is laser-focused on helping our Practices dominate online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JB: Great. And if a solo-practice dentist or even a large DSO wanted to get in touch, who should they contact?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about DoctorLogic check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;doctorlogic.com&lt;/a&gt; or email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sales@doctorlogic.com&quot;&gt;sales@doctorlogic.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><category term="Website" /><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Your website is a combination of the explanation of your culture, your business card, an old Yellow Pages ad. Review sites have now become a new and powerful “word of mouth” referral source, with many turning to such sites before choosing a new practice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inc 5000 Press Release</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/inc-5000-press-release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inc 5000 Press Release" /><published>2019-08-15T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-15T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/inc-5000-press-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/inc-5000-press-release.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas, TX. August 15, 2019&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;em&gt;Inc.&lt;/em&gt; magazine ranked DoctorLogic #1285 on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/inc5000/2019/top-private-companies-2019-inc5000.html&quot;&gt;2019 Inc. 5000&lt;/a&gt; list, the most prestigious ranking of the nation’s fastest-growing private companies in America. The list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment—its independent small businesses. Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees on the Inc. 5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re beyond excited to have DoctorLogic as part of the prestigious Inc. 5000 list for the 2nd year in a row,” said Andre Riley, Chief Revenue Officer of DoctorLogic. “This award belongs to each and every person who works at DoctorLogic, our amazing clients, and everyone who helped support us along the way. Our team is very passionate about our products and services and I’m grateful and proud of all of their hard work. ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dallas-based software developer DoctorLogic, is a Patient Marketing Website platform that combines stunning designs, unique content, patient reviews, photo galleries, and more to grow medical practices through online marketing. The company’s three-year growth rate was 320%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only have the companies on the 2019 Inc. 5000 been very competitive within their markets, but the list as a whole shows staggering growth compared with prior lists. The 2019 Inc. 5000 achieved an astounding three-year average growth of 454 percent, and a median rate of 157 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The companies on this year’s Inc. 5000 have followed so many different paths to success,” says &lt;em&gt;Inc.&lt;/em&gt; editor in chief James Ledbetter. “There’s no single course you can follow or investment you can take that will guarantee this kind of spectacular growth. But what they have in common is persistence and seizing opportunities.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete results of the Inc. 5000, including company profiles and an interactive database that can be sorted by industry, region, and other criteria, can be found at www.inc.com/inc5000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About DoctorLogic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DoctorLogic’s all-in-one Website Marketing Platform was built to grow medical practices through stunning, responsive websites and diverse digital marketing strategies. Our technology helps doctors increase their internet leads with our patent-pending software that leverages their unique content, photo galleries, patient reviews, and more in a new way that creates up to 100X more Google-friendly indexed pages within their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact Keisha Dunstan at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kdunstan@doctorlogic.com&quot;&gt;kdunstan@doctorlogic.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html">Dallas, TX. August 15, 2019 – Inc. magazine ranked DoctorLogic #1285 on the 2019 Inc. 5000 list, the most prestigious ranking of the nation’s fastest-growing private companies in America. The list represents a unique look at the most successful companies within the American economy’s most dynamic segment—its independent small businesses. Microsoft, Dell, Domino’s Pizza, Pandora, Timberland, LinkedIn, Yelp, Zillow, and many other well-known names gained their first national exposure as honorees on the Inc. 5000.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Showcase Talent Morales</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Showcase Talent Morales" /><published>2019-08-07T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales.html">&lt;p&gt;When DoctorLogic set out to create a website product that would set a new standard in the medical industry, we knew the power behind our platform would likely reside within our photo gallery tool. This intuitive, easy-to-use, Google-friendly section of our websites has proven to be a fan favorite, allowing physicians to display their outcomes like never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently reached out to Dr. Rolando Morales, a plastic surgeon in Houston, to get his feedback on how he uses the gallery tool to shed some additional insight on this awesome feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DocLogic_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolando Morales, M.D.- Houston Plastic Surgeon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Morales specializes in cosmetic plastic surgery for the face, breast and body. In just over 2 years, he has has added over 360 photos of his case work with our tools and attributes this to his success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you find the DoctorLogic Before and After Gallery tool useful?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! It’s the most used tool by far of all components of the platform. It allows me to add new patient cases whenever I want, which adds unique and relevant pages to my website, just as if I had my own blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prior to coming on board with DoctorLogic, did you have a before and after gallery? If yes, what was it like in comparison to yours now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I had a gallery and it was extremely basic. In addition, it was tedious to use. In order to add patients to my gallery I had to go through the webmaster, submit photos, and case specifics. If I did not like the way it looked or read, I had to go back to the webmaster for changes. It was very time consuming as it took forever to get things posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the DoctorLogic tool, I can simply add cases to my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the DoctorLogic Before and After Photo Gallery Tool affected your practice with new or prospective patients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gallery pages are the most popular pages on my website. They are well laid out and organized, and I can put as many photos as I want on the page to display my case. I can do this anytime I want – day or night. I’m able to upload photos, create informative descriptions about what the patient wanted, and explain what I did to achieve these goals. It has helped me to educate prospective patients about the procedures I offer, while at the same time, show new clients specific cases and outcomes of procedures they are thinking about having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you add to the gallery?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to add about 5 new patient case studies per month. Truthfully, I’m so busy in the operating room, otherwise I’d add more! Even though the tool is easy to use, and very intuitive, you still want to make each case shine. So I do spend time making sure my photos are of good quality, and that I write detailed descriptions so that visitors to the page understand what took place during surgery. In addition, I think it is important to mix it up. 50 cases of the same procedure may or may not benefit me, but patient and procedure variety does. So I try and choose who and what I put on the site carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you find the gallery easy to use?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, very easy! I can upload photos myself, move them around, change the order, etc. The gallery tool has &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/gallery/5-easy-steps.html&quot;&gt;5-easy steps&lt;/a&gt; that walk you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your favorite aspect of the gallery tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, just having total control of my gallery is my favorite part of it all. The ease in moving around the order of photos, deleting them and adding more, and having the overall flexibility makes it seamless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You hear us use the phrases “tagging and keywords” as they pertain to the gallery pages. What is your take on this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not an SEO expert, but I know the procedures I offer, the techniques I perform, and the products I use during a given procedure. The tagging and keyword aspect of the platform allows me to put all of these search terms on my gallery page, which I know is beneficial to those who are searching. When someone is seriously considering a plastic surgery procedure, they want to know details and find someone like them to study the results. When they land on a case that has these very important details, it is very helpful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/screen-reviews-manage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any idea of the traffic you receive on your gallery pages? Do people mention them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do get good traffic on my gallery pages. In fact, many times during my consultations patients will pull out their phones and show me one of my galleries, or use my phone to take a screenshot of a case that they want to examine further. The great thing about the gallery tool is that the mobile site is perfectly scaled to show the side-to-side pics, which makes my consultations even easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you tell Doctors who use DoctorLogic’s platform, but who do not utilize the gallery tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use it! I can’t really imagine having my website and not taking full advantage of this outstanding tool. My advice would be to take good, consistent photos, and work to increase your volume of cases, as well as the variety and quality you incorporate into the gallery. Try and upload 5-10 per month, and watch your website and your business grow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since partnering with DoctorLogic, Dr. Morales saw a 2,944% increase in Page 1 keyword rankings, a 371% increase in website visitors, and a 179% increase in website leads. In addition to an improved website architecture and keyword ranking, &lt;strong&gt;the Before and After Photo Gallery brings in 74% of all page view traffic, with 27% leads coming strictly from the gallery page.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create stunning case-example pages in minutes with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic Gallery Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Before-After-Gallery" /><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><summary type="html">When DoctorLogic set out to create a website product that would set a new standard in the medical industry, we knew the power behind our platform would likely reside within our photo gallery tool. This intuitive, easy-to-use, Google-friendly section of our websites has proven to be a fan favorite, allowing physicians to display their outcomes like never before.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 29get More Website Visitors</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 29get More Website Visitors" /><published>2019-07-29T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-29T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s time to get more visitors to your medical practice’s website. That’s because more visitors equals more conversions from visitors to leads, and more leads becoming actual patients!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you increase website traffic? We’ve put together this list of five things you can do to start getting your visitor numbers up today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-things-that-get-more-visitors-to-your-website&quot;&gt;5 Things That Get More Visitors to Your Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-make-it-easy-for-people-to-find-you&quot;&gt;1. Make it easy for people to find you.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like common sense, but you’d be surprised by how many people unintentionally make their practice very hard to find online. Don’t try to get fancy with your website name or web address, keep it simple! What’s the name of your practice? When searching for domains online, try to use something as close to your practice name as possible. If it’s already taken, try to pick the one that’s most similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-lead-people-from-across-the-web-back-to-your-site&quot;&gt;2. Lead people from across the web back to your site.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating profiles on other sites, offering advice on platforms, and joining online groups and communities can help you and your practice gain more visibility online. Make sure you claim all profiles that already exist for your practice, including those found on RateMDs, Vitals, etc., as well as your physical practice on Google Maps. Next, ensure there’s a link to your practice website on all of the profiles you both claim and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-leverage-social-to-garner-patient-trust&quot;&gt;3. Leverage social to garner patient trust.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use social as a way to connect to patients on a more personal level. This type of interaction will improve patient trust and allow prospective patients to see your willingness to engage outside of the office, driving more people to your website. Also make sure you’re linking to your site from all your profiles, including LinkedIn, Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook. If you have a Facebook business page, use the CTA button at the top to take people directly to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-optimize-for-search-engines&quot;&gt;4. Optimize for search engines.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/posts/tag/SEO&quot;&gt;search engine optimization (SEO) before&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s worth noting here as well. Making your site easy for search engines to find and crawl will mean they’ll likely reward you by sending more website traffic your way. Some SEO best practices include utilizing local keywords, creating valuable content, improving page load time, including title, header, and image tags as well as meta descriptions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-make-your-site-user-friendly&quot;&gt;5. Make your site user-friendly.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people land on your site and soon realize it’s not user-friendly, they’ll quickly bounce off (in other words, they’ll leave). Want them to stick around and explore your site, see the procedures you offer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/leveraging-before-and-after-galleries.html&quot;&gt;Before and After photos&lt;/a&gt;, patient reviews, and more? Then ensure your site is user-friendly. You can do this by making your site easy to navigate, speeding up page load time (great for SEO and users alike!), using white space, ensuring it’s responsive and mobile-friendly, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ready-for-more-website-traffic&quot;&gt;Ready for More Website Traffic?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, you only want to employ these tactics once your website is up and running and has the look and feel that you want. If it doesn’t properly represent your medical practice’s brand and values, then you don’t want to drive traffic to it until it does. After all, the last thing you want is to misrepresent the important work that you do! Once your site is where you want it, then it’s time to start driving traffic to it in order to get more visitors, more conversions, more leads and ultimately more patients through your doors!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">It’s time to get more visitors to your medical practice’s website. That’s because more visitors equals more conversions from visitors to leads, and more leads becoming actual patients!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 22how To Conduct Reputation Audit</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 22how To Conduct Reputation Audit" /><published>2019-07-22T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit.html">&lt;p&gt;We live in an age where anyone can find out information about you with the click of a button. No longer do people have to ask their friends or go searching in the Yellow Pages. By simply typing your name into a search bar, prospective patients can learn a lot about you. So how do you know what they’re seeing and how can you control it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll outline a few ways you can do research into what your name returns online. This online audit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/reputation-management-for-doctors-in-a-digital-world.html&quot;&gt;your reputation&lt;/a&gt; will allow you to see what prospective patients are seeing, as well as better manage what shows up when you Google yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-one-conduct-an-online-search&quot;&gt;Step One: Conduct an Online Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, pretend you’re a prospective patient: type your name into different search engines to see what’s returned. A good idea is to check the top three search engines: Google, Bing, and Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at what’s returned on the first page of each search—what’s showing up? Ideally, your practice’s website is first, followed by a scholarly article you wrote or an association you’re a member of, some physician review sites, and then your social media pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-two-manage-your-pages&quot;&gt;Step Two: Manage Your Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on each link on the first page of each search result to see where it takes you. Ask yourself: do you own these pages? If so, are they showing you and your practice in the best light? You might be surprised by what’s still being returned by an online search; it could be an old practice website or even a personal blogging platform. Go in and edit or spruce up pages you think can be improved, update any outdated information, and delete or take offline those pages that are no longer relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the search returns pages you don’t own, who does? If they’re physician review websites, have you claimed your profile? See if the site provides this capability, and then create an account so you can see and manage reviews. If there’s a third-party website you don’t recognize with information about you and/or your practice, try contacting the website owner or administrator. Hopefully, the site has a contact page where you can easily find who you’re looking for. If not, you can usually find contact information in the footer of the website. Still no luck? Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whois.net&quot;&gt;WhoIs.net&lt;/a&gt;, type in the exact URL/web address, and you’ll be able to see the website registrar’s email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-three-separate-the-personal-from-the-professional&quot;&gt;Step Three: Separate the Personal from the Professional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a physician, seeing as your name is just as associated with your professional life as it is your personal one, it’s not unlikely for personal social media accounts or blogging platforms to be returned by search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to keep this from happening, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/removals?pli=1&quot;&gt;Google’s Content Removal page&lt;/a&gt; to request that they not show up in search results. You can also go into the settings of your personal social media profiles to see if you can select that they not be indexed by the search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, our online reputation is just as important—if not more so—as our offline one. That’s because the majority of your patients are probably first coming into contact with you online, and most likely via search engines. Conducting an online audit of your online reputation every three to six months will help ensure you’re putting your best digital foot forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reputation-Management" /><summary type="html">We live in an age where anyone can find out information about you with the click of a button. No longer do people have to ask their friends or go searching in the Yellow Pages. By simply typing your name into a search bar, prospective patients can learn a lot about you. So how do you know what they’re seeing and how can you control it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 17increase New Patients Smile Galleries</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 17increase New Patients Smile Galleries" /><published>2019-07-17T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries.html">&lt;p&gt;As a cosmetic dentist, there are many ways you can market your practice to potential patients. SEO, PPC, retargeting, social media, postcards, and magazines are the most common tactics used to get a dental practice’s brand known in the community. However, one of the most impactful ways to brand yourself is to display &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/products/smile-gallery-plugin/&quot;&gt;smile galleries&lt;/a&gt; on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before and after photos are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; important because they are one of the two key factors that set you apart from your competition. Patients who are actively looking for a cosmetic dental procedure often make decisions based on both galleries and reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the procedures involved in cosmetic or reconstructive cases. Typically, these are your cash-paying patients who bring value to your practice and often times, act as brand ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, displaying your before-and-after cases online allows potential patients to see your work vs. your competition’s work. This enables you to establish credibility and build trust to new visitors on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Value Behind A Smile Gallery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that approximately 7 out 10 patients looking to have a cosmetic procedure won’t call a practice to book a consultation if they aren’t able to view before-and-after photos on the practice’s website?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the “Look Book” inside your consultation room isn’t nearly as relevant today unless all of those cases are on your website. Additionally, many dentists use the smile galleries found on their website during new patient consultations by using a monitor or large TV to showcase their talent. This allows them to pull up cases that are similar to the needs of the new patient and show how they have helped countless others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a good “best practice” because if the consumer wants to think about it before committing, they know that they can go back to your website and look at your photos again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following strategy is currently helping AACD members all over the U.S. grow their online presence, grow their inbound lead volume, and grow their revenue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.) Patient Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to fully release the identity of your patient, but providing context around gender, age, and ethnicity on each of your cases helps your potential patients relate to your work. This is a good thing because it helps showcase your capabilities and they can see that you have helped others just like them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.) Procedure Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help them understand what procedure they had performed. A patient looking at a before-and-after smile doesn’t have your education and experience. With only showcasing the pictures, they don’t know if someone had implants or veneers. Make it easy and provide some context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.) Conditions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain what conditions someone had prior to coming to see you. Did they have gaps in their teeth, bad bite, cigarette-stained teeth, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.) Photos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider displaying two angles: a head shot so people can see the entire face/smile, and a close-up. If you have a difficult or complex case that required the patient to visit you for multiple treatments, you could take photos for each stage of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.) Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell the story. You don’t have to be an expert marketer and write a 500-word blog, but you can easily describe three key points so the potential patient can relate to your existing patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I. Explain WHY the patient came to see you. What problem were you solving?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II. Explain WHAT procedures you performed. What solution did you offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;III. Discuss that the patient had a positive outcome. What experience would new patients like to have? Explain that you can help them feel more confident when they smile, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This three-part storytelling is simple and follows basic psychology to selling. Patient had a problem, you had a solution, they had a positive outcome. You are helping website visitors connect the dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t displaying your galleries online or if you only have photos and aren’t using these five ways above to explain your work, consider signing up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/products/smile-gallery-plugin/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic Smile Gallery Trial&lt;/a&gt;. You can sign up today and begin using our software to upload your galleries and describe your cases inside your website. The best part is – it’s absolutely &lt;strong&gt;FREE for 1 year for all AACD members!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to begin? Contact DoctorLogic for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Content-Marketing" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">As a cosmetic dentist, there are many ways you can market your practice to potential patients. SEO, PPC, retargeting, social media, postcards, and magazines are the most common tactics used to get a dental practice’s brand known in the community. However, one of the most impactful ways to brand yourself is to display smile galleries on your website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients" /><published>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hour later, and no call back, so I called again. After the second ring, I was greeted with, “Dentist office, can you please hold.” Before I could respond I was put on hold. This was not a great experience…needless to say I hung up and did not call back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your front desk staff and the way they handle the first phone conversation can quite literally mean the difference between a thriving practice full of referrals and delighted patients and a practice struggling just to get by. Having friendly and sincere people representing your practice is the thing that will leave the most lasting impression on patients, especially new patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at a few behaviors that should be a part of your front desk process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;efficient-system-for-phone-calls-and-patient-arrivals&quot;&gt;Efficient system for phone calls and patient arrivals.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the voice and face of a doctor’s front office can be overwhelming, especially if your team is dealing with high call volume, and patient arrivals all at the same time. This is an opportunity to revisit your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;every-call-should-be-answered-before-the-third-ring&quot;&gt;Every call should be answered before the third ring.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure the phone is answered on brand, have a little script available. And if your staff has to put a caller on hold, it’s okay. First, make them feel comfortable by having your phone attendees introduce themselves, then ask permission to put the caller on hold or ask if they would prefer a call back. If a patient arrives while your attendant is on the phone, simply give them a nod and a smile and let them know you’ll be right with them. They will feel acknowledged and will wait to interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-about-first-impression&quot;&gt;It’s About First Impression.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While searching for an orthopaedic in my area, I called several offices. I made a decision on one particular office based on the phone attendee. She asked open ended questions and had a genuine interest in me and my symptoms. She acknowledged my reason for calling, showed empathy and expressed compassion for my situation. Because of these reasons I made the appointment because I figured the doctor would also be this way. When I visited the office, the reception used my name several times, came from behind the window to hand me the forms and showed me how to work the kiosk to sign in. I walked out of there feeling like this practice is truly committed to their patients and I even mentioned to the doctor this was the best experience I have ever had in an office…this was after a SHOT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-smiling-over-the-phone&quot;&gt;The Power of Smiling Over The Phone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a smile widens on a phone call, and no one is there to see it, does it make a sound? Yes, it does. The advice of smiling over the phone has been around for years, but it’s amazing how many people don’t put it into practice. Besides teaching your team the importance of smiling, set little things to help them develop the habit. Like having a mirror on their computer or having little reminders near the phone…”Shoulders Back. Smile” is an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the telephone is more than likely the first “voice” experience potential patients have with your medical practice. So needless to say the experience must be an exceptional one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone by the third ring to avoid patients going to voicemail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Script a greeting for your staff to use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone with a big smile on your face…the caller on the other end will appreciate it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train your staff to encourage the caller to schedule an appointment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no mystery when it comes to converting phone calls to new patients. It’s as easy as having empathy for the person on the other end of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsites For Medical Seo</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsites For Medical Seo" /><published>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html">&lt;p&gt;Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-microsite&quot;&gt;What is a Microsite?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to HubSpot, a microsite is an individual web page or small cluster of web pages that act as a separate entity for a brand. A microsite typically lives on its own domain, but some exist as a subdomain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsites can be used to help brands achieve a number of things. For example, some companies have used them to highlight a specific campaign or target specific buyer personas. Others have used them to tell a short story, or to inspire a specific call-to-action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-launch-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Launch Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not your practice should launch a microsite will really depend on its purpose. There are some instances where a microsite is a good idea, such as when a site is created to support a brand that is an extension of a parent company or when a company is running a special event or promotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s enough content available to make the microsite worthwhile, launching a separate microsite can be a great direction. However, if there isn’t enough content, this can hurt your goals rather than help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-seo-microsite-game&quot;&gt;The SEO Microsite Game.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some website owners think you can create a microsite, link back to the main website, get some traffic, and increase conversions. Seems like an easy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has determined sites created for the sole purpose directing back to website with back links, or to boost certain keywords, is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/black-hat-seo&quot;&gt;black hat SEO&lt;/a&gt; tactic and looks spammy. Not only that, but Google considers sites like this to be extremely low quality. And remember, Google penalizes sites they deem to be low quality. To avoid a penalty, it’s best to avoid setting up microsites unless it’s for branding purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-say-no-to-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Say No to Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes time and effort to create and optimize the content for microsites. Basically the same steps you took to set up your main site still applies, and they can take just as long. Imagine going through that for more than one site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search engines rank sites that have lots of good, quality content. If you’re creating microsites your practice’s content will be spread out. Your content is better off gaining traction on your main website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While microsites can serve legitimate purposes, it’s not recommended to use them solely for SEO. For SEO, focus on getting your main website rank high by producing quality, well optimized content and building relevant links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save yourself time and avoid the headache of creating tons of mini sites to boost your SEO. Get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about our platform to help you grow your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will design your website so you can showcase your work with a video or photo gallery. Additionally, we can add our review tool to help you get reviews from your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make your practice stand out from the rest of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Are Medical Keywords Important</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Are Medical Keywords Important" /><published>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall the days where if I said I was looking up symptoms I would have been deemed a hypochondriac. It’s okay…I’m not alone. Statistics show &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchengineland.com/77-percent-of-online-health-seekers-start-at-search-engines-pew-study-145105&quot;&gt;77% of consumers now use search engines&lt;/a&gt; to conduct research before consulting a doctor and a surprising number of these people see a doctor about the results they find during their search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Google accommodating billions of users with top-notch, reliable medical information in certain search results, it’s never been more important for practices to provide exceptional medical content to compete for common, high-volume search terms in your field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re evaluating how to stand out in these search terms, one of the key factors you should be considering is a keyword or keyword phrase strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-a-keyword&quot;&gt;What’s a Keyword?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact definition states a &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/learn/seo/what-are-keywords&quot;&gt;keyword or keyword phrase&lt;/a&gt; is a query term entered into a search engine or website by patients. A keyword can be a single word or a series of words. It’s the search term you want to rank for with a certain page. So when people search for a keyword or phrase in Google or other search engines, they should find the page on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone searches Google for “how to fix gap teeth without braces” Google works to discern what the user is looking for, and it returns a list of web pages with this topic. If your website uses the exact phrase the user searched for as a keyword, part of the phrase (“gap teeth”), or a related phrase (i.e. “teeth gaps,” “braces”) Google is more likely to show the user your websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Keywords1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google works to discern what the user is looking for.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-keywords-so-important&quot;&gt;Why Are Keywords So Important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put…ROI. Choosing the right keyword phrases and using them correctly for SEO is quite frankly the easiest and most effective way to get more users to your website. SEO is important to your practice’s success, and keywords play a major role in the SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Keywords2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SEO is important to your practice's success.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People will find their way onto your pages in a variety of ways, including social media and direct traffic to name a few. But, in today’s market, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/search-engines-more-traffic-publishers-social-media-2017-2018-2&quot;&gt;search generates the biggest share of traffic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-should-your-practice-start&quot;&gt;Where Should Your Practice Start?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless if you’re taking the first step to or making adjustments to an up and running SEO strategy, the best place to start is to find the right long-tail keywords. Long-tail keywords allow small and medium sized practices to stand out and boost your medical practice’s ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-short-taillong-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;What are Short-Tail/Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanised.co.uk/seo/short-tail-vs-long-tail-keywords/&quot;&gt;Short-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are limited to one or two words that cover a general topic, such as “breast lift”. Very general term, right? Yes, it will attract lots of search traffic, but it’s expensive and difficult to rank for especially if you’re new to the keyword/SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;Long-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are specific terms or phrases such as “best breast lift surgeon near me”. You may see less traffic, but if a patient is searching for this term then they are most likely closer to making a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short-tail keywords are still very useful to the growth of your practice. Long-tail keywords can help your medical practice play to your SEO strengths while building the authority to rank for short-tail keywords in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-should-medical-practices-choose-long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;How Should Medical Practices Choose Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start by utilizing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/search/how-google-autocomplete-works-search/&quot;&gt;Google’s search bar recommendations&lt;/a&gt; to understand how it suggests possible long tails. By checking out what potential keywords are most popular and what’s applicable to what you provided in terms of care, your practice can narrow down your list or add possibilities you have missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have time to walk through all of the items needed to plan and implement a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/ppc/&quot;&gt;paid advertising strategy&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to connect with us at DoctorLogic. Our software generates on average 30,000 relevant, unique exact match, long-tail keyword combinations for every campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Medical-PPC" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working" /><published>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html">&lt;p&gt;If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-do-you-actually-have-a-strategy&quot;&gt;1. Do you actually have a strategy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure or not feeling confident in what you think you have then you don’t have a strategy. To get started first and foremost, develop a plan of action. Without a plan, your setting your initiatives up for failure. Try not to throw out initiatives without developing a strategy first, and be sure to clearly define your objectives and ROI (return on investment) metrics… which leads me to my second point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-youre-not-tracking-kpi-metrics&quot;&gt;2. You’re not tracking KPI metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to prove your marketing strategy works, data has to back it up. Every successful marketing strategy needs expectations set and frequent monitoring on what, when, and how; what got launched, when it went live, and how it performed. Data-driven decision making is the key to successful marketing. Here’s a great reference for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.impactbnd.com/the-10-marketing-kpis-you-should-be-tracking&quot;&gt;which KPIs you should be tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-youre-wanting-results-now&quot;&gt;3. You’re wanting results NOW.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of the phrase, you need to learn how to crawl before you walk? The same applies for marketing initiatives. Marketing is powerful but results don’t happen overnight. To prove success for a marketing plan, focus on KPIs at the beginning and throughout the campaign, and ROI at the end. Often times, campaigns get shut down early because they didn’t prove value within the first few days. The key to avoiding this is to set attainable goals and learn from the results for your next campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-your-marketing-budget-is-mia&quot;&gt;4. Your marketing budget is M.I.A.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare practices are apprehensive towards spending marketing dollars. With the industry being highly competitive, allocating a certain percentage to marketing is a must. Additionally, when you track KPIs and ROI, you can make data-driven decisions to increase marketing dollars where it makes sense. For more help on how to allocate a marketing budget, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webascender.com/blog/how-to-allocate-your-digital-marketing-budget-in-2019/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-youre-living-the-definition-of-insanity&quot;&gt;5. You’re living the “Definition of Insanity”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of insanity is doing the same thing and expecting different results. Marketing initiatives are not one-and-done or set-it-and-forget-it. Constant optimization is required for optimal success. Try different initiatives as well. The more data you can collect on what worked and what didn’t, the more you can leverage it for your success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.</summary></entry></feed>