<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-05T18:53:04+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Positivepatientexperience</title><link href="/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positivepatientexperience" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/PositivePatientExperience</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout and cleanliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workspace-resource.com/office-furniture/crucial-design-tips-for-creating-a-patient-focused-healthcare-facility/&quot;&gt;design tips&lt;/a&gt; to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with staff:&lt;/strong&gt; Friendliness can go a long way. When staff members are welcoming and inviting, patients feel valued and cared for. The front-desk staff must be well-trained and willing to provide information to the patient, such as expected wait time, bathroom location, any complimentary beverages, etc., Also keep in mind interactions with staff can be via phone as well. Finding ways to translate that sense of welcomeness through the phone can have the same affect towards their overall experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theberylinstitute.org/blogpost/947424/302264/Phone-Skills-Making-or-Breaking-The-Patient-Experience&quot;&gt;Here’s a great reference&lt;/a&gt; for scripting and guiding phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait times:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to wait. Restaurants and grocery stores have transformed online and mobile ordering so items are ready for pickup upon arriving. Amazon Prime ships same-day or two-day packages. Websites have to be speedy-quick or consumers will bounce due to loading time… it’s the new trend. When they’re used to skipping lines, sitting in a waiting area for minutes to hours on end, tries their patience. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.medicalgps.com/how-long-will-you-wait-4-simple-tips-for-easing-the-wait-experience/&quot;&gt;97% of patients&lt;/a&gt; get frustrated over wait times, and overall patient satisfaction decreases as wait time increases. If your wait times cannot be avoided, try finding ways to occupy their time. Some ideas are: free internet, TV, or latest up-to-date magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with the doctor(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Patients remember the way their doctor treated them. Friendliness doesn’t begin and end with the front-desk. Doctors need to be friendly and accommodating as well. Being personable makes patients feel valued. Take time to thoroughly explain their medical condition and open the discussion for questions. When a patient openly discusses their questions with you, it’s important to reciprocate the same openness and honesty by replying “that’s a great question, I’m glad you asked.” Providing a sense of partnership to patients promotes positive patient experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusively, there are many ways to create memorable experiences. It might be fun to switch up the experiences every now and then and ask for patient feedback. Ultimately, providing a positive, memorable experience not only benefits your patients, it benefits your practice as well. Positive experiences translate to patient retention and practice growth. The ultimate practice goal, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Layout and cleanliness: The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some design tips to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post With Form</title><link href="/blog/new-post-with-form" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post With Form" /><published>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-With-Form</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/new-post-with-form">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="healthcare-marketing" /><category term="PPC" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forestrytest</title><link href="/blog/forestrytest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forestrytest" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/forestrytest</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/forestrytest.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test using the forestry CMS bob&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="practice-management" /><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">This is a test using the forestry CMS bob</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bariatric</title><link href="/blog/Bariatric.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bariatric" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Bariatric</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Bariatric.html">&lt;p&gt;Only 1% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bariatricsurgerynewjersey.com/why-only-1-percent-patients-choose-bariatric-surgery/&quot;&gt;eligible patients&lt;/a&gt; choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, when I’m nervous about something I have a tendency to research to ease my nervousness. I’m not an anomaly. Today’s consumer is digital savvy and turn to Google to find everything. Potential patients are not ignoring Google when it comes to important searches and this includes weight loss surgery. And if you’re Bariatric practice is not sitting at the &lt;strong&gt;top&lt;/strong&gt; of Google’s search ranking, then it’s &lt;strong&gt;buried&lt;/strong&gt; under a list of other Bariatric providers and needless to say, &lt;em&gt;that’s not good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-fix-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you fix this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient acquisition strategy is a great place to start. In order to acquire new Bariatric patients you need to address the process of finding a lead, turning the lead into a prospect and then turning them into patients. I know this sounds like a long process, but actually finding lead and prospects isn’t as difficult as it may seem. There’s really no shortage, the challenge is getting them through the final stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-get-on-the-same-digital-page&quot;&gt;Let’s Get On The Same Digital Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-healthcare-marketing-trends.html&quot;&gt;January 15 blog&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the healthcare marketing trend providers should look at to grow their practice in 2019. These tips are a great direction when you’re looking to build your marketing plan. Today, let’s dive into some items related to patient acquisition. From educating the right Bariatric patient, interacting with them and of course following up properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve all heard “Content is King”. This is not going away. As matter of fact, having more unique and quality content gives opportunity to rank well in search. Add useful content to your website that your visitors will consider valuable, such as downloadable tip sheet, blogs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries/&quot;&gt;before and after photo galleries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often do you get frustrated with trying to find information on a website and decide it would be easier to refine your search in Google? Personally, I’m guilty of this. Adding call to actions can ease this frustration and is the best approach to meet patients where they are in the purchasing journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patient has found your website. Now make it easy for them to click to your contact page where they can ask for more information, or participate in a live chat. Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/chat/&quot;&gt;managed chat service&lt;/a&gt; to connect with visitors to your site 24/7. Providers who use chat are seeing a 40% increase in leads!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educating potential patients should not stop once they leave your website. And part of the buyer journey is following up properly. Give your site visitors opportunity to share their email addresses by offering free content that is engaging and can be used often, like a downloadable recipe book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide all the facts they need about bariatric surgery in an online bariatric surgery seminar. This is a great introduction and helps with providing the right content to the patient. Of course, this is a not meant to be a replacement for the in-person seminar, but a great introduction to your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And of course, the foundation of your strategy is your website. If your website is not &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-things-every-website-must-have.html&quot;&gt;optimized properly&lt;/a&gt;, it will miss the mark on being found and providing the right experience discussed in the other 5 tips. Check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot;&gt;website’s SEO&lt;/a&gt; to make sure potential patients are finding you when they conduct online searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Only 1% of eligible patients choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post List 2</title><link href="/blog/Post-List-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post List 2" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-List-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Post-List-2.html">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="healthcare-marketing" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation Test</title><link href="/blog/Reputation-Test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation Test" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Reputation-Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Reputation-Test.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with this premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy teams are all alike; every unhappy team is unhappy in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the Anna Karenina principle? It’s derived from the famous first sentence of Leo Tolstoy’s seminal novel: “Happy families are all alike; every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is as follows: in order for a marriage to thrive, it must succeed in many different respects. If you and your partner argue about money, clash about parenting, or differ in political ideology, you’re doomed to unhappiness — no matter how happy you are in other areas of your relationship. Back in 340 BC, Aristotle emphasized the same principle a bit differently: “Men are good in but one way, but bad in many.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/christopher-ayme-157131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, success is not about doing just one thing correctly, but about avoiding many possible ways to fail. The Anna Karenina principle, popular in science and math, holds true for a lot of things in life — including effective teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If teams want to hit their goals, meet their deadlines, and surpass their KPIs, they need to succeed in all the critical ways — and avoid all the common pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is this magical recipe for effective teamwork? In the early days of building monday.com, we spoke with hundreds of managers and discussed all the unique reasons that teams are unhappy. We discovered seven factors that make or break a team’s success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Let’s start with this premise:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing Matt</title><link href="/blog/Testing-Matt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing Matt" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Testing-Matt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Testing-Matt.html">&lt;p&gt;He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, with no real clue of what he was doing, he opened it and tried to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was terrifying,” Benoit says now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also the beginning of what has become one of the more interesting narratives in these early days of the modern era of the electric car, one that asks and answers a lot of questions and has turned the 36-year-old Benoit — a father of three who works in IT in Boston — into one of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCfV0_wbjG8KJADuZT2ct4SA&quot; title=&quot;www.youtube.com&quot;&gt;early superstars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tesla that started it all, a Model S that Benoit refers to as Delores, was purchased from a salvage yard after it had been caught in a flood in New Jersey. Benoit had a friend who owned a Model S, and the moment he pulled it into Benoit’s driveway to take him for a ride, Benoit was obsessed. The way it was whisper quiet. The impossible acceleration from zero to I-feel-like-I’m-on-a-roller-coaster-and-about-to-throw-up in an instant. The way he could feel all of the work that went into creating the vehicle, a history of progress that combined to create this feeling of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was like a laptop on wheels,” he says. “The perfect mixture of my two things: tech and cars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had to have one, but a new Model S starts at $76,000 and can run as high as $133,000. That wasn’t happening. So he purchased Delores for $14,000, with the idea that he was going to do something no amateur mechanic had done before. He was going to rebuild a Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I felt like a trailblazer,” Benoit says of pulling everything in the car apart and figuring out how it worked. “We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the ultimate DIY project, with no guidance from Tesla. Benoit says the company skirts the state’s Right to Repair Initiative, which was passed by voters in 2012 and requires manufacturers to allow vehicle owners access to the same diagnostic and repair information made available to dealerships and authorized repair centers. “They get away with this because they don’t have any dealerships,” Benoit says. “You order your car online.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undeterred, Benoit stripped the car, tore out all of the ruined electronics, and pried out the seats, which had rusted in place, thanks to the saltwater. Then he contacted Tesla to order the parts he needed for the rebuild, and it was here that Benoit hit another obstacle, one that would define the arc of his story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tesla does not want anyone working on its cars besides Tesla, and it refused to sell Benoit the parts he wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Tesla representative, in a statement to the Globe, said “there are significant safety concerns when salvaged Teslas are repaired improperly or when Tesla parts are used outside of their original design intent, as these vehicles could pose a danger to both the mechanic and other drivers on the road.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="website-design" /><summary type="html">He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contentmarketing</title><link href="/blog/ContentMarketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contentmarketing" /><published>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/ContentMarketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/ContentMarketing.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;valuable-content-targets-ideal-customers&quot;&gt;Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a healthcare provider, you want to be sure the content on your website provides value to potential and existing patients. Content can be used to drive patients where you would like them to visit on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dentist presenting a case study on a patient, and the struggle the patient faced before coming in contact with them will be a memorable way a reader can relate with the practice. This will create a positive image of your brand to a potential patient who may be struggling with the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/blog/visual-content-you-need-to-use-in-your-marketing-campaign/&quot;&gt;65% of people are visual learners&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also a good idea to use plenty of visual content on your site to target ideal patients and improve your online patient experience. A great example of this is a plastic surgeon using before and after galleries to display their procedure results, and videos of them discussing a specific procedure to better educate their patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the content on your website is boring, unorganized, and irrelevant, you will leave a bad first impression on your visitors thus leaving a negative view of your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boost-traffic-to-your-medical-site&quot;&gt;Boost Traffic to Your Medical Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a high rank in major search engine results is quality exposure for your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using frequently searched keywords in your industry will also help convert potential patients and increase the visibility of your brand. For instance, a woman in Dallas has a desire for fuller breasts. She searches “Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the title of a before and after photo in your site gallery reads “Amazing Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”. There is a high chance when she completes her search, your site could be at the top of the search results as the keyword in your gallery matches her search phrase. Not only will she head straight for the photo, but she’ll also check out your reviews page and possibly schedule a consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relevant content and keywords will help boost traffic to your site. Content is displayed the second those 590,000 search results pop up. If visitors are unable to find your site due to poor content on your website, then your patient volume is not where it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, give your patients a sense of assurance your practice is the right solution to their healthcare needs. After all, if patients are finding their way to your site, you need to find a way to keep them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in content marketing for your medical practice, contact us today to learn more. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Markethealthcarefacility</title><link href="/blog/MarketHealthcareFacility.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Markethealthcarefacility" /><published>2019-02-21T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/MarketHealthcareFacility</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/MarketHealthcareFacility.html">&lt;p&gt;Attracting patients online, especially in a competitive market, can be tough. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/modernize-your-patient-experience.html&quot;&gt;In my previous blog&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed how online consumerism has changed and how potential patients are conducting their research online. Online research includes both search engines and social media, as long as the information they’re finding is trustworthy and answering their questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I’m going to provide 5 high-level tips on marketing your healthcare facility to get your practice showing up everywhere potential patients are searching. Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-its-all-about-the-website&quot;&gt;1. It’s all about the website.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t currently have a website for your practice, or it’s so outdated it doesn’t work, you’re going to want to begin developing a new and strategic website. What do I mean by strategic? Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strategic website should act as your marketing hub. It’s well-thought out and proving out your marketing goals. When configured correctly, a strategic website can be the highest performing marketing initiative you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some must-haves for a strategic website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appealing design and easy-to-navigate pages&lt;/strong&gt; - Think of your website as the welcome mat to your practice. For many users, it will be the first thing they stumble upon, so naturally, you’re going to want to make a good impression with a welcoming design. Typically, when prospective patients turn towards search engines, they’re searching for something or someone in specific, and they’re wanting information as quickly as possible. Make sure your website is structured fluidly so users can easily and quickly discover the information they’re searching. P.S. Don’t overlook optimizing your design for mobile searchers. Mobile is just as important as desktop optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice information&lt;/strong&gt; - Your website must contain the location(s) of your practice, phone number, and map/directions. I don’t know about you, but when I’m looking for a dentist, I’m going to want the closest one to my home or job. I’m not willing to drive two-hours for a teeth-cleaning. Imagine a prospective patient being in the market for a routine teeth-cleaning, performing an online search, discovering your practice, and calling to book an appointment. Sounds great right? But when they call to make an appointment, they find out you’re in an entirely different state! This can easily be remedied by providing all the information on your website, upfront. This way, you’re only bringing in leads who are relevant to your market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call-to-actions (CTA)&lt;/strong&gt; - When a prospective patient is on your website, it’s important to think about the action you’d like them to take. Do you want them to book an appointment, fill out a contact form, call your phone number, etc.,? Your CTA can vary throughout your site depending on the context of the page. Also, make sure what you’re asking of them is relevant to the information you’re providing on the page. This will help maximize conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content, content, content&lt;/strong&gt; - Developing content may be one of the hardest parts of configuring a strategic website, but it’s one of the most important. Users want trustworthy and educational content. If I’m in the market for a plastic surgery procedure, I will want to learn more about what to expect, typical length of the procedure, and of course pricing. I’m wanting to be educated. Content should be focused around answering questions. When content is developed around this strategy, readers gain a sense of reassurance and associate your practice as a credible expert. One thing to note, you should consistently publish and revise content. It’s not a one-and-done type of configuration task. Have a new tool you’re using for procedures? Make sure your website is up to date with that information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-search-engine-optimization-seo&quot;&gt;2. Search engine optimization (SEO)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a website set up, ensuring it’s search engine friendly is vital. You will want to think through both on-page and off-page SEO contributors as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some best-practices for on-page SEO (factors on your website you control):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content relevance and keywords&lt;/strong&gt; - In conjunction with your content strategy, your content should rank for materials relevant to your industry, topics, and competitors. You should also formulate a keyword strategy to guide you through content building. Be careful not to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2012/03/21/dangers-of-keyword-stuffing&quot;&gt;keyword stuff&lt;/a&gt;. Google’s algorithm rewards relevant content and punishes keyword stuffers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tag, tag, tag&lt;/strong&gt; - On every page of your site, you have page title tags, meta description tags, header tags (H1, H2’s) and more. Best practice is to optimize those tags to be as relevant as possible. These tags tell Google what your page is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure and foundation&lt;/strong&gt; - During the development process of your site, make sure you’re building out optimized URLs relevant to the page it’s directing to, and ideally, include one to two keywords. Though having an optimally-built and appropriately tagged website is a great start to stand out from your online competition, make sure you don’t overlook your website’s loading speed. When consumers are searching for information, they want information quickly. If your page takes too long to load, the user will leave and find another page that loads quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some best-practices for off-page SEO (external factors to your website or social media success):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain authority&lt;/strong&gt; - The more content you have, ranking with high-quality keywords and relevant tags, the more authority your page will have and the higher it will rank organically (non-paid). The higher it ranks, the more traffic you’ll receive, but you’ll also potentially beat out your competitors’ organic ranking. Your goal is to be anywhere on page 1 of organic search results, since the majority of online users don’t click on to page 2. The first organic search result is ideal, or at least in the top three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social&lt;/strong&gt; - I’ll touch more on how to be successful with social media marketing below, but social sharing and reputation play a strong factor in off-page SEO and authority building, so be sure you’re active on social media and adding sharing icons to your website’s pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-local-listing&quot;&gt;3. Local listing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the example I shared above about the dentist being out of state? Having your practice listed on Google My Business (GMB) is also important to avoid such situations. GMB is great for establishing local traffic. Adding this listing will help potential patients find your practice… and help you stand out from your competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-video-marketing&quot;&gt;4. Video marketing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really stand out from your competition, you should invest in video marketing. A great way to use video marketing is with customer testimonials. Clients like to see success stories and being able to see real-life stories builds trust and credibility. You could go about videos in two ways. One, you could offer a testimonials page on your website where you display the video gallery. Another option is to create a YouTube channel for your practice. You could also offer educational content via videos in addition to success stories; explaining how a certain treatment is administered. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/how-to-optimize-a-youtube-channel-and-videos-for-better-visibility/&quot;&gt;Here’s a great resource&lt;/a&gt; for optimizing a YouTube channel for higher visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-social-media&quot;&gt;5. Social media&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media provides another method of visibility and credibility to your practice. The goal of social media marketing should be to maintain contact with your followers and increase engagement. If you think social media isn’t important to standing out from your competitors, think again… &lt;a href=&quot;https://stodzyinternetmarketing.com/healthcare-marketing/&quot;&gt;57% of patients&lt;/a&gt; choose their PCP based on social media presence alone. A great start to leveraging social media is to share the content you’ve already created for your website, such as, procedure expectations, success stories, or blogs. You can also look into seasonal posts, such as, tips for withstanding flu season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it! 5 high-level tips on marketing your healthcare facility and standing out online. If you’d like to dive deeper into any of these topics, contact us! We love providing expert online marketing guidance for healthcare professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Attracting patients online, especially in a competitive market, can be tough. In my previous blog, I discussed how online consumerism has changed and how potential patients are conducting their research online. Online research includes both search engines and social media, as long as the information they’re finding is trustworthy and answering their questions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marketingstrategies</title><link href="/blog/MarketingStrategies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marketingstrategies" /><published>2019-02-12T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-12T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/MarketingStrategies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/MarketingStrategies.html">&lt;p&gt;It can seem as if new marketing trends are popping up every day, and keeping up with them is nearly impossible. So how do you know which ones are actually worth investing in, and which ones are passing fads?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll look at a few marketing strategies we think will actually stick around and work for your business in 2019 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more marketers are beginning to notice the effectiveness of video and pushing to include more video content in their overall marketing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/MarketingStrategy1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Invest in video channels.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/53/assets/hubspot.com/research/reports/State%20of%20Inbound%202018%20Global%20Results.pdf?__hstc=20629287.412c8a76c91bff063c9957a7f4788486.1497889639600.1543364182830.1545948761723.25&amp;amp;__hssc=20629287.2.1547577563257&amp;amp;__hsfp=1476023372&quot;&gt;HubSpot’s State of Inbound 2018 report&lt;/a&gt;, YouTube and Facebook video ranked as two of the top three content distribution channels that marketers plan to add to their marketing efforts in coming months. And senior marketing leaders are enthusiastic about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/MarketingStrategy2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Marketing leaders are enthusiastic about video.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why all the hype? Because &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/video-marketing-statistics?__hstc=37514559.86908053a04deef209d41cbbf486b52a.1546876321479.1554315931393.1554478540077.53&amp;amp;__hssc=37514559.15.1554478540077&amp;amp;__hsfp=1915899968#sm.0000f7ujhkwrse8sqa62aq63w23fi&quot;&gt;64% of customers&lt;/a&gt; are more likely to buy a product online after watching a video about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;messaging-apps&quot;&gt;Messaging Apps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you noticed that more and more companies have chat bots pop up once you’ve been browsing their websites for a while? Has a business messaged you via Facebook while you’re looking at their page?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messaging apps like on-site chat bots, Facebook Messenger, WhatsApp, and WeChat are gaining steam. Facebook Messenger alone has over 1.3 billion users, leading Facebook to launch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/business/marketing/messenger&quot;&gt;Messenger Business&lt;/a&gt;, noting that among people surveyed who message businesses on Facebook, the majority say being able to do so helps them feel more confident about the brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when it comes to chatbots, people are starting to see the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/MarketingStrategy3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Potential benefits of chatbots.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drift.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/2018-state-of-chatbots-report.pdf&quot;&gt;Drift’s 2018 State of Chatbots Report&lt;/a&gt;, 24 hour service is one of the top benefits, followed by getting an instant response and answers to simple questions you don’t want to get on the phone with a sales rep for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;automation&quot;&gt;Automation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to make your life easier? Invest in marketing automation tools. They can not only put an end to the mundanity of repetitive tasks, but help improve the timing, relevance, and ultimately user response of your marketing techniques via rules-based personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of implementing automation tools can be in your social media and email marketing efforts. For example, Facebook allows you to schedule posts ahead of time using the “Publishing Tools” tab on any page you manage. You can also use tools &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffer.com/&quot;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://hootsuite.com/&quot;&gt;Hootsuite&lt;/a&gt; to manage all of your social media accounts from one platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to email marketing, solutions like &lt;a href=&quot;https://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;can make your life easier by allowing you to segment audiences, draft emails, and have the tool schedule them for when recipients are most likely to open, click, and/or respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only can the above three marketing strategies—video, messaging apps, and automation—help your business more easily and effectively reach customers, it can also keep you one step ahead of the competition. These strategies, along with implementing &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot;&gt;content and SEO best practices&lt;/a&gt;, can really help take your company to the next level this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">It can seem as if new marketing trends are popping up every day, and keeping up with them is nearly impossible. So how do you know which ones are actually worth investing in, and which ones are passing fads?</summary></entry></feed>