<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-18T14:20:44+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Positivepatientexperience</title><link href="/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positivepatientexperience" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/PositivePatientExperience</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/PositivePatientExperience.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout and cleanliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workspace-resource.com/office-furniture/crucial-design-tips-for-creating-a-patient-focused-healthcare-facility/&quot;&gt;design tips&lt;/a&gt; to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with staff:&lt;/strong&gt; Friendliness can go a long way. When staff members are welcoming and inviting, patients feel valued and cared for. The front-desk staff must be well-trained and willing to provide information to the patient, such as expected wait time, bathroom location, any complimentary beverages, etc., Also keep in mind interactions with staff can be via phone as well. Finding ways to translate that sense of welcomeness through the phone can have the same affect towards their overall experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theberylinstitute.org/blogpost/947424/302264/Phone-Skills-Making-or-Breaking-The-Patient-Experience&quot;&gt;Here’s a great reference&lt;/a&gt; for scripting and guiding phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait times:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to wait. Restaurants and grocery stores have transformed online and mobile ordering so items are ready for pickup upon arriving. Amazon Prime ships same-day or two-day packages. Websites have to be speedy-quick or consumers will bounce due to loading time… it’s the new trend. When they’re used to skipping lines, sitting in a waiting area for minutes to hours on end, tries their patience. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.medicalgps.com/how-long-will-you-wait-4-simple-tips-for-easing-the-wait-experience/&quot;&gt;97% of patients&lt;/a&gt; get frustrated over wait times, and overall patient satisfaction decreases as wait time increases. If your wait times cannot be avoided, try finding ways to occupy their time. Some ideas are: free internet, TV, or latest up-to-date magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with the doctor(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Patients remember the way their doctor treated them. Friendliness doesn’t begin and end with the front-desk. Doctors need to be friendly and accommodating as well. Being personable makes patients feel valued. Take time to thoroughly explain their medical condition and open the discussion for questions. When a patient openly discusses their questions with you, it’s important to reciprocate the same openness and honesty by replying “that’s a great question, I’m glad you asked.” Providing a sense of partnership to patients promotes positive patient experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusively, there are many ways to create memorable experiences. It might be fun to switch up the experiences every now and then and ask for patient feedback. Ultimately, providing a positive, memorable experience not only benefits your patients, it benefits your practice as well. Positive experiences translate to patient retention and practice growth. The ultimate practice goal, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Layout and cleanliness: The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some design tips to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Micrositesseo</title><link href="/blog/MicrositesSEO.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Micrositesseo" /><published>2019-03-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/MicrositesSEO</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/MicrositesSEO.html">&lt;p&gt;asy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has determined sites created for the sole purpose directing back to website with back links, or to boost certain keywords, is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/black-hat-seo&quot;&gt;black hat SEO&lt;/a&gt; tactic and looks spammy. Not only that, but Google considers sites like this to be extremely low quality. And remember, Google penalizes sites they deem to be low quality. To avoid a penalty, it’s best to avoid setting up microsites unless it’s for branding purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-say-no-to-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Say No to Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes time and effort to create and optimize the content for microsites. Basically the same steps you took to set up your main site still applies, and they can take just as long. Imagine going through that for more than one site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search engines rank sites that have lots of good, quality content. If you’re creating microsites your practice’s content will be spread out. Your content is better off gaining traction on your main website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While microsites can serve legitimate purposes, it’s not recommended to use them solely for SEO. For SEO, focus on getting your main website rank high by producing quality, well optimized content and building relevant links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save yourself time and avoid the headache of creating tons of mini sites to boost your SEO. Get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about our platform to help you grow your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will design your website so you can showcase your work with a video or photo gallery. Additionally, we can add our review tool to help you get reviews from your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make your practice stand out from the rest of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">asy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post With Form</title><link href="/blog/new-post-with-form" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post With Form" /><published>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-With-Form</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/new-post-with-form">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="healthcare-marketing" /><category term="PPC" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forestrytest</title><link href="/blog/forestrytest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forestrytest" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/forestrytest</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/forestrytest.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test using the forestry CMS bob&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="practice-management" /><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">This is a test using the forestry CMS bob</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bariatric</title><link href="/blog/Bariatric.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bariatric" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Bariatric</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Bariatric.html">&lt;p&gt;Only 1% of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bariatricsurgerynewjersey.com/why-only-1-percent-patients-choose-bariatric-surgery/&quot;&gt;eligible patients&lt;/a&gt; choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, when I’m nervous about something I have a tendency to research to ease my nervousness. I’m not an anomaly. Today’s consumer is digital savvy and turn to Google to find everything. Potential patients are not ignoring Google when it comes to important searches and this includes weight loss surgery. And if you’re Bariatric practice is not sitting at the &lt;strong&gt;top&lt;/strong&gt; of Google’s search ranking, then it’s &lt;strong&gt;buried&lt;/strong&gt; under a list of other Bariatric providers and needless to say, &lt;em&gt;that’s not good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-fix-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you fix this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A patient acquisition strategy is a great place to start. In order to acquire new Bariatric patients you need to address the process of finding a lead, turning the lead into a prospect and then turning them into patients. I know this sounds like a long process, but actually finding lead and prospects isn’t as difficult as it may seem. There’s really no shortage, the challenge is getting them through the final stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-get-on-the-same-digital-page&quot;&gt;Let’s Get On The Same Digital Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-healthcare-marketing-trends.html&quot;&gt;January 15 blog&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about the healthcare marketing trend providers should look at to grow their practice in 2019. These tips are a great direction when you’re looking to build your marketing plan. Today, let’s dive into some items related to patient acquisition. From educating the right Bariatric patient, interacting with them and of course following up properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ve all heard “Content is King”. This is not going away. As matter of fact, having more unique and quality content gives opportunity to rank well in search. Add useful content to your website that your visitors will consider valuable, such as downloadable tip sheet, blogs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries/&quot;&gt;before and after photo galleries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How often do you get frustrated with trying to find information on a website and decide it would be easier to refine your search in Google? Personally, I’m guilty of this. Adding call to actions can ease this frustration and is the best approach to meet patients where they are in the purchasing journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The patient has found your website. Now make it easy for them to click to your contact page where they can ask for more information, or participate in a live chat. Use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/chat/&quot;&gt;managed chat service&lt;/a&gt; to connect with visitors to your site 24/7. Providers who use chat are seeing a 40% increase in leads!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Educating potential patients should not stop once they leave your website. And part of the buyer journey is following up properly. Give your site visitors opportunity to share their email addresses by offering free content that is engaging and can be used often, like a downloadable recipe book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide all the facts they need about bariatric surgery in an online bariatric surgery seminar. This is a great introduction and helps with providing the right content to the patient. Of course, this is a not meant to be a replacement for the in-person seminar, but a great introduction to your practice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And of course, the foundation of your strategy is your website. If your website is not &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/five-things-every-website-must-have.html&quot;&gt;optimized properly&lt;/a&gt;, it will miss the mark on being found and providing the right experience discussed in the other 5 tips. Check your &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/why-seo-matters.html&quot;&gt;website’s SEO&lt;/a&gt; to make sure potential patients are finding you when they conduct online searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Only 1% of eligible patients choose Bariatric Surgery as an option. Although it’s the #1 solution for long term, weight loss with proven results, it’s the most underutilized method for weight loss. Why is this? Of course, there are legitimate reasons why someone may not move forward with the surgery. And one of those is the emotional commitment. Potential patients are nervous about having this type of surgery. They believe the surgery is more dangerous than obesity itself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post List 2</title><link href="/blog/Post-List-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post List 2" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-List-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Post-List-2.html">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="healthcare-marketing" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation Test</title><link href="/blog/Reputation-Test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation Test" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Reputation-Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Reputation-Test.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with this premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy teams are all alike; every unhappy team is unhappy in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the Anna Karenina principle? It’s derived from the famous first sentence of Leo Tolstoy’s seminal novel: “Happy families are all alike; every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is as follows: in order for a marriage to thrive, it must succeed in many different respects. If you and your partner argue about money, clash about parenting, or differ in political ideology, you’re doomed to unhappiness — no matter how happy you are in other areas of your relationship. Back in 340 BC, Aristotle emphasized the same principle a bit differently: “Men are good in but one way, but bad in many.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/christopher-ayme-157131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, success is not about doing just one thing correctly, but about avoiding many possible ways to fail. The Anna Karenina principle, popular in science and math, holds true for a lot of things in life — including effective teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If teams want to hit their goals, meet their deadlines, and surpass their KPIs, they need to succeed in all the critical ways — and avoid all the common pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is this magical recipe for effective teamwork? In the early days of building monday.com, we spoke with hundreds of managers and discussed all the unique reasons that teams are unhappy. We discovered seven factors that make or break a team’s success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Let’s start with this premise:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputationmanagementdoctors</title><link href="/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputationmanagementdoctors" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/ReputationManagementDoctors.html">&lt;p&gt;For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do to better manage your online reputation and how do you respond when you do in fact receive a negative review?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-your-reputation-from-the-get-go&quot;&gt;Managing Your Reputation from the Get Go&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of your business lives online, so you should be prepared to take the proper steps to ensure you’re putting your best foot forward from the start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-website&quot;&gt;Your Website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Populate your website with positive reviews from happy patients. You can have a dedicated testimonials page if you like, but I recommend having them sprinkled throughout your website. A few on your About page, a couple more on your Contact page, etc. will make them visible no matter where a visitor goes on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-social-profiles&quot;&gt;Your Social Profiles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important social network to pay attention to in terms of reviews is Facebook. That’s because Facebook has a built-in section where people can review you. When it comes to these reviews, &lt;em&gt;respond to them immediately&lt;/em&gt;, both positive and negative. There’s nothing worse than leaving a negative review unanswered, and for a long amount of time, on a popular social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;review-websites&quot;&gt;Review Websites&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review websites include the sites I mentioned before, Yelp and Google, but also physician-specific review websites like RateMDs, HealthGrades, and Vitals. First of all, if you haven’t claimed your profile on one of these sites yet, do so now. You want to be able to manage your information on all of these sites before someone tarnishes your name without you even knowing about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;responding-to-a-negative-review&quot;&gt;Responding to a Negative Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, at least one negative review is bound to come your way. This can be disheartening and feel personal, but it’s important to &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; respond in a professional manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a recommended course of action when you see you’ve received a negative review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond ASAP:&lt;/strong&gt; The sooner you respond, the less harm will be done. Instead of someone solely reading the negative review, they also get to see your response. In the case I mentioned earlier, if someone were to read the negative review of the doctor’s office, the office manager or doctor could quickly respond that it was a problem with that person’s individual insurance plan, not the doctor. These quick responses and resolutions may even move the reviewer to remove the review entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always be professional:&lt;/strong&gt; As I mentioned earlier, we are human; we take things personally even if we maybe shouldn’t. Don’t let that turn you into a raging internet troll! Take a few hours, maybe even a day, to absorb the review and formulate a response. I know in #1 I said respond ASAP, but it’s always better to take a little bit longer and respond appropriately than to respond immediately and unprofessionally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a professional in today’s world can mean people splashing your name around the internet, saying whatever they want with impunity. Don’t take it to heart, and don’t let it affect your business. Try your best to be on top of your digital reputation management from the get go, and when that inevitable negative review does come your way, take it in stride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="online-reviews" /><summary type="html">For example, one of the first things disgruntled patients do these days is find where online they can post about their negative experience. Oftentimes, this is a doctor’s personal website or review page (think Yelp or Google reviews).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing Matt</title><link href="/blog/Testing-Matt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing Matt" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Testing-Matt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Testing-Matt.html">&lt;p&gt;He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, with no real clue of what he was doing, he opened it and tried to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was terrifying,” Benoit says now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also the beginning of what has become one of the more interesting narratives in these early days of the modern era of the electric car, one that asks and answers a lot of questions and has turned the 36-year-old Benoit — a father of three who works in IT in Boston — into one of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCfV0_wbjG8KJADuZT2ct4SA&quot; title=&quot;www.youtube.com&quot;&gt;early superstars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tesla that started it all, a Model S that Benoit refers to as Delores, was purchased from a salvage yard after it had been caught in a flood in New Jersey. Benoit had a friend who owned a Model S, and the moment he pulled it into Benoit’s driveway to take him for a ride, Benoit was obsessed. The way it was whisper quiet. The impossible acceleration from zero to I-feel-like-I’m-on-a-roller-coaster-and-about-to-throw-up in an instant. The way he could feel all of the work that went into creating the vehicle, a history of progress that combined to create this feeling of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was like a laptop on wheels,” he says. “The perfect mixture of my two things: tech and cars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had to have one, but a new Model S starts at $76,000 and can run as high as $133,000. That wasn’t happening. So he purchased Delores for $14,000, with the idea that he was going to do something no amateur mechanic had done before. He was going to rebuild a Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I felt like a trailblazer,” Benoit says of pulling everything in the car apart and figuring out how it worked. “We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the ultimate DIY project, with no guidance from Tesla. Benoit says the company skirts the state’s Right to Repair Initiative, which was passed by voters in 2012 and requires manufacturers to allow vehicle owners access to the same diagnostic and repair information made available to dealerships and authorized repair centers. “They get away with this because they don’t have any dealerships,” Benoit says. “You order your car online.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undeterred, Benoit stripped the car, tore out all of the ruined electronics, and pried out the seats, which had rusted in place, thanks to the saltwater. Then he contacted Tesla to order the parts he needed for the rebuild, and it was here that Benoit hit another obstacle, one that would define the arc of his story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tesla does not want anyone working on its cars besides Tesla, and it refused to sell Benoit the parts he wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Tesla representative, in a statement to the Globe, said “there are significant safety concerns when salvaged Teslas are repaired improperly or when Tesla parts are used outside of their original design intent, as these vehicles could pose a danger to both the mechanic and other drivers on the road.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><category term="website-design" /><summary type="html">He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contentmarketing</title><link href="/blog/ContentMarketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contentmarketing" /><published>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-26T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/ContentMarketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/ContentMarketing.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;valuable-content-targets-ideal-customers&quot;&gt;Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a healthcare provider, you want to be sure the content on your website provides value to potential and existing patients. Content can be used to drive patients where you would like them to visit on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dentist presenting a case study on a patient, and the struggle the patient faced before coming in contact with them will be a memorable way a reader can relate with the practice. This will create a positive image of your brand to a potential patient who may be struggling with the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/blog/visual-content-you-need-to-use-in-your-marketing-campaign/&quot;&gt;65% of people are visual learners&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also a good idea to use plenty of visual content on your site to target ideal patients and improve your online patient experience. A great example of this is a plastic surgeon using before and after galleries to display their procedure results, and videos of them discussing a specific procedure to better educate their patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the content on your website is boring, unorganized, and irrelevant, you will leave a bad first impression on your visitors thus leaving a negative view of your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;boost-traffic-to-your-medical-site&quot;&gt;Boost Traffic to Your Medical Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a high rank in major search engine results is quality exposure for your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using frequently searched keywords in your industry will also help convert potential patients and increase the visibility of your brand. For instance, a woman in Dallas has a desire for fuller breasts. She searches “Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the title of a before and after photo in your site gallery reads “Amazing Breast Implants in Dallas, TX”. There is a high chance when she completes her search, your site could be at the top of the search results as the keyword in your gallery matches her search phrase. Not only will she head straight for the photo, but she’ll also check out your reviews page and possibly schedule a consultation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having relevant content and keywords will help boost traffic to your site. Content is displayed the second those 590,000 search results pop up. If visitors are unable to find your site due to poor content on your website, then your patient volume is not where it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, give your patients a sense of assurance your practice is the right solution to their healthcare needs. After all, if patients are finding their way to your site, you need to find a way to keep them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in content marketing for your medical practice, contact us today to learn more. We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">Valuable Content Targets Ideal Customers</summary></entry></feed>