<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-13T21:21:48+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Post With Form</title><link href="/blog/new-post-with-form" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post With Form" /><published>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-With-Form</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/new-post-with-form">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content marketing" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forestrytest</title><link href="/blog/forestrytest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forestrytest" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/forestrytest</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/forestrytest.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test using the forestry CMS bob&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="practice-management" /><category term="content-marketing" /><summary type="html">This is a test using the forestry CMS bob</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post List 2</title><link href="/blog/Post-List-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post List 2" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Post-List-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Post-List-2.html">&lt;p&gt;When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; toys. Kenner had acquired the &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-starts&quot;&gt;It Starts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the 1977 Christmas season, Kenner came up with an unconventional idea: an IOU. The company’s $16 Early Bird Certificate Package was a box that included some stickers, a cardboard display stand for a dozen 3¾-inch action figures, and a mail-in offer to receive four of the upcoming figures (Luke Skywalker, Leia Organa, Chewbacca, and R2-D2) between February and June of 1978.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/justin-veenema-31135.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenner delivered on its promise. Throughout early 1978, children received the promised four figures, kindling interest in completing the full 12-piece set. These first dozen toys, known as 12-backs, went on to sell 26 million units that year, kick-starting what would become one of the biggest toy franchises in history. To date, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; merch has moved nearly $20 billion in sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first act of trust ignited a phenomenon. &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting became a hobby, then a passion, then a worldwide industry with insurance policies protecting collections worth millions and collectors chasing the rarest and most elusive pieces. In 2017, that hobby would be tested by an aspiring collector, a thief hidden in plain sight, and a rare plastic action figure worth more than your average car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early February 2017, 39-year-old collector Zach Tann would unknowingly set in motion one of the biggest scandals in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; collecting history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-figure-collection&quot;&gt;My Figure Collection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obi Wan Kenobi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C3P0&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Snaggle Tooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-favorite-figures&quot;&gt;My Favorite Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Luke Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R2-D2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content" /><category term="practice management" /><summary type="html">When George Lucas’s film premiered on May 25, 1977, no one knew it would even succeed, much less become a decades-spanning, money-making juggernaut. Certainly not Kenner, the company tasked with making Star Wars toys. Kenner had acquired the Star Wars merchandising license only a month before the film’s release. When kids immediately fell in love with Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia, and Darth Vader, their action figures were nowhere near ready.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reputation Test</title><link href="/blog/Reputation-Test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reputation Test" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Reputation-Test</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Reputation-Test.html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with this premise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy teams are all alike; every unhappy team is unhappy in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the Anna Karenina principle? It’s derived from the famous first sentence of Leo Tolstoy’s seminal novel: “Happy families are all alike; every unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is as follows: in order for a marriage to thrive, it must succeed in many different respects. If you and your partner argue about money, clash about parenting, or differ in political ideology, you’re doomed to unhappiness — no matter how happy you are in other areas of your relationship. Back in 340 BC, Aristotle emphasized the same principle a bit differently: “Men are good in but one way, but bad in many.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/christopher-ayme-157131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, success is not about doing just one thing correctly, but about avoiding many possible ways to fail. The Anna Karenina principle, popular in science and math, holds true for a lot of things in life — including effective teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If teams want to hit their goals, meet their deadlines, and surpass their KPIs, they need to succeed in all the critical ways — and avoid all the common pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is this magical recipe for effective teamwork? In the early days of building monday.com, we spoke with hundreds of managers and discussed all the unique reasons that teams are unhappy. We discovered seven factors that make or break a team’s success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="content marketing" /><summary type="html">Let’s start with this premise:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing Matt</title><link href="/blog/Testing-Matt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing Matt" /><published>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/Testing-Matt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Testing-Matt.html">&lt;p&gt;He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, with no real clue of what he was doing, he opened it and tried to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was terrifying,” Benoit says now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also the beginning of what has become one of the more interesting narratives in these early days of the modern era of the electric car, one that asks and answers a lot of questions and has turned the 36-year-old Benoit — a father of three who works in IT in Boston — into one of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCfV0_wbjG8KJADuZT2ct4SA&quot; title=&quot;www.youtube.com&quot;&gt;early superstars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tesla that started it all, a Model S that Benoit refers to as Delores, was purchased from a salvage yard after it had been caught in a flood in New Jersey. Benoit had a friend who owned a Model S, and the moment he pulled it into Benoit’s driveway to take him for a ride, Benoit was obsessed. The way it was whisper quiet. The impossible acceleration from zero to I-feel-like-I’m-on-a-roller-coaster-and-about-to-throw-up in an instant. The way he could feel all of the work that went into creating the vehicle, a history of progress that combined to create this feeling of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was like a laptop on wheels,” he says. “The perfect mixture of my two things: tech and cars.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had to have one, but a new Model S starts at $76,000 and can run as high as $133,000. That wasn’t happening. So he purchased Delores for $14,000, with the idea that he was going to do something no amateur mechanic had done before. He was going to rebuild a Tesla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I felt like a trailblazer,” Benoit says of pulling everything in the car apart and figuring out how it worked. “We’re in a society where if you need to know something you Google it, but there was nothing out there, no one who knew how to fix them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the ultimate DIY project, with no guidance from Tesla. Benoit says the company skirts the state’s Right to Repair Initiative, which was passed by voters in 2012 and requires manufacturers to allow vehicle owners access to the same diagnostic and repair information made available to dealerships and authorized repair centers. “They get away with this because they don’t have any dealerships,” Benoit says. “You order your car online.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undeterred, Benoit stripped the car, tore out all of the ruined electronics, and pried out the seats, which had rusted in place, thanks to the saltwater. Then he contacted Tesla to order the parts he needed for the rebuild, and it was here that Benoit hit another obstacle, one that would define the arc of his story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tesla does not want anyone working on its cars besides Tesla, and it refused to sell Benoit the parts he wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Tesla representative, in a statement to the Globe, said “there are significant safety concerns when salvaged Teslas are repaired improperly or when Tesla parts are used outside of their original design intent, as these vehicles could pose a danger to both the mechanic and other drivers on the road.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content marketing" /><category term="website" /><summary type="html">He pulled a 1,300-pound, 400-volt battery out of a Tesla that had been underwater.</summary></entry></feed>