<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-08T16:15:27+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DoctorLogic</title><subtitle>DoctorLogic provides online marketing tools for the medical industry, primarily to specialty doctors and dentists who own their practice.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Showcase Talent Morales</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Showcase Talent Morales" /><published>2019-08-07T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/showcase-talent-morales.html">&lt;p&gt;When DoctorLogic set out to create a website product that would set a new standard in the medical industry, we knew the power behind our platform would likely reside within our photo gallery tool. This intuitive, easy-to-use, Google-friendly section of our websites has proven to be a fan favorite, allowing physicians to display their outcomes like never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently reached out to Dr. Rolando Morales, a plastic surgeon in Houston, to get his feedback on how he uses the gallery tool to shed some additional insight on this awesome feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DocLogic_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolando Morales, M.D.- Houston Plastic Surgeon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Morales specializes in cosmetic plastic surgery for the face, breast and body. In just over 2 years, he has has added over 360 photos of his case work with our tools and attributes this to his success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you find the DoctorLogic Before and After Gallery tool useful?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! It’s the most used tool by far of all components of the platform. It allows me to add new patient cases whenever I want, which adds unique and relevant pages to my website, just as if I had my own blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prior to coming on board with DoctorLogic, did you have a before and after gallery? If yes, what was it like in comparison to yours now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I had a gallery and it was extremely basic. In addition, it was tedious to use. In order to add patients to my gallery I had to go through the webmaster, submit photos, and case specifics. If I did not like the way it looked or read, I had to go back to the webmaster for changes. It was very time consuming as it took forever to get things posted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the DoctorLogic tool, I can simply add cases to my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How has the DoctorLogic Before and After Photo Gallery Tool affected your practice with new or prospective patients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gallery pages are the most popular pages on my website. They are well laid out and organized, and I can put as many photos as I want on the page to display my case. I can do this anytime I want – day or night. I’m able to upload photos, create informative descriptions about what the patient wanted, and explain what I did to achieve these goals. It has helped me to educate prospective patients about the procedures I offer, while at the same time, show new clients specific cases and outcomes of procedures they are thinking about having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How often do you add to the gallery?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to add about 5 new patient case studies per month. Truthfully, I’m so busy in the operating room, otherwise I’d add more! Even though the tool is easy to use, and very intuitive, you still want to make each case shine. So I do spend time making sure my photos are of good quality, and that I write detailed descriptions so that visitors to the page understand what took place during surgery. In addition, I think it is important to mix it up. 50 cases of the same procedure may or may not benefit me, but patient and procedure variety does. So I try and choose who and what I put on the site carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you find the gallery easy to use?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, very easy! I can upload photos myself, move them around, change the order, etc. The gallery tool has &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/gallery/5-easy-steps.html&quot;&gt;5-easy steps&lt;/a&gt; that walk you through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your favorite aspect of the gallery tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, just having total control of my gallery is my favorite part of it all. The ease in moving around the order of photos, deleting them and adding more, and having the overall flexibility makes it seamless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You hear us use the phrases “tagging and keywords” as they pertain to the gallery pages. What is your take on this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not an SEO expert, but I know the procedures I offer, the techniques I perform, and the products I use during a given procedure. The tagging and keyword aspect of the platform allows me to put all of these search terms on my gallery page, which I know is beneficial to those who are searching. When someone is seriously considering a plastic surgery procedure, they want to know details and find someone like them to study the results. When they land on a case that has these very important details, it is very helpful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/screen-reviews-manage.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any idea of the traffic you receive on your gallery pages? Do people mention them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do get good traffic on my gallery pages. In fact, many times during my consultations patients will pull out their phones and show me one of my galleries, or use my phone to take a screenshot of a case that they want to examine further. The great thing about the gallery tool is that the mobile site is perfectly scaled to show the side-to-side pics, which makes my consultations even easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you tell Doctors who use DoctorLogic’s platform, but who do not utilize the gallery tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use it! I can’t really imagine having my website and not taking full advantage of this outstanding tool. My advice would be to take good, consistent photos, and work to increase your volume of cases, as well as the variety and quality you incorporate into the gallery. Try and upload 5-10 per month, and watch your website and your business grow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since partnering with DoctorLogic, Dr. Morales saw a 2,944% increase in Page 1 keyword rankings, a 371% increase in website visitors, and a 179% increase in website leads. In addition to an improved website architecture and keyword ranking, &lt;strong&gt;the Before and After Photo Gallery brings in 74% of all page view traffic, with 27% leads coming strictly from the gallery page.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create stunning case-example pages in minutes with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/features/galleries&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic Gallery Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Before-After-Gallery" /><category term="Healthcare-Marketing" /><summary type="html">When DoctorLogic set out to create a website product that would set a new standard in the medical industry, we knew the power behind our platform would likely reside within our photo gallery tool. This intuitive, easy-to-use, Google-friendly section of our websites has proven to be a fan favorite, allowing physicians to display their outcomes like never before.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 29get More Website Visitors</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 29get More Website Visitors" /><published>2019-07-29T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-29T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-29get-more-website-visitors.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s time to get more visitors to your medical practice’s website. That’s because more visitors equals more conversions from visitors to leads, and more leads becoming actual patients!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you increase website traffic? We’ve put together this list of five things you can do to start getting your visitor numbers up today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-things-that-get-more-visitors-to-your-website&quot;&gt;5 Things That Get More Visitors to Your Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-make-it-easy-for-people-to-find-you&quot;&gt;1. Make it easy for people to find you.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like common sense, but you’d be surprised by how many people unintentionally make their practice very hard to find online. Don’t try to get fancy with your website name or web address, keep it simple! What’s the name of your practice? When searching for domains online, try to use something as close to your practice name as possible. If it’s already taken, try to pick the one that’s most similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-lead-people-from-across-the-web-back-to-your-site&quot;&gt;2. Lead people from across the web back to your site.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating profiles on other sites, offering advice on platforms, and joining online groups and communities can help you and your practice gain more visibility online. Make sure you claim all profiles that already exist for your practice, including those found on RateMDs, Vitals, etc., as well as your physical practice on Google Maps. Next, ensure there’s a link to your practice website on all of the profiles you both claim and create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-leverage-social-to-garner-patient-trust&quot;&gt;3. Leverage social to garner patient trust.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use social as a way to connect to patients on a more personal level. This type of interaction will improve patient trust and allow prospective patients to see your willingness to engage outside of the office, driving more people to your website. Also make sure you’re linking to your site from all your profiles, including LinkedIn, Instagram, Twitter, and Facebook. If you have a Facebook business page, use the CTA button at the top to take people directly to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-optimize-for-search-engines&quot;&gt;4. Optimize for search engines.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/posts/tag/SEO&quot;&gt;search engine optimization (SEO) before&lt;/a&gt;, but it’s worth noting here as well. Making your site easy for search engines to find and crawl will mean they’ll likely reward you by sending more website traffic your way. Some SEO best practices include utilizing local keywords, creating valuable content, improving page load time, including title, header, and image tags as well as meta descriptions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-make-your-site-user-friendly&quot;&gt;5. Make your site user-friendly.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If people land on your site and soon realize it’s not user-friendly, they’ll quickly bounce off (in other words, they’ll leave). Want them to stick around and explore your site, see the procedures you offer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/leveraging-before-and-after-galleries.html&quot;&gt;Before and After photos&lt;/a&gt;, patient reviews, and more? Then ensure your site is user-friendly. You can do this by making your site easy to navigate, speeding up page load time (great for SEO and users alike!), using white space, ensuring it’s responsive and mobile-friendly, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ready-for-more-website-traffic&quot;&gt;Ready for More Website Traffic?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, you only want to employ these tactics once your website is up and running and has the look and feel that you want. If it doesn’t properly represent your medical practice’s brand and values, then you don’t want to drive traffic to it until it does. After all, the last thing you want is to misrepresent the important work that you do! Once your site is where you want it, then it’s time to start driving traffic to it in order to get more visitors, more conversions, more leads and ultimately more patients through your doors!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">It’s time to get more visitors to your medical practice’s website. That’s because more visitors equals more conversions from visitors to leads, and more leads becoming actual patients!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 22how To Conduct Reputation Audit</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 22how To Conduct Reputation Audit" /><published>2019-07-22T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-22T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-22how-to-conduct-reputation-audit.html">&lt;p&gt;We live in an age where anyone can find out information about you with the click of a button. No longer do people have to ask their friends or go searching in the Yellow Pages. By simply typing your name into a search bar, prospective patients can learn a lot about you. So how do you know what they’re seeing and how can you control it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll outline a few ways you can do research into what your name returns online. This online audit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/content/galleries/reputation-management-for-doctors-in-a-digital-world.html&quot;&gt;your reputation&lt;/a&gt; will allow you to see what prospective patients are seeing, as well as better manage what shows up when you Google yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-one-conduct-an-online-search&quot;&gt;Step One: Conduct an Online Search&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, pretend you’re a prospective patient: type your name into different search engines to see what’s returned. A good idea is to check the top three search engines: Google, Bing, and Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at what’s returned on the first page of each search—what’s showing up? Ideally, your practice’s website is first, followed by a scholarly article you wrote or an association you’re a member of, some physician review sites, and then your social media pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-two-manage-your-pages&quot;&gt;Step Two: Manage Your Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on each link on the first page of each search result to see where it takes you. Ask yourself: do you own these pages? If so, are they showing you and your practice in the best light? You might be surprised by what’s still being returned by an online search; it could be an old practice website or even a personal blogging platform. Go in and edit or spruce up pages you think can be improved, update any outdated information, and delete or take offline those pages that are no longer relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the search returns pages you don’t own, who does? If they’re physician review websites, have you claimed your profile? See if the site provides this capability, and then create an account so you can see and manage reviews. If there’s a third-party website you don’t recognize with information about you and/or your practice, try contacting the website owner or administrator. Hopefully, the site has a contact page where you can easily find who you’re looking for. If not, you can usually find contact information in the footer of the website. Still no luck? Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whois.net&quot;&gt;WhoIs.net&lt;/a&gt;, type in the exact URL/web address, and you’ll be able to see the website registrar’s email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-three-separate-the-personal-from-the-professional&quot;&gt;Step Three: Separate the Personal from the Professional&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a physician, seeing as your name is just as associated with your professional life as it is your personal one, it’s not unlikely for personal social media accounts or blogging platforms to be returned by search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to keep this from happening, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/removals?pli=1&quot;&gt;Google’s Content Removal page&lt;/a&gt; to request that they not show up in search results. You can also go into the settings of your personal social media profiles to see if you can select that they not be indexed by the search engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, our online reputation is just as important—if not more so—as our offline one. That’s because the majority of your patients are probably first coming into contact with you online, and most likely via search engines. Conducting an online audit of your online reputation every three to six months will help ensure you’re putting your best digital foot forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reputation-Management" /><summary type="html">We live in an age where anyone can find out information about you with the click of a button. No longer do people have to ask their friends or go searching in the Yellow Pages. By simply typing your name into a search bar, prospective patients can learn a lot about you. So how do you know what they’re seeing and how can you control it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 07 17increase New Patients Smile Galleries</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 07 17increase New Patients Smile Galleries" /><published>2019-07-17T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-17T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/2019-07-17increase-new-patients-smile-galleries.html">&lt;p&gt;As a cosmetic dentist, there are many ways you can market your practice to potential patients. SEO, PPC, retargeting, social media, postcards, and magazines are the most common tactics used to get a dental practice’s brand known in the community. However, one of the most impactful ways to brand yourself is to display &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/products/smile-gallery-plugin/&quot;&gt;smile galleries&lt;/a&gt; on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before and after photos are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; important because they are one of the two key factors that set you apart from your competition. Patients who are actively looking for a cosmetic dental procedure often make decisions based on both galleries and reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the procedures involved in cosmetic or reconstructive cases. Typically, these are your cash-paying patients who bring value to your practice and often times, act as brand ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, displaying your before-and-after cases online allows potential patients to see your work vs. your competition’s work. This enables you to establish credibility and build trust to new visitors on your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Value Behind A Smile Gallery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that approximately 7 out 10 patients looking to have a cosmetic procedure won’t call a practice to book a consultation if they aren’t able to view before-and-after photos on the practice’s website?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the “Look Book” inside your consultation room isn’t nearly as relevant today unless all of those cases are on your website. Additionally, many dentists use the smile galleries found on their website during new patient consultations by using a monitor or large TV to showcase their talent. This allows them to pull up cases that are similar to the needs of the new patient and show how they have helped countless others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a good “best practice” because if the consumer wants to think about it before committing, they know that they can go back to your website and look at your photos again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following strategy is currently helping AACD members all over the U.S. grow their online presence, grow their inbound lead volume, and grow their revenue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.) Patient Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to fully release the identity of your patient, but providing context around gender, age, and ethnicity on each of your cases helps your potential patients relate to your work. This is a good thing because it helps showcase your capabilities and they can see that you have helped others just like them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.) Procedure Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help them understand what procedure they had performed. A patient looking at a before-and-after smile doesn’t have your education and experience. With only showcasing the pictures, they don’t know if someone had implants or veneers. Make it easy and provide some context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.) Conditions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain what conditions someone had prior to coming to see you. Did they have gaps in their teeth, bad bite, cigarette-stained teeth, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.) Photos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider displaying two angles: a head shot so people can see the entire face/smile, and a close-up. If you have a difficult or complex case that required the patient to visit you for multiple treatments, you could take photos for each stage of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.) Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell the story. You don’t have to be an expert marketer and write a 500-word blog, but you can easily describe three key points so the potential patient can relate to your existing patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I. Explain WHY the patient came to see you. What problem were you solving?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II. Explain WHAT procedures you performed. What solution did you offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;III. Discuss that the patient had a positive outcome. What experience would new patients like to have? Explain that you can help them feel more confident when they smile, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This three-part storytelling is simple and follows basic psychology to selling. Patient had a problem, you had a solution, they had a positive outcome. You are helping website visitors connect the dots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t displaying your galleries online or if you only have photos and aren’t using these five ways above to explain your work, consider signing up for &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/products/smile-gallery-plugin/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic Smile Gallery Trial&lt;/a&gt;. You can sign up today and begin using our software to upload your galleries and describe your cases inside your website. The best part is – it’s absolutely &lt;strong&gt;FREE for 1 year for all AACD members!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to begin? Contact DoctorLogic for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Content-Marketing" /><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">As a cosmetic dentist, there are many ways you can market your practice to potential patients. SEO, PPC, retargeting, social media, postcards, and magazines are the most common tactics used to get a dental practice’s brand known in the community. However, one of the most impactful ways to brand yourself is to display smile galleries on your website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Convert Phone Call Into New Patients" /><published>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/how-to-convert-phone-call-into-new-patients.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hour later, and no call back, so I called again. After the second ring, I was greeted with, “Dentist office, can you please hold.” Before I could respond I was put on hold. This was not a great experience…needless to say I hung up and did not call back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your front desk staff and the way they handle the first phone conversation can quite literally mean the difference between a thriving practice full of referrals and delighted patients and a practice struggling just to get by. Having friendly and sincere people representing your practice is the thing that will leave the most lasting impression on patients, especially new patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at a few behaviors that should be a part of your front desk process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;efficient-system-for-phone-calls-and-patient-arrivals&quot;&gt;Efficient system for phone calls and patient arrivals.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the voice and face of a doctor’s front office can be overwhelming, especially if your team is dealing with high call volume, and patient arrivals all at the same time. This is an opportunity to revisit your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;every-call-should-be-answered-before-the-third-ring&quot;&gt;Every call should be answered before the third ring.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure the phone is answered on brand, have a little script available. And if your staff has to put a caller on hold, it’s okay. First, make them feel comfortable by having your phone attendees introduce themselves, then ask permission to put the caller on hold or ask if they would prefer a call back. If a patient arrives while your attendant is on the phone, simply give them a nod and a smile and let them know you’ll be right with them. They will feel acknowledged and will wait to interact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-about-first-impression&quot;&gt;It’s About First Impression.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While searching for an orthopaedic in my area, I called several offices. I made a decision on one particular office based on the phone attendee. She asked open ended questions and had a genuine interest in me and my symptoms. She acknowledged my reason for calling, showed empathy and expressed compassion for my situation. Because of these reasons I made the appointment because I figured the doctor would also be this way. When I visited the office, the reception used my name several times, came from behind the window to hand me the forms and showed me how to work the kiosk to sign in. I walked out of there feeling like this practice is truly committed to their patients and I even mentioned to the doctor this was the best experience I have ever had in an office…this was after a SHOT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-smiling-over-the-phone&quot;&gt;The Power of Smiling Over The Phone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a smile widens on a phone call, and no one is there to see it, does it make a sound? Yes, it does. The advice of smiling over the phone has been around for years, but it’s amazing how many people don’t put it into practice. Besides teaching your team the importance of smiling, set little things to help them develop the habit. Like having a mirror on their computer or having little reminders near the phone…”Shoulders Back. Smile” is an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the telephone is more than likely the first “voice” experience potential patients have with your medical practice. So needless to say the experience must be an exceptional one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone by the third ring to avoid patients going to voicemail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Script a greeting for your staff to use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Answer the phone with a big smile on your face…the caller on the other end will appreciate it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train your staff to encourage the caller to schedule an appointment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no mystery when it comes to converting phone calls to new patients. It’s as easy as having empathy for the person on the other end of the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">Recently, I was in search for a dentist who could accept walk ins and emergencies due to a cracked tooth caused by a popcorn kernel. I found this dentist online and called them after seeing their website. I dialed the number. The phone rang. I was greeted with a robotic voice mail, “Thank you for calling our Dentist office. We are very busy with our current patients. Leave your name and number and we’ll call you as soon as we can.” Click. So, I left a message.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsites For Medical Seo</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsites For Medical Seo" /><published>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/microsites-for-medical-seo.html">&lt;p&gt;Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-microsite&quot;&gt;What is a Microsite?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to HubSpot, a microsite is an individual web page or small cluster of web pages that act as a separate entity for a brand. A microsite typically lives on its own domain, but some exist as a subdomain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsites can be used to help brands achieve a number of things. For example, some companies have used them to highlight a specific campaign or target specific buyer personas. Others have used them to tell a short story, or to inspire a specific call-to-action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-launch-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Launch Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not your practice should launch a microsite will really depend on its purpose. There are some instances where a microsite is a good idea, such as when a site is created to support a brand that is an extension of a parent company or when a company is running a special event or promotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s enough content available to make the microsite worthwhile, launching a separate microsite can be a great direction. However, if there isn’t enough content, this can hurt your goals rather than help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-seo-microsite-game&quot;&gt;The SEO Microsite Game.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some website owners think you can create a microsite, link back to the main website, get some traffic, and increase conversions. Seems like an easy direction…when in actuality it’s not. A microsite should be created if, and only if,the microsite actually serves a unique purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has determined sites created for the sole purpose directing back to website with back links, or to boost certain keywords, is actually a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/black-hat-seo&quot;&gt;black hat SEO&lt;/a&gt; tactic and looks spammy. Not only that, but Google considers sites like this to be extremely low quality. And remember, Google penalizes sites they deem to be low quality. To avoid a penalty, it’s best to avoid setting up microsites unless it’s for branding purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-say-no-to-microsites&quot;&gt;Why Say No to Microsites?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes time and effort to create and optimize the content for microsites. Basically the same steps you took to set up your main site still applies, and they can take just as long. Imagine going through that for more than one site.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search engines rank sites that have lots of good, quality content. If you’re creating microsites your practice’s content will be spread out. Your content is better off gaining traction on your main website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While microsites can serve legitimate purposes, it’s not recommended to use them solely for SEO. For SEO, focus on getting your main website rank high by producing quality, well optimized content and building relevant links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save yourself time and avoid the headache of creating tons of mini sites to boost your SEO. Get in touch with &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/&quot;&gt;DoctorLogic&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about our platform to help you grow your practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will design your website so you can showcase your work with a video or photo gallery. Additionally, we can add our review tool to help you get reviews from your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will make your practice stand out from the rest of the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Website" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Before you consider a microsite, understand there are pros and cons to using them as part of your marketing strategy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Are Medical Keywords Important</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Are Medical Keywords Important" /><published>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/why-are-medical-keywords-important.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall the days where if I said I was looking up symptoms I would have been deemed a hypochondriac. It’s okay…I’m not alone. Statistics show &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchengineland.com/77-percent-of-online-health-seekers-start-at-search-engines-pew-study-145105&quot;&gt;77% of consumers now use search engines&lt;/a&gt; to conduct research before consulting a doctor and a surprising number of these people see a doctor about the results they find during their search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Google accommodating billions of users with top-notch, reliable medical information in certain search results, it’s never been more important for practices to provide exceptional medical content to compete for common, high-volume search terms in your field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re evaluating how to stand out in these search terms, one of the key factors you should be considering is a keyword or keyword phrase strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-a-keyword&quot;&gt;What’s a Keyword?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact definition states a &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/learn/seo/what-are-keywords&quot;&gt;keyword or keyword phrase&lt;/a&gt; is a query term entered into a search engine or website by patients. A keyword can be a single word or a series of words. It’s the search term you want to rank for with a certain page. So when people search for a keyword or phrase in Google or other search engines, they should find the page on your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone searches Google for “how to fix gap teeth without braces” Google works to discern what the user is looking for, and it returns a list of web pages with this topic. If your website uses the exact phrase the user searched for as a keyword, part of the phrase (“gap teeth”), or a related phrase (i.e. “teeth gaps,” “braces”) Google is more likely to show the user your websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/Keywords3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google works to discern what the user is looking for.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-are-keywords-so-important&quot;&gt;Why Are Keywords So Important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put…ROI. Choosing the right keyword phrases and using them correctly for SEO is quite frankly the easiest and most effective way to get more users to your website. SEO is important to your practice’s success, and keywords play a major role in the SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/assets/img/posts/Keywords2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SEO is important to your practice’s success.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People will find their way onto your pages in a variety of ways, including social media and direct traffic to name a few. But, in today’s market, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/search-engines-more-traffic-publishers-social-media-2017-2018-2&quot;&gt;search generates the biggest share of traffic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-should-your-practice-start&quot;&gt;Where Should Your Practice Start?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless if you’re taking the first step to or making adjustments to an up and running SEO strategy, the best place to start is to find the right long-tail keywords. Long-tail keywords allow small and medium sized practices to stand out and boost your medical practice’s ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-short-taillong-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;What are Short-Tail/Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanised.co.uk/seo/short-tail-vs-long-tail-keywords/&quot;&gt;Short-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are limited to one or two words that cover a general topic, such as “breast lift”. Very general term, right? Yes, it will attract lots of search traffic, but it’s expensive and difficult to rank for especially if you’re new to the keyword/SEO game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wordstream.com/long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;Long-tail keywords&lt;/a&gt; are specific terms or phrases such as “best breast lift surgeon near me”. You may see less traffic, but if a patient is searching for this term then they are most likely closer to making a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short-tail keywords are still very useful to the growth of your practice. Long-tail keywords can help your medical practice play to your SEO strengths while building the authority to rank for short-tail keywords in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-should-medical-practices-choose-long-tail-keywords&quot;&gt;How Should Medical Practices Choose Long-Tail Keywords?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start by utilizing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blog.google/products/search/how-google-autocomplete-works-search/&quot;&gt;Google’s search bar recommendations&lt;/a&gt; to understand how it suggests possible long tails. By checking out what potential keywords are most popular and what’s applicable to what you provided in terms of care, your practice can narrow down your list or add possibilities you have missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have time to walk through all of the items needed to plan and implement a &lt;a href=&quot;https://doctorlogic.com/services/ppc/&quot;&gt;paid advertising strategy&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to connect with us at DoctorLogic. Our software generates on average 30,000 relevant, unique exact match, long-tail keyword combinations for every campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact-us-today&quot;&gt;Contact Us Today!&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Medical-PPC" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">It’s no secret people use Google for everything — especially for health issues.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Healthcare Marketing Plan Working" /><published>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-16T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/is-healthcare-marketing-plan-working.html">&lt;p&gt;If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-do-you-actually-have-a-strategy&quot;&gt;1. Do you actually have a strategy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure or not feeling confident in what you think you have then you don’t have a strategy. To get started first and foremost, develop a plan of action. Without a plan, your setting your initiatives up for failure. Try not to throw out initiatives without developing a strategy first, and be sure to clearly define your objectives and ROI (return on investment) metrics… which leads me to my second point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-youre-not-tracking-kpi-metrics&quot;&gt;2. You’re not tracking KPI metrics.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to prove your marketing strategy works, data has to back it up. Every successful marketing strategy needs expectations set and frequent monitoring on what, when, and how; what got launched, when it went live, and how it performed. Data-driven decision making is the key to successful marketing. Here’s a great reference for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.impactbnd.com/the-10-marketing-kpis-you-should-be-tracking&quot;&gt;which KPIs you should be tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-youre-wanting-results-now&quot;&gt;3. You’re wanting results NOW.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of the phrase, you need to learn how to crawl before you walk? The same applies for marketing initiatives. Marketing is powerful but results don’t happen overnight. To prove success for a marketing plan, focus on KPIs at the beginning and throughout the campaign, and ROI at the end. Often times, campaigns get shut down early because they didn’t prove value within the first few days. The key to avoiding this is to set attainable goals and learn from the results for your next campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-your-marketing-budget-is-mia&quot;&gt;4. Your marketing budget is M.I.A.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare practices are apprehensive towards spending marketing dollars. With the industry being highly competitive, allocating a certain percentage to marketing is a must. Additionally, when you track KPIs and ROI, you can make data-driven decisions to increase marketing dollars where it makes sense. For more help on how to allocate a marketing budget, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.webascender.com/blog/how-to-allocate-your-digital-marketing-budget-in-2019/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-youre-living-the-definition-of-insanity&quot;&gt;5. You’re living the “Definition of Insanity”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of insanity is doing the same thing and expecting different results. Marketing initiatives are not one-and-done or set-it-and-forget-it. Constant optimization is required for optimal success. Try different initiatives as well. The more data you can collect on what worked and what didn’t, the more you can leverage it for your success.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html">If your marketing strategy is non-existent or unprosperous, take a look at these common reasons why marketing strategies don’t work.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Types Content For Medical Practice</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Types Content For Medical Practice" /><published>2019-03-28T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-28T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/5-types-content-for-medical-practice.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blog-series&quot;&gt;Blog Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog series are great for multiple reasons. First of all, they allow you to offer your audience a ton of value by exploring a topic in-depth over a span of time. Second, they’re great for search engines, as you’ll have multiple pages/posts of content on a topic, increasing your authority in said topic in the eyes of search engine spiders (the bots that scan websites in order to properly rank them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what types of subjects should you write blog series on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing for a specific procedure:&lt;/strong&gt; What the patient can do physically to prepare, what the procedure itself will entail, what s/he should purchase to have at home after the procedure, what drugs s/he will be taking, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At-home treatments:&lt;/strong&gt; Are there DIY, at-home, or natural treatments prospective patients can try in addition to the services you provide?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient testimonials:&lt;/strong&gt; Interview multiple patients who have had your most popular procedure. Ask them the same questions so prospective patients can get an idea of the different experiences people have had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;infographics&quot;&gt;Infographics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are visual learners, which is why infographics are so popular. Consider creating infographics based on statistics relevant to your practice (recovery time based on procedure, number of procedures+which types performed annually), as well as ones that are more instructional (what to expect during your recovery, how family+friends can help, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ebooks&quot;&gt;EBooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Longer-form content should be “gated”, or only accessible when people enter their email address. This way you can move more people into your marketing funnel and move them down the pipeline to becoming actual patients. Ebooks can be extensions of blog series (in which you expand even further upon each individual subject) or more technical explanations of procedures from your practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video content is becoming increasingly popular because it’s incredibly effective: Videos are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vidyard.com/blog/science-behind-why-video-works/&quot;&gt;12 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to be watched than text is to be read, and content is &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.forrester.com/blogs/09-01-08-the_easiest_way_to_a_first_page_ranking_on_google/&quot;&gt;50 times more likely&lt;/a&gt; to make it to the first page of Google results if it includes video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage video via:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doctor and staff introduction videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How certain machines are used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tour of your practice’s office/facilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patient testimonials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;newsletters&quot;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem old school to some, especially given strides in technology like virtual reality and artificial intelligence, but email is still one of the most effective forms of digital marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilize your email list by keeping both past and prospective patients in the loop. Highlight recent patient testimonials, popular blog posts, a staff member introduction video, and other content you’ve put hard work into making! This will help keep your practice top of mind, even if your recipients aren’t regularly visiting your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it: the 5 types of content needed to boost the brand for your medical practice. Content not only helps improve SEO rankings, it increases leads and gets prospects to convert into customers. Allow DoctorLogic to help you with your content marketing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Content-Marketing" /><summary type="html">Here are a few ideas to get your content creation juices flowing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Positive Patient Experience</title><link href="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positive Patient Experience" /><published>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorlogic.com/blog/positive-patient-experience.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout and cleanliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workspace-resource.com/office-furniture/crucial-design-tips-for-creating-a-patient-focused-healthcare-facility/&quot;&gt;design tips&lt;/a&gt; to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with staff:&lt;/strong&gt; Friendliness can go a long way. When staff members are welcoming and inviting, patients feel valued and cared for. The front-desk staff must be well-trained and willing to provide information to the patient, such as expected wait time, bathroom location, any complimentary beverages, etc., Also keep in mind interactions with staff can be via phone as well. Finding ways to translate that sense of welcomeness through the phone can have the same affect towards their overall experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theberylinstitute.org/blogpost/947424/302264/Phone-Skills-Making-or-Breaking-The-Patient-Experience&quot;&gt;Here’s a great reference&lt;/a&gt; for scripting and guiding phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait times:&lt;/strong&gt; No one likes to wait. Restaurants and grocery stores have transformed online and mobile ordering so items are ready for pickup upon arriving. Amazon Prime ships same-day or two-day packages. Websites have to be speedy-quick or consumers will bounce due to loading time… it’s the new trend. When they’re used to skipping lines, sitting in a waiting area for minutes to hours on end, tries their patience. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.medicalgps.com/how-long-will-you-wait-4-simple-tips-for-easing-the-wait-experience/&quot;&gt;97% of patients&lt;/a&gt; get frustrated over wait times, and overall patient satisfaction decreases as wait time increases. If your wait times cannot be avoided, try finding ways to occupy their time. Some ideas are: free internet, TV, or latest up-to-date magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactions with the doctor(s):&lt;/strong&gt; Patients remember the way their doctor treated them. Friendliness doesn’t begin and end with the front-desk. Doctors need to be friendly and accommodating as well. Being personable makes patients feel valued. Take time to thoroughly explain their medical condition and open the discussion for questions. When a patient openly discusses their questions with you, it’s important to reciprocate the same openness and honesty by replying “that’s a great question, I’m glad you asked.” Providing a sense of partnership to patients promotes positive patient experience.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusively, there are many ways to create memorable experiences. It might be fun to switch up the experiences every now and then and ask for patient feedback. Ultimately, providing a positive, memorable experience not only benefits your patients, it benefits your practice as well. Positive experiences translate to patient retention and practice growth. The ultimate practice goal, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><category term="Reputation-Management" /><summary type="html">Layout and cleanliness: The way an office looks when a patient visits gives a testament to the type of service they should expect to receive. If the waiting area has trash laying around, an unpleasant smell, or unorganized chairs, it gives the impression the staff is lazy, unorganized, or doesn’t care. This is an extreme example, but I doubt this is the type of first impression you want to give regardless of how your practice is laid out. Therefore, ensuring the entire office (waiting rooms to patient rooms) is kept tidy and clean helps the patient gain confidence the staff cares about their experience. Here are some design tips to ensure patients receive a comfortable experience.</summary></entry></feed>